NARRATOR:
A fiery object
crashes into the Earth
and ignites the modern UFO era.
It would become
the absolute touchstone event
and the best‐known event
in the world
connecting our reality
to the E. T. phenomenon.
NARRATOR:
For more than seven decades,
the Army has denied
what it initially reported‐‐
that it had recovered
a flying disc.
But could evidence
of such an event still exist?
‐(beeping)
‐Oh, my God.
There is something there,
and we need to dig it up.
NARRATOR:
Are there remnants
of alien technology
scattered
in the New Mexico desert?
LINDA MOULTON HOWE:
I think he's holding something
made by another intelligence.
I have never, ever seen
anything like this.
NARRATOR:
And could materials
already recovered
soon reveal the truth
about an extraterrestrial
presence on Earth?
There's something big
going on here.
I'm getting chills
because we've got some elements
that are showing up‐‐
they shouldn't be there.
GIORGIO A. TSOUKALOS:
If the evidence has not yet been
uncovered,
that does not mean the evidence
is not there.
NARRATOR:
There is a doorway
in the universe.
Beyond it is
the promise of truth.
It demands
we question everything
we have ever been taught.
The evidence is all around us.
The future is
right before our eyes.
We are not alone.
We have never been alone.
NARRATOR:
Los Angeles, California.
October 2019.
Ancient astronaut theorist
Giorgio Tsoukalos...
‐Hey, Linda.
‐...is meeting up
with investigative journalist
Linda Moulton Howe
at a secure storage facility.
‐All right, let's do it.
‐Let's go.
NARRATOR:
For more than two decades,
Linda has been in possession of
highly unusual metal fragments
given to her
by someone who claims
they were extracted
from an extraterrestrial craft.
‐Man, this is some door.
‐(beep)
(Tsoukalos chuckles)
Okay.
Well, over the years,
I've learned that this is really
‐pretty valuable.
‐Right.
And that I better keep it
in something
‐like a safety deposit box.
‐Right.
NARRATOR:
In recent months,
the United States Army
has taken an interest
in doing its own examination
of these materials.
Linda is eager to show Giorgio
just what it is
that has caught
the Army's attention.
Here is where the magic
bismuth magnesium zinc resides.
There it is,
inside the magic box.
Yeah. Here, I'll take it
over here and show it to you.
I have found,
since having this
in 1996
and evolving with research, that
it has become now so valuable.
What am I looking at, Linda?
What is this?
Well, here is...
You see all these layers?
‐Yeah.
‐When you go to a scanning
‐electron microscope...
‐Huh.
...and you see that the black,
the black side‐‐
it's pure bismuth,
and it's one to four microns,
which is about
half the size of a blood cell,
and then it's alternating
just like a torte cake.
‐TSOUKALOS: Yeah.
‐And the top silver‐‐
that's the magnesium‐zinc alloy.
‐Okay.
‐So,
layer by layer by layer
in microns.
TSOUKALOS:
It's almost
as if it's reflective, too.
HOWE:
Yes, and when you get it
in the sun,
it looks like a snowfield.
And that's the magnesium zinc.
NARRATOR:
In addition
to this layered material,
Linda also has
an unusual piece of aluminum.
HOWE:
As I understand
from a physicist, it is this
pure aluminum,
99.5% pure aluminum.
TSOUKALOS:
As far as I know,
we can't produce 99 point...
I mean, this is incredibly pure.
So where were these pieces
allegedly found?
HOWE:
These came out of White Sands
in New Mexico,
outside of Roswell.
Is there a connection
to Roswell with this piece?
NARRATOR:
In July of 1947,
an unidentified flying object
crashed to Earth in the desert
just outside
Roswell, New Mexico.
It is today the most famous
UFO event on record,
in part
because it was the Army itself
that reported the craft
as a flying disc.
BILL BIRNES:
July 8 and 9,
the newspaper headlines‐‐
"Army Captures Flying Disc
Outside of Roswell."
How did the newspaper get
that story? Walter Haut.
He was the official
public information officer
at the Roswell 509th, who gave
the story to the newspaper.
NARRATOR:
But the military
quickly walked back its story.
Within days,
the mysterious Roswell UFO
was given an earthly origin,
when the government claimed
that the downed craft was merely
a weather balloon.
They changed it and said
it was a weather balloon
and everything else.
They said they took it
to Wright‐Patterson
Air Force Base in Ohio.
RICHARD DOLAN:
When you really think
about this,
why on earth would
anyone send any kind
of weather balloon to Wright
Field for technical analysis?
None of it makes any sense
whatsoever,
unless that material
was much more exotic
and much more
scientifically interesting
than just a mere balloon.
DAVID CHILDRESS:
When you look
at the whole Roswell incident,
it seems to be a recovery that
was very much
a scrambled ad hoc thing.
And, in fact, witnesses had been
to the crash site
before the military got there.
So in the chaos of trying
to clean up this crash site,
you have to wonder that whether
they would really get it all.
Where would this material
actually go?
And would they have left
some of it behind,
just by accident?
NARRATOR:
In April 2011,
the FBI released thousands
of files
as part of its online FBI vault,
including a 1950 briefing
to FBI Director J. Edgar Hoover
regarding informant information
about three flying saucers
that were recovered
in New Mexico.
Many researchers believe
this corroborates
long‐standing rumors
that the Roswell incident
involved not one
but three crashed UFOs.
And there were numerous
other incidents reported
during that time period
in the area
of Roswell
and White Sands Proving Ground
that remain mostly unknown.
You look at where the world
today, when they think
of a UFO crash,
they think of Roswell.
‐Mm‐hmm.
‐Certainly there
have been crashes
in New Mexico
outside of Roswell.
We know that there were a lot
of UFO crashes going
from the '40... like,
'47, '48, '49, and so forth.
How did you come into possession
of these pieces?
Well, I'll never forget
the day that Art Bell called me,
and he said,
"Linda, I received a box
with a letter, and there's
some metal pieces in here."
He said,
"I think they're aluminum,
but I want you
to start investigating."
That would have been in 1996,
that spring.
NARRATOR:
Art Bell was the founder
and original host
of the long‐running,
paranormal‐themed radio program
Coast to Coast AM.
In 1996, he and Linda began
to receive shipments in the mail
of small metallic fragments.
We started getting two shipments
coming from a man
who identified himself
in a series
of five typed letters.
And he said
he was an Army sergeant,
that his grandfather had died
in 1974,
and had left a box
that had a diary and metals.
And the Army sergeant said,
"I want you to have this
and see what you can find out."
NARRATOR:
The letters detail
how the grandfather extracted
the metallic items
from a wedge‐shaped craft
while working as a member
of a recovery crew
between Roswell and White Sands
Proving Ground in 1948.
Art Bell turned over these
mysterious fragments and letters
to Linda Moulton Howe
for further study.
In June of 1996,
Linda commissioned
university researchers
to use
a scanning electron microscope
and a technique known as "X‐ray
fluorescence spectrometry"
to analyze the samples.
The analysis revealed
alternating microscopic layers
of the metals bismuth,
magnesium and zinc
only microns thick,
a combination that baffles
exotic metal experts.
GEORGE KNAPP:
I think we've got technology
that we didn't make.
A lot of people
have come forward
with bits and pieces
of the same tale.
We are presently analyzing
metamaterials
that we did not make,
that's created in a way
that is beyond our technology.
TSOUKALOS:
Are there more pieces
of these items?
Well, for the last,
uh, 15 years,
I had a combination
of another piece
of the bismuth magnesium zinc
and another smaller piece
of the aluminum.
So, the pair that I had before
is now involved
with military testing.
NARRATOR:
In 2019,
Linda handed over
additional samples
of the exotic metals
for examination
by the United States Army.
As far as Linda is concerned,
even though the fragments were
allegedly taken from a craft
that was in the Army's
possession in 1948,
there are likely
only a handful of people
who are aware of its existence.
She is hopeful that the
examination of her materials
will prove that they were not
manufactured on Earth,
and perhaps those who know
what really happened at Roswell
will finally reveal
both the truth
and what they recovered
to the public.
Do you have any new leads
that maybe happened recently
of someone
that has found other material?
Well, there is a geologist
down in Roswell,
and he has sent me e‐mails
saying
that he's got exotic metals
and all of these materials.
And I think
we could go down there,
see what he has found so far,
and maybe go out with him
and explore ourselves.
Awesome. Let's go.
♪ ♪
NARRATOR:
If multiple flying discs
crashed in the New Mexico desert
in 1947,
was all the debris
recovered long ago?
Or could there be remnants
that were spirited away
by curious locals
and military personnel,
and some still lying out
in the open,
waiting to be found?
NARRATOR:
Roswell, New Mexico.
July 1947.
NARRATOR:
Major Jesse Marcel,
the head intelligence officer
at Roswell Army Air Field,
travels to Fort Worth, Texas,
with the debris recovered
from the Roswell crash site.
He and Brigadier General
Roger Ramey,
head of the Eighth Air Force,
are scheduled to present
their findings to the media.
BIRNES: Jesse Marcel flies
to Fort Worth,
the headquarters
of the Eighth Air Force,
and he's set up
to tell the whole world
about the crash
of a flying saucer at Roswell,
except Roger Ramey says
to Jesse Marcel,
"Could you just go
in the map room for a second?
I want to arrange some stuff
out here."
The story from Jesse Marcel
and from the photographer
is that the real wreckage
had been spirited away.
"Hold up something.
"Get some Reynolds Wrap out‐‐
off‐off the fish in your freezer
and hold it up and say that's
what you found, not a disc,"
which is exactly what they did.
And the reporters basically just
turned around, went home.
NARRATOR:
For UFO researchers,
evidence that
the actual wreckage from Roswell
was indeed replaced
with a weather balloon
can be found
within the notorious photograph,
along with clues as to what was
being hidden from the public.
When General Roger Ramey was,
uh, posing for photographs
with Jesse Marcel,
in the aftermath of all this,
you can see him very clearly
holding a piece of paper.
POPE:
General Ramey had a document
in his hands,
the so‐called Ramey Memo.
Modern forensic
document analysis
and photographic enhancement
has enabled some researchers
to zoom in on this
and to clarify at least
some portions of the text.
What it tells us is astounding.
Some of the phrases in the memo
are "victims of the wreck"
and "disc which we will ship."
So, clearly,
if the official story is true,
well, this makes no sense.
No, clearly, something more
than just a weather balloon
was involved here,
and the memo might just be
the smoking gun.
NARRATOR:
As far as Roswell researchers
are concerned,
the memo points to a cover‐up,
with the downed UFO
and its extraterrestrial crew
being shipped from the base
and locked away
from the public eye.
But if true,
might there be fragments
of evidence from the crash
that were small enough
to slip through the cracks?
The question is always, well,
where is the evidence,
where is the evidence?
Well, if the evidence
has not yet been uncovered
or dug out of the ground,
that does not mean
the evidence is not there.
NARRATOR:
Central New Mexico.
October 19, 2019.
Investigative journalist
Linda Moulton Howe
has invited ancient astronaut
theorist Giorgio Tsoukalos
to join her on a trip
to a spot in the desert
just outside Roswell,
very near what is known
as the "skip site."
According to eyewitnesses,
one of the three UFOs
seen in the sky in July 1947
first crashed to Earth
near this location, then was
propelled back into the air,
skipping like a stone in a pond
before finally coming to rest.
Linda was contacted
by geologist Frank Kimbler,
who wants to show her
mysterious metal fragments
that he found here
and search the area for more.
TSOUKALOS:
Linda, this is so exciting.
I have not been here
in a couple of years.
So, I'm really looking forward
‐t‐to meeting Frank.
‐Yeah.
Well, I'm glad that we've got
a geologist who's helping,
because the geologist
looks at land
and says if there is debris,
there's going to be some
kind of a drift with the land.
And, just from what I know,
he has studied
some areas meticulously.
Right.
NARRATOR: Giorgio and Linda
arrive at the skip site
and meet Frank Kimbler,
a local geologist
and professor of Earth science.
‐How are you? Good to see you.
‐Nice to meet you. How are you?
‐All right.
‐Frank, it is...
‐Linda. Finally.
‐Yes.
You and I have been chasing
these artifacts
‐from UFOs...
‐Chasing the metals...
‐...for so many years.
‐...looking for,
looking for parts.
‐Yes!
‐It's great.
NARRATOR: Professor Kimbler
has spent nearly a decade
searching areas beneath
the purported trajectory
of the Roswell craft
with infrared technology
and metal detectors.
KIMBLER:
When an object crashes,
they're gonna scatter
a variety of materials around.
Knobs, control devices,
plastic, wires, whatever.
If it's coming apart, it's gonna
leave those pieces behind.
And those are the kinds
of pieces that I want to find
and have found some of.
NARRATOR:
Since 2011,
Professor Kimbler has uncovered
more than a dozen metal
fragments that he has subjected
to scientific testing
and found to be highly unique.
That's what...
We want to go out there and see
‐where you've been getting this.
‐TSOUKALOS: Yeah, I can't wait.
‐Frank.
‐Yeah?
What's inside the case?
Oh, this, this is
the magic right here.
This is some of the material
that I have found
out here, uh,
using a metal detector.
‐Uh...
‐TSOUKALOS: Interesting.
KIMBLER:
This stuff
is, is very interesting.
It's all twisted and mangled up.
Something that you would expect
to happen from a, uh, a‐a crash
is to have metal that's‐that's
compact and twisted.
When Professor Kimbler laid out
his box of his pieces of metal,
the first thing that struck me
is these were
tiny, tiny, tiny fragments.
Could they possibly be
from wreckage?
These pieces are small, uh,
which is things that the
government would have missed.
‐Uh, yeah.
‐They wouldn't have
been able to find it.
And here's my magic.
Let's get a comparison here.
‐KIMBLER: Oh, look at that.
‐This...
HOWE:
Look at‐‐ it's like a snowfield.
After all these years, the‐‐
all of the pieces,
they look absolutely pristine.
That's the magnesium zinc side.
KIMBLER:
This has got layers to it,
and that's amazing. That's...
‐But I bet you've never seen
anything like this.
‐No.
Being an Earth scientist,
being a geologist,
I've seen lots of all kinds
of materials that are out there.
I have never, ever seen
anything like this.
This fragment that Linda
is showing me,
it‐‐ that stuff
is absolutely amazing.
I've never seen anything like it
before in my life.
And what's interesting about it
is that it has some layers,
some banding on it.
And that banding is very similar
to some of the banding
that I found in photomicrographs
of the material
that I have from out here.
I think,
as Giorgio is holding this,
he's holding something made
by another intelligence
from some place
we don't understand.
And this is truly
extraterrestrial.
NARRATOR:
Is it possible that Giorgio
is holding an actual fragment
of an extraterrestrial craft?
And if so, could even more
incredible artifacts
still remain in the desert
outside Roswell?
NARRATOR: Ancient astronaut
theorist Giorgio Tsoukalos
and investigative journalist
Linda Moulton Howe
are in an area
outside Roswell, New Mexico
with geologist Frank Kimbler.
I've got one of the, uh, the
infrared pictures right here,
that actually is,
it's kind of contrast‐enhanced.
NARRATOR:
As far as Professor Kimbler
is concerned,
if one or more
extraterrestrial crafts
really did crash in the desert,
the best place to find
more debris is right here.
Right now we are roughly about
maybe two, two and a half miles
from where the object
skipped down,
according
to eyewitness accounts.
This is actually the disturbed
area right here,
which is right
where we're going.
And it's right where
the eyewitness account
basically says that the craft
left a furrow.
So you can tell
that something went on.
It even looks like
there's a little a gouge mark
that was left by the craft
as it came in.
NARRATOR:
The disturbed area that
Professor Kimbler identified
has become known as the "gouge."
In 2002, an archaeological dig
was conducted in this area
by the University
of New Mexico, Albuquerque,
to search for topographical
evidence of a UFO crash.
KIMBLER:
They found a V‐shaped gouge
that seemed to indicate
that something came down
and skated across the ground,
like a typical aircraft
crashing into the ground,
leaving a‐a big furrow there.
NARRATOR:
Author Donald Schmitt,
an advisor
to the International UFO Museum
& Research Center
board of directors,
took part in the excavation.
DONALD SCHMITT:
We flagged that area,
did electromagnetic
sensory testing of the sites
to sift through possible samples
from the crash.
All in an attempt to find
a piece of that missing evidence
that would demonstrate
once and for all
that this was something
extraordinary.
NARRATOR:
The dig collected
countless soil samples
from in and around the gouge.
But curiously, access to this
wealth of potential evidence
has been restricted
by the Bureau of Land Management
ever since.
KIMBLER:
There's 600 pounds of stuff
stored in a vault
in the Maxwell Museum
at the University of New Mexico
that nobody has looked at,
and it needs to be looked at.
NARRATOR:
Demands by UFO researchers
to be given access
to the contents of the 2002 dig
have fallen on deaf ears.
In the nearly two decades since,
the V‐shaped gouge has been
filled in with sediment,
but many believe
that if there is more debris
still to be found,
it is most likely
to be found here.
We need to get going,
and we need to get out there
so you guys can experience
finding some of this stuff,
‐which is amazing.
‐TSOUKALOS: All right.
Let's go explore.
HOWE: So, where do you think's
best here now?
KIMBLER:
We're in the perfect spot.
And we're gonna cover
this whole thing right here.
NARRATOR:
Uncovering bits of debris
in this vast desert
is a daunting task,
but after nearly a decade
spent combing the entire area,
Professor Kimbler has pinpointed
certain hot spots.
Some of the artifacts
he brought with him today
were discovered
in this very location
just within the past month.
So, just above the area
of the ground,
we're gonna sweep back and forth
like this.
We're gonna cover this
side to side,
back and forth,
little by little.
I've been out here
six or seven or eight hours
at a whack swinging this thing
till my arms break off.
We can, uh, cut across this way.
HOWE:
You're waiting for that beep.
We're looking off in‐in
this general direction out here.
The craft basically
either had some kind
of mechanical failure
or something blew up.
NARRATOR:
Professor Kimbler scans
the area along the gouge,
meticulously covering
every inch.
After nearly two hours,
he has not detected
any metal objects.
Giorgio,
my arm is about to break off,
and I'm kind of hoping
that you just might have
‐a little bit
better luck than me doing this.
‐Sure. Let's see.
‐You saw what I was doing,
it's already fired up.
‐Yep. Okay.
And I'm gonna let you
swing this. And we can just...
‐Let's see if it's working.
‐(beeping)
‐There you go,
it's working perfect.
‐Great. Perfect. Excellent.
Maybe you'll be able to...
‐to get the magic
flowing on this.
‐Mm‐hmm.
I think we need to head up
right over here because
this is right
at the base of the hill
and there's
a bunch of disturbed rocks.
Might be a good place to, uh,
‐to capture material
that has run off.
‐Okay.
‐(beeping)
‐It's also...
‐Oh!
NARRATOR:
Within just a few minutes of
taking over the metal detecting,
Giorgio gets a hit.
KIMBLER:
I heard something.
TSOUKALOS:
Yeah.
‐(beeping)
‐There is something.
KIMBLER:
Oh, my God.
(beeping continues)
KIMBLER:
There is something there
and we need to dig it up.
‐Let me help you find it.
‐Okay.
It's right here somewhere.
‐We'll find it.
‐It's right here.
‐We will find it.
‐(beeping)
KIMBLER:
You're on top of it.
‐You're right there.
‐Right there.
(beeping)
See if it's there.
It's in my hand.
Wow.
Now comes the hard part.
‐It's a‐a piece of wire.
‐(Tsoukalos and Howe laughing)
All right. Okay.
‐A tiny little piece of wire.
‐Little wire.
KIMBLER:
We're gonna keep it. We're gonna
take it and have it analyzed
because maybe it's got
something in it that's weird.
Let's still investigate this.
KIMBLER:
We need to take it
and‐and have it tested.
NARRATOR:
Giorgio hands off
the metal detector to Linda,
who continues along the gouge.
Just a few feet from
where Giorgio detected
‐a piece of wire...
‐(beeping)
‐Oh.
...they get another hit.
(beeping)
‐All right. Oh.
‐Pick up your, uh,
your bracelet, too.
I tell you what,
let's, um, dump it,
dump it into this hand,
right here.
There we go.
It's another piece of wire.
TSOUKALOS:
This is strange‐looking, though.
‐Why is it so
twisted and mangled?
‐I have no idea.
TSOUKALOS:
You said that
if there was debris,
this would be one of the places
because of the geographic, uh...
‐terrain right here.
‐It's, it's runoff,
and this is what I've used time
and time again to find stuff.
NARRATOR:
As far as Giorgio and Linda
are concerned,
any metal objects found in
the so‐called "gouge" area
are worth examining.
Is it possible that these
bits of wire represent debris
from the 1947 crash that was
overlooked by the military?
NARRATOR:
Sergeant Melvin E. Brown,
who served in
the 509th Atomic Bomb Squadron
for the U. S. Army Air Force,
lies on his deathbed
at a local hospital.
With his dying words,
Brown reveals to his family
a secret that he has kept hidden
for nearly 40 years‐‐
a secret about
what he saw in 1947
when he was stationed
in Roswell, New Mexico.
Sergeant Melvin Brown is another
key player in all of this.
He was rounded up
by higher command
in the aftermath of the crash.
He was essentially
put on guard duty.
And, intriguingly, there were
some low flatbed lorries
with tarpaulins over them.
SCHMITT:
The first opportunity he got,
he peeked inside
the back of the truck.
And there, under a canvas tarp,
were two of the bodies
from the crash site.
When he was on his deathbed,
he brought up Roswell.
Days before he passed away,
he talked about,
"It was not a weather balloon.
It wasn't from here.
And I saw two of the bodies,
and they were not human."
POPE:
Deathbed testimony is a critical
part of the Roswell story.
There are several.
There are many reasons
why some of the witnesses
stayed quiet for so long:
fear, threats.
All of this plays a part.
NARRATOR:
Many UFO researchers
believe that,
much like these
deathbed testimonies,
it is only a matter of time
before physical evidence
of a crashed extraterrestrial
craft finally surfaces.
And some even suggest
that such evidence
has already been recovered.
HOWE:
Here it is, right here.
NARRATOR:
One day after uncovering wires
near the Roswell skip site,
Giorgio Tsoukalos and
Linda Moulton Howe have traveled
to Theta Plate Lab,
where they are met
by owner Aaron Velasquez.
HOWE:
Hi.
It's good to finally meet you.
‐Welcome.
‐Hello.
NARRATOR:
Geologist Frank Kimbler
arrived earlier with
the metal fragments
he has collected
over the past eight years
in and around
the Roswell crash site.
Hey, Frank.
Good to see you again.
‐It's good to see you guys.
We're‐we're good.
‐Good to see you again.
‐Ready for some testing?
‐We're ready for some testing.
This is the exciting part.
‐Excellent.
‐I've been waiting for this.
NARRATOR:
Professor Kimbler's fragments
will be scientifically tested,
along with the wires they found
in the desert just yesterday
to determine
their elemental makeup.
VELASQUEZ:
So, we're gonna use
this machine.
It's an X‐ray
florescence machine.
It can do
materials identification,
so we're gonna hit it
with an X‐ray beam
and it'll tell us
what it can tell us.
So, it has the ability
to show us the elements that are
in this within a certain range,
is that right?
‐VELASQUEZ: Correct, correct.
‐Mm‐hmm.
Okay, here we go.
So, we're seeing
a big peak here.
This is iron. All right.
What else seems like a match?
Well...
Selenium.
KIMBLER:
What in the world?
Yeah, that‐that is
exactly my reaction.
‐Yeah.
‐What is selenium
doing with that?
KIMBLER:
I know that selenium is used
in the electronics industry
for semiconductors.
Let's go ahead and, uh,
take a look at
the second wire, please.
‐That there is... selenium.
‐This is selenium.
‐Still?
‐VELASQUEZ: Yeah.
NARRATOR:
The makeup of
the second wire fragment
appears to be nearly identical
to the first.
Might the presence of selenium,
a semiconductor,
indicate that they were part of
an electronic device?
‐KIMBLER: This one.
‐VELASQUEZ: Okay.
NARRATOR:
Frank has also brought with him
a number of metal pieces
that he has gathered
in the same area over the years,
and has yet to test.
So, it looks like
it's a match for iron.
But I'm curious about
that little shoulder.
Copper.
‐KIMBLER: Okay.
‐Copper...
So, I mean,
it's dead‐on copper match.
‐KIMBLER: So, we know we've got
some copper in there.
‐Mm‐hmm.
And then this stuff over here...
I'd call it a good match
for zirconium.
KIMBLER:
For zirconium?
‐Wow.
‐Yeah.
That would be unusual.
VELASQUEZ:
This is a good match
for molybdenum.
KIMBLER:
So, now we've got not only
zirconium in there,
but we have molybdenum.
And those are considered
impurities, Giorgio,
but they shouldn't be there.
But what does that mean when
you say it shouldn't be there?
KIMBLER:
Because that's unusual
for any alloys
that I've looked at previously.
It's part of
our high‐tech industry.
VELASQUEZ:
It's weird for me, too.
So, you'd see molybdenum
in a stainless steel,
but not an iron copper alloy.
‐KIMBLER: Yeah.
‐VELASQUEZ: Yeah.
‐KIMBLER: I agree with that.
‐TSOUKALOS: Okay.
‐I like it.
‐And zirconium has been found
in some cases
where material has been tested
and it was somehow
related to a crash.
‐I've run across that myself.
‐Zirconium.
NARRATOR:
In 2009, a Freedom of
Information Act request
brought to light
a research study
conducted at Wright‐Patterson
Air Force Base in 1949,
the site in Ohio where the
wreckage from Roswell was taken.
According to released documents,
metallurgists discovered
zirconium
while examining pieces of
strange metal
recovered in
the New Mexico desert.
Is this a piece that you found
where we were walking around?
Absolutely.
In fact, if we could bring
the picture back up,
there's an interesting
little part on this
because this is one
that I talked about before
that has
explosive cratering on it
because it went through
an explosion,
and I can show that
and prove it on that piece.
‐So, do you need me
to scan around?
‐Right...
‐See that right there?
‐VELASQUEZ: That pit?
KIMBLER:
That pit right there is
an explosive crater.
NARRATOR
Explosive cratering?
Could this
curious feature indicate
that the metal fragments
Frank found,
in separate locations
near Roswell,
came from exploded objects?
Perhaps even one or more
extraterrestrial crafts?
As the team tests
the rest of the metal fragments,
they are surprised to discover
that nearly all of them seem to
have the same elemental makeup.
There's definitely a similarity.
I mean, it looks like
it's the same material.
It's just
in different proportions.
(clicks tongue)
Boy.
VELASQUEZ:
So, it could be the same stuff.
‐KIMBLER: I think
we have the proof.
‐HOWE: Yeah.
KIMBLER:
We just need to get
more testing done.
I can't wait to learn
what we'll find out next.
NARRATOR:
The battery of tests
being performed by the U. S. Army
on Linda's layered metal
fragments could take months
or even years.
In the meantime,
the material collected
from the Roswell skip site
has been sent to another lab
for further analysis.
But curiously, one element
that has already been detected
in Professor Kimbler's materials
has also been found
in another metal fragment
suspected to be debris
from a UFO,
and from a location
on the other side of the world.
NARRATOR:
The Roswell incident remains
the most well‐known
UFO event in history,
but there have been reports
of numerous other UFO crashes
all over the world,
as well as the recovery
of strange metal debris.
In 1991, geologists searching
for gold deposits
in Russia's Ural Mountains made
a highly unexpected discovery.
At depths of over 30 feet,
they found a scattering of
tiny metal coils and springs.
CHILDRESS:
Russian scientists are finding
these tiny nanoparticles.
They found thousands
of these things.
They have to look at them
through microscopes.
They're‐they're‐‐
Some of them are just
one ten‐thousandth of an inch,
you know, in size.
There are all kinds of spirals
and tiny machined bits.
When they look at it, they seem
to be exactly like the kind of
tiny nanoparticles
and machine bits
that we are creating today.
What you see under the electron
microscope is mind‐boggling
because you see spirals.
You see definitely something
where the scientists
who investigated this
came to the conclusion
that these items are
artificially made
out of tungsten and molybdenum.
And so that right there
is incredibly interesting
because that was found exactly
at the skip site.
NARRATOR:
Molybdenum is the same material
detected in the metal fragments
that Frank Kimbler found
in the desert outside Roswell.
It is a super‐strong element
commonly used
in NASA spacecraft.
YURI KARASH:
These microscopic spirals
were made of wolfram
and molybdenum.
The melting temperature
for wolfram is above
6,000 degrees Fahrenheit,
and for molybdenum is about
5,000 degrees Fahrenheit.
TRAVIS TAYLOR:
Some, uh, version of NASA
from some other star system
could send a probe here
to Earth, and it could fail, uh,
and crash into Earth, and‐and
we would look at it and think,
"Wow, where did this come from?"
Maybe one day, we might be
creating our own Roswell
when we send our first probe
to the nearest star.
NARRATOR:
Ancient astronaut theorists
point out
that dozens of visitors to
the Ural Mountains have reported
encounters with strange,
cigar‐shaped craft
trailing fire across the sky.
Could this be
the Russian Roswell?
Indeed, people living
in the Ural Mountains,
maybe more often than, uh,
people living in
other parts of Russia,
witness some strange phenomena
in the air and on the ground.
PAUL STONEHILL:
Ural Mountains are
a very interesting space
in the paranormal history
of Russia.
And I've studied a lot
because there have always been
incredible UFO sightings
in the Ural Mountains.
There are stories
of civilizations
that have disappeared
or went under the ground.
Uh, the so‐called, uh, dwarf
people in the Ural Mountains.
NARRATOR:
If the nanoparticles discovered
in the Ural Mountains are debris
from a crashed alien craft,
they bring up another
intriguing possibility,
because based on how deep below
the earth they were found,
they could have been deposited
there thousands of years ago.
There's thinking that
these things must be
over 50,000 years old.
So, is this also a debris field
from a crashed extraterrestrial
craft in the Ural Mountains?
There could be crash sites
all over the world
that are hundreds of thousands
of years old,
right up to modern times.
NARRATOR:
Rumors abound that
there are facilities
located all over the world
holding the remnants
of crashed
extraterrestrial craft,
like in the remote hills
of China,
at Pine Gap in Australia,
and Rudloe Manor in England.
TSOUKALOS:
Who knows if over the chronology
of the history of planet Earth
there were more craft, just like
at Roswell, that crashed?
NARRATOR:
Is it possible that Roswell is
just one of many locations
on planet Earth
where debris from
crashed extraterrestrial craft
can be found?
Perhaps further testing that was
conducted on the metal fragments
unearthed near the Roswell
skip site will reveal
indisputable evidence
of alien visitation.
NARRATOR:
Giorgio Tsoukalos meets
Linda Moulton Howe at her home
two weeks after sending out
the materials collected
at the Roswell crash site to
a laboratory in Dallas, Texas,
for further testing.
Aaron Velasquez, who performed
the initial testing,
has received and analyzed
the data.
‐Hi, Aaron.
‐Good to see you again.
How are you?
Nice to see you guys.
I've been well.
We're sitting here
on pins and needles.
So, what can you show us?
So, we found that, of the
samples of Frank's material,
three of them,
while they look like the rest,
have a very, very high
concentration of carbon in them.
Much more than the aluminum,
despite what they look like.
There's been some supposition
that that could be
from high heat.
So that was odd.
But odder still is we had
one sample of the five
which had
indium, which is
a very rare element.
So it's not the sort of thing
that you would get
by accident, guaranteed.
So are we talking
about something
that's really strange here?
Yes. Yes.
Well, uh, what about
those wires that we found?
Yeah.
So, that is also odd.
So, the elements that
we found with the wire
were all explainable, except
it, too, had indium in it.
What about evidence
of impact and heat?
Yes, that's another thing
that we noted.
It was very obvious
under the scanning
electron microscope
that these had been subjected
to very, very high heat.
They were melted.
There was also
some shearing apparent.
So, these were, these were
cut or sliced by...
by some action as well over
the years, or‐or at an impact.
That's‐that's incredible.
Yes, it's very interesting.
NARRATOR:
For Giorgio and Linda,
the results are nothing less
than astonishing.
Multiple tests have now
confirmed that the materials
recovered at
the Roswell skip site
are of a highly unusual nature,
and show evidence of having been
subjected to an explosion.
Might the strange layered
material being examined
by the U. S. Army prove to be
even more extraordinary?
HOWE:
In the bismuth, magnesium, zinc,
we're dealing with technologies
that astound people
who are in exotic metals
because they couldn't make
the bismuth, magnesium, zinc,
and a physicist tells me
this is the key.
This is the crux of
how this kind of technology
makes possible
the unidentified flying objects
move in such astounding ways.
MAN:
Whoa!
And in this whole issue
of finding
more materials from UFOs,
I'm still on the trail.
TSOUKALOS: Oftentimes,
I'm told that to suggest that
a UFO, an extraterrestrial
craft, crashed at Roswell
is nonsensical because
extraterrestrials can fly
across the galaxy,
and then they crash on Earth?
Well, yeah. You know why?
'Cause it's technology,
and technology fails.
I think that there may be more
material there to be found.
NARRATOR:
Is physical evidence
of an extraterrestrial presence
on Earth right beneath our feet?
Could there be debris
from crashed alien craft
not only in
the New Mexico desert
but all across the world?
Perhaps the materials that have
already been recovered
will soon provide
the ultimate proof
that we are not alone
in the universe,
or even on our own planet.
CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
A+E NETWORKS