Free Bobby to ride free!
- Who's Bobby?
- He's their president.
He's on trial in there for running
a meth lab out of his garage.
Bobby's riding five to seven,
what Bobby's riding.
Back behind your bikes, guys!
...free! Free Bobby to ride...
It's a free country, Porky!
- Back behind your bikes now.
- We got a right
- to be heard!
- Behind your bikes, you do.
Free Bobby to ride free!
Hey! Hey! Hey, what's going on?
I'm an uncle. I'm an uncle.
Walsh, behind you!
Where is Officer Janko?!
Excuse me, ma'am, we're a little busy.
- Please take a seat.
- I need to speak to her now.
Ma'am, we're gonna have to
ask you to calm down, please.
I'm not going to calm down until
you bring me Officer Janko.
She's not here now. Maybe
I can help you with something?
Yeah. You could start by explaining
why I got a doctor
badgering me and calling my house
after my car accident last week.
I'm sorry, what does this
have to do with Officer Janko?
I was in a single-car crash.
- Uh-huh.
- She's the only person
that knows about this accident
besides me,
and she filed a damn report.
- Did you go to the hospital?
- No.
- File a claim?
- I didn't even tell my husband,
'cause I knew he'd have a fit.
Look, I'm-I'm sure
it's probably a coincidence.
I've read about cops
selling accident reports
- like this before.
- I think you might
be getting ahead of yourself.
Here's the information.
Dr. Mehta.
Janko must have tipped off the doctor,
who knows who else?
All right.
And you were alone in the store
when the robbers entered?
I'm-I'm always the first one in.
I thought the front door was locked
when I opened up the safe
and started taking inventory
of the jewels, but he entered,
pulled the gun, pointed
it right at my face.
And did he push you or hit you?
No. He just said...
"Call the cops and you're dead."
So I just stood there and
watched him empty out the safe.
Well, you did the smart thing.
Can he find me?
What do you mean?
I-I don't know how this works.
Is a crime report public?
My name as a witness?
No. Police report is not made public.
So he can't, right?
Full disclosure.
A new fairness law
went into effect recently.
It requires us to hand over
witnesses' contact information
to the defense attorneys.
You mean, like my address?
Well, yes, but just to the attorneys.
How is that fairness?
I mean, what about
the witnesses, the victims?
How-How's that fair to us?
Katie, Goodman is in Rikers
until the trial.
There is nothing to worry about.
Ms. Hodge?
I was in the building,
thought I'd save myself a trip later.
Goodman case files?
Yes. It's been 15 days.
You're now required by law
to give over the witnesses' information.
Actually, the law says
15 days from arraignment,
so I have two more hours.
So you're one of those.
One of what?
I just think it's a sin
to waste a colleague's time.
I am happy to save you a trip.
Do me a favor?
Treat this like the loaded weapon it is.
Kind of an overstatement.
Well, maybe.
But your client is
a repeat violent offender.
So yes, the new law says I have
to hand over the contacts.
It does not say you need to download
all the names and addresses to him.
I will do whatever I see fit
to make sure that my client
receives a fair trial.
I am sure you will.
You have a good day.
I will certainly try.
And at 10:30 you are
meeting with Chief Kimura
to review her proposal
on new mental health
training initiatives.
At 11:00...
Push back my 11:00.
I'm gonna need more time with Kimura.
All right. So 11:30?
- Good.
- Great. So at 11:30
you will meet
with Chief Fitzgerald about...
Could it wait five minutes?
We are almost done.
Actually, no, it can't.
A lawsuit's just been filed
against the department
claiming excessive force
was used during an arrest.
So? We get those complaints all the time.
The plaintiff is an NYPD detective
who's been deep undercover
the last nine months.
Our officer
didn't know he was
taking down a fellow cop.
What do we got?
Vic is a white male in his 50s
found this morning by a jogger.
Wife, kids and the nanny were
asleep up their apartment.
His name is Felix Roth.
- Like the photographer?
- Beats me.
His wife's upstairs... you can
ask her if he takes pictures.
You think?
We got it from here.
Danny, this guy's been all over the news
the past couple of weeks.
- What'd he do?
- Well, more like
what didn't he do?
A ton of his former models
came forward claiming sexual assault.
It's up to, like, 20 now,
- and counting. Real nasty stuff, too.
- Really?
So 'twas beauty killed the beast.
Synced & corrected by -robtor-
www.addic7ed.com
That's the wife, Allie Roth.
All right, thanks.
Mrs. Roth?
Detective Reagan.
This is my partner, Detective Baez.
Wanted to offer our condolences.
Thank you.
I'm sure this has been
a very difficult time
for your family already,.
The past few weeks have been hell.
When's the last time
you saw your husband?
Three days ago.
I asked him to stay at a hotel
until everything blew over.
Any idea why he
would come back here last night?
Not a clue.
I have no idea why he'd
be dropping by at that hour.
Where are Thatcher and Everest?
In the playroom.
Detectives, this is our nanny, Melissa.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to check on my kids.
Of course.
Uh, I'm Detective Reagan.
This is my partner, Detective Baez.
Would you mind if we
ask you a few questions?
- Mm-hmm.
- How long have you worked
for the Roths?
- Um, about a year.
- Is there anything unusual
- we should know about them?
- There's nothing usual
about them.
But Felix was a great father.
He loved his children.
Mm-hmm. Do you live here?
No. I-I live with my dad in the Bronx.
But I do stay over when I work
late and have to be in early.
So you were here last night?
- I was.
- Did you see
or hear anyone enter
or leave the apartment?
No. Uh, Mrs. Roth went to bed before me,
and I didn't hear anything
until the doorman came in with the news.
Any chance Mrs. Roth might have
been involved in this?
God, no. Of course not.
I... I mean, they had their issues,
but she loved him.
She could never.
Did you ever see Mr. Roth
bring another woman back here?
No. He wasn't sneaking around.
But you have heard the accusations?
You mean the lies?
He wasn't that kind of man.
Okay? He... he was a lot of things,
but he wasn't the monster
they made him out to be.
Hey, Sarge. Heard you wanted to see me.
Do you remember a woman
by the name of Donna Davis?
You wrote an accident report
for her last week.
Oh, yeah, how could I forget?
She was a hot mess. She
ran a car into a stop sign.
Who does that?
So you...
completed that report?
Yeah. I was... I was riding with Long,
but... I completed the report.
You have any idea
how that accident report
could have ended up in the hands
of some ambulance chaser named Dr. Mehta?
- Wait. What?
- Or do you think
that Long could have sold it
or shared it?
Long? No.
No chance he could've let it
slip into the wrong hands?
No, there's no way.
What is with the third degree?
I hate to say it,
but your partners since me
haven't exactly had
the best track record.
First it was Maya, then Troy...
It's like it's becoming a pattern.
Okay, well, here's a pattern.
Once a report has been processed,
every officer in this precinct
has access to it.
Okay, we'll have to start by following up
with the officer who wrote it.
Wait, you're no longer my sergeant...
You should have given this
- to McNichols to look into.
- If I gave it to McNichols,
she would send it right over
to IAB, as per protocol.
I'm trying to help you out
by getting to the bottom of this.
Well, I don't need your help.
I haven't done anything wrong.
Detective Alex Porter
filed the suit, but he
won't pop as a cop.
- How come?
- He used his undercover name.
- So, one good thing.
- Two good things.
Porter's been embedded for nine months
with the Satan's Bishops motorcycle gang.
They hate cops.
And how is that a good thing?
Means he probably started
the fight and escalated it...
Another layer of his cover.
And filing a lawsuit for damages
was also part of the play.
Please walk me through the allegations.
Porter was part of a protest
outside the courthouse
where the club's president is being tried
on drugs and weapons charges.
Conner and the cops stepped in...
Conner's a first-rate cop, boss.
...when the gang
advanced on the courthouse.
Fights broke out.
Body cams.
Conner was working the detail in uniform,
but he's a detective assigned
to the 3-6 squad.
So he's not required to wear a body cam.
Exactly.
Cell phone video.
None that have surfaced.
Well, there's one out there.
There always is, so find it.
Because we shouldn't
talk to our undercover.
It's not worth the risk.
Well... I'm afraid
that's gonna be my decision.
I'm just saying these bikers
watch each other like hawks.
Their main business
is running illegal firearms
up here from down south.
- I know that.
- There's no loyalty
to a cause, a movement, a religion.
Just a bunch of mercenaries and pirates.
Nobody trusts anybody
despite all the blood oaths
and sacred bonds.
I know that, too.
I saw this documentary.
Let me talk to Conner.
So he can tell you how innocent he is
and you can tell me?
I'm afraid that's only half the story.
Boss, I know Conner. He's a good cop.
Let me get a read. That's my job.
No, that's procedure.
The job is to get a read,
and if it's squirrelly,
report that fact back to me.
Copy that, boss.
Well, it's about time.
I was with Chatwal.
Why's it always got to be you
that stands up to the D.A.?
I don't know.
I guess all of my colleagues
care about the future of their jobs.
And what was your angle?
That you can't have
huge policy changes
without being prepared
on the retail level.
I mean, it's our fault we're not ready,
and the cracks are starting to show.
And when you say our fault,
you mean his fault?
Implied.
But he's not willing to do anything
that might indicate that...
the new laws are anything but perfect.
So we all got to suffer
because of this guy's ego?
Yes, and his reelection chances,
- of course.
- Damn it.
What?
Katie Gray's on her way
to St. Benjamin in an ambulance.
Let's go.
And when I reached down for my keys...
I felt someone behind me.
He shoved me up against the door.
Hit me in my face.
And he threw me on the ground.
We're gonna find whoever did this.
Not with my help.
You told me not to worry.
Now look at me.
I understand...
why you feel that way.
But this robbery doesn't
necessarily connect to Goodman.
Okay, you got proof?
No.
Then please, just leave.
Let's just give her
some time to calm down.
She's right not to trust me.
Yeah, but you're not
the one that hurt her.
Are you the assigned A.D.A.?
Uh, no, she's a witness in another case.
Did you bring her in?
I was the first on the scene.
And it matches a string of robberies
in her neighborhood and...
And then beaten up?
No, just the purses with the others.
So it's not really a match.
Well, not...
exactly, no.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
This was a loud and clear
warning not to testify.
Yeah, but Marcus Goodman
is still at Rikers.
So, he outsourced it.
Look, we owe it
to the rest of the witnesses
on that list to keep them safe.
I agree.
Did you know that Roth's wife Allie
was a model, too?
Yeah, it says here she was
one of his first muses.
Yeah, well, it says in this interview
that they had sex the day they met.
During a photo shoot.
Right on the studio floor.
Soho in the '80s. Times were different.
Thanks, Debbie Harry.
The point I'm trying to make is,
that's the same exact move
that all these young women
are accusing him of now.
The move he made on his
wife back in the day.
So?
So, if he liked them young
back when he met his wife,
maybe he still likes them young.
And she got sick of being
traded in for newer models,
and finally snapped.
Yes.
I've heard of weaker motives.
Think she's done grieving?
Let's go find out.
I was new to the city,
I was broke,
and he made me an overnight success.
He gave me my life.
Yeah, how did it feel
to watch him continue
to do that to younger girls
year after year?
I didn't watch.
We didn't talk about it.
But, yeah, I knew.
That's why I wanted out.
And that's why you murdered your husband?
Seriously?
Dead serious.
God, no. No, that's...
that's why I brought the models he abused
to the reporter who broke the story.
What are you talking about?
I'd never see our kids again
if I filed for divorce.
What makes you say that?
Felix is famous and powerful
and highly functional.
And I'm washed up and under
treatment for depression.
So he would've gotten
custody, no doubt about it.
Even my lawyer said so.
Okay, so let me get this straight.
You're telling us that you purposely
orchestrated your husband's downfall?
It's easy math, Detectives.
No more Felix,
no more Felix-signed prints.
Yes, I killed his reputation.
But I did not kill my husband.
She's holding out on something.
Well, according to the nanny, she was
in the apartment the entire time.
Okay, well, where's the nanny today?
Could be her day off?
Well it's not our day off.
I say we lean in on the nanny.
Find out what she really
thinks of her dear family
and beloved boss.
That's what they got you doing, Sid...
Retail interviews on civilian complaints?
Just when they pop.
How'd this pop?
How about I ask the questions?
Shoot.
Chain of events.
These Satan's Bishops guys
were advancing on the courthouse.
We were under orders to
keep them at the curb.
We ordered them back, they kept going.
- Who laid hands first?
- The biker.
- And you did what?
- Pushed him away.
He kept coming, so I took him down.
- Choke hold?
- No.
- Choke hold light?
- I got a grip.
For, like, five seconds.
He was pretty greasy...
You've seen these guys.
Hard to get a handle on them.
- Uh-huh.
- It's all about money.
The way the city pays out,
it's like cops are ATMs.
Burns my ass, too.
So you know what I'm saying.
Loud and clear.
- But here's the thing.
- Hmm?
Is there any chance you might've
been a little too aggressive?
I know I acted fairly.
And besides, you've seen these guys,
these bikers... They're dirt bags.
Can't affect how you treat them.
I know that.
It was all clean.
- Mm-hmm.
- By the book.
And every other guy on the scene
will attest to that.
They got my back.
Uh-huh, they got your back.
Or...
they're hiding the truth.
You have any more questions,
I'll see you with a union rep present.
All right, fair enough.
What the hell happened to you, Sid?
You used to be one of us.
Hey, Long.
What's up, Sarge?
Ask you something? Have you
ever been to a Dr. Mehta?
Yeah. You looking for a new doc?
Just curious.
Well, he's a great guy.
Been helping cops and
their families for years.
Doesn't matter if the stuff is covered.
He's never turned away a boy in blue.
Ah, so, you recommend him?
You bet your ass I would.
Plus, he's been struggling lately.
All these fancy new
urgent cares popping up
all over the city... it's
tough for an old school
GP like him to keep afloat.
That why you've been
feeding him accident reports?
Excuse me?
It's been going on, and you
just laid out a perfect reason
why a good guy might
do something like that.
Hey, boss...
just move along?
Is that a threat?
There's nothing to see here, I promise.
You know, there's still
no proof that Katie's
assault was tied to Marcus.
This isn't on you.
I know, just find Ms. Stewart,
offer her protection.
Just play it safe until we know more.
You're not gonna be able to
protect every witness like this.
Why? There's only five of them.
Yeah, I mean, as this problem grows.
Asking cops to watch out
for witnesses and victims
of every case that
this office is prosecuting
is completely unrealistic.
Chatwal is not gonna ask for
special help from One PP.
You know 'cause you asked?
Yeah, and he tore me up.
I can see why she likes
staying over at the Roths.
Yeah, me, too.
Melissa, it's Detective
Reagan and Baez. Open up.
Melissa isn't home.
You're her father?
Hector Rodriguez.
Do you mind if we come in
just for a minute,
ask you a few questions?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Thanks.
That's a beautiful statue.
Reminds me of my mother's.
That was passed down
to me from my mother.
Oh, yeah? Where you from?
- Monte Cristi.
- Dominican Republic?
Melissa was born here, though.
- I have the papers.
- That's okay.
We're not worried about
her immigration status.
We're more interested in her former boss.
Felix Roth?
I never approved
of her work for that man.
- Why not?
- The money she earned
was coming directly from sales
of his sinful photos.
I told her she wasn't allowed to go back
and must quit.
Well, she didn't quit, did she?
No.
She disobeyed me, went back to work,
and now she's mixed up
in this murder investigation.
- Right.
- Have you noticed anything
off about her recently?
She acting any differently?
I barely recognize her anymore.
Do you know where she is?
We had a fight.
She took off.
What did you two fight about?
She told me she was pregnant.
Does she have a boyfriend?
What's it matter?
She said she wanted to get rid of it.
My grandchild.
Do you know where she went
after you two had a fight?
I've been calling her
but she won't answer.
Melissa was calling and texting
a number registered to
Felix Roth Studios all hours.
Felix had a second number?
Yep.
- His business.
- Mm-hmm.
So maybe Melissa was
more than just his nanny.
Explains why she defended him.
Also explains something else.
What?
She's pregnant.
What if Felix is the father?
Explains why Mrs. Roth
would have been angry enough to kill him.
Yeah. Now we just have to explain
why Mrs. Roth sent Melissa
a $10,000 Venmo payment.
Uh, maybe a very generous
Christmas bonus?
At the end of January?
Well, what do you think it is,
hush money?
There's only way to find out.
Forget Conner's a cop.
Think of him as a perp.
You still buying the whole hog?
Yes.
The whole hog?
I don't think what happened
rises to the level
of a complaint and a payout.
Payout?
- Yeah.
- Policy on settling complaints
is not in your purview. Clear?
- Yes.
- Nor is being
the rank and file's favorite uncle.
Well, those days are gone.
Give me a break. You bucking
to be back in a precinct?
- No.
- Then cut it out.
My account of the conversation
would be that Detective Conner
used appropriate force.
Okay? He framed his recounting
in a way that might help
keep his balls out of the wringer,
which is insurance
any smart cop would take out.
Come in.
I just got word
that two more citizens arrested
at that protest filed similar complaints.
"Citizens"? You know
what those guys call themselves?
Satan's Bishops!
Don't give me "citizens."
Porter's a cop!
I would remind you
that the first complaint
came from one of our own.
Yes, sir.
Anything I can do?
Yeah.
Can you do the impossible?
I can have this ready
for you in five minutes.
- Hey.
- Yeah. Perfect.
Hey. Uh, I'm glad I caught you.
Did you talk to Long?
Yeah. He said there's nothing to see.
Jamie, I really think
that you should just drop
this whole thing.
Which is a lot different
than saying I know nothing about this.
I got to take this to IAB.
No, you don't.
Yeah, of course I do.
Jamie, this is a lot
bigger than you think.
Okay.
What does... what does that mean?
Multiple cops, multiple precincts.
All feeding this guy reports?
That's what I'm hearing.
- Then I got to do something.
- No.
You got to get to the bottom of it.
That's what you got to do.
These guys are passing out
people's private information.
They are breaking the law.
Do you ever consider how this affects me?
What are you talking about?
All these guys,
they think that I'm a rat,
and I'm coming in and running
and I'm tattling to the boss.
That is not what I meant to happen.
Then handle it.
There's dinner in the fridge.
You cooked?
It tastes a lot like the taco truck
from up the street.
You ever feel like you woke up
in an alternate universe?
Like a, um, like an Opposite Day?
No, more like an Opposite World.
Where it's like what?
Where it's like the one person
in this murder case
who liked the victim, who
actually stood up for the victim
is suddenly nowhere to be found.
But all the likely suspects
are everywhere to be found?
Exactly. The betrayed wife,
the young women
he's accused of assaulting
throughout the years,
they're all ready, willing
and able to cooperate 24/7.
I got one of my cops
accusing another of my
cops of excessive force.
I guess that's an Opposite World.
The cop got a beef
with the cop they're accusing?
Well... it's, uh, complicated.
Oh. Well, who do you believe?
Okay. I mean, here's the thing.
In my usual world,
I could just lean in on
the officer's account.
I know their training.
I know the oath that they take.
Hell, I recited it to most of them.
But in this case,
they're both my officers.
Hmm. I guess that's Opposite World.
There you go.
I think you might be onto something here.
Wow. If you agree with me,
- then I know it must be Opposite World.
- No.
I'm trying to wrap my head around why
I'm now required by law
to hand over the witnesses' names,
addresses, everything
to the attorney for the defendant.
As in the attorney
- can share it with the defendant?
- It's like,
just, "Here it is. Here's everyone
"that is going to testify against you
and how to get ahold of 'em."
It's like I woke up in...
Telling you, it's a real thing.
Now you guys got me thinking like this.
- How's that?
- I got these cops that I think
are sidelining as shills for
a doc-in-a-box in our precinct,
and I haven't sent it up to IAB yet.
You didn't hear that.
Hey, hear what?
Because something tells me
that maybe things aren't what they seem.
In Opposite World.
- Opposite World.
- That's right.
Opposite World.
Telling you.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm not gonna do this again.
Do what?
I know that look.
Yes, I need your help.
And there it is.
Call Baker and make an appointment.
I'd like to keep this off the books.
And I would rather keep a
separation of church and state
between you and me.
Our witnesses and victims are at risk
with this new disclosure law.
Laws I had no hand in writing.
You didn't write 'em, any of 'em,
but you do uphold them.
Why are you carrying
Chatwal's water again?
Look, he is not going to ask
for extra protection
because he thinks it will reflect poorly
on the criminal justice reform
that he championed.
And he'd be right.
My fight
is for the innocent people at risk,
and I need your help.
Erin, I will do everything I can
to keep those people safe.
But your office needs
to work out flaws in your system.
Your office.
Not mine.
How was the tour?
Another day at the office.
Uneventful, huh?
- Just the way you like it?
- Look,
I know you think
you got to turn this over.
I get it.
- But just do me one favor, okay?
- What's that?
Come meet me here at
the end of your tour.
You want me to wait to make
the notification to IAB?
Please, boss. I'm not a bad guy.
I'm trying to do the right thing here.
Just trust me, okay?
One condition.
Anything.
You lay off Eddie and spread the word.
She had nothing to do with this.
Someone's at the door.
Henry.
Seven Pillars of Wisdom author.
Starts with a "T."
T.E. Lawrence.
Thanks.
So, how are you doing, Detective?
Okay.
Except for this.
Want to sit down?
Sure.
Coffee?
So, you got a problem with this meeting.
Yeah.
Yes... sir.
Okay. If you were me,
what would you have done?
Taken my word I was the victim
of excessive force
by an NYPD officer.
- A fellow detective.
- Yes,
which makes it even worse.
The higher up you rise,
the more you should know better.
We do take you at your word.
Then why the off-campus get-together?
Part of my job is to protect your cover.
But as you know, we do
have to get both sides.
And his side was... Let me guess...
Appropriate action
under the circumstances.
- That's about it.
- That being
his full weight on his knee in my kidney
and then his knee in my crotch,
with his mitt on my windpipe
and a kick to the head for dessert.
And it is your belief you sustained that
in your action with Detective Conner?
Yes, sir, that's my belief.
Okay, who put hands on first?
I did.
I'm playing a role.
I need to be convincing in that role.
I tried to tell him I was undercover.
I said it right to him. "I'm an uncle."
You sure he heard you?
Honestly, it...
it might have come out
a little messed up,
what with the choke hold he had on me.
So no.
But that doesn't clear him.
Why not let someone
else file a complaint?
Why is it you who goes the extra mile?
Come on.
Bunch of outlaw bikers crying
"that cop roughed me up"?
How seriously do you think
that would land?
You sent me undercover
to root out some bad guys.
You didn't say only these bad guys.
If I see the guns they run
up here getting delivered
to the Convent of the Sacred Heart,
I'm giving up the nuns.
Same as this cop.
That's how I see the job.
Here's some cell phone video
that caught my arrest.
You're welcome
for me not making it public.
This it?
TARU said Melissa's phone
pinged in the vicinity
of 37 Prince Street about 20 minutes ago.
- It's got to be it.
- Well, it looks like a doctor's office.
- It's a gynecologist.
- That appropriate?
- Should we wait outside?
- What? Are you serious?
We've been looking for her
for two days. For all we know,
she's probably come and gone.
We have to go inside.
Okay. We'll go inside.
Melissa, we need to talk to you.
This is none of your business.
No, it is our business.
Is Felix the father?
Yes.
Then, who found out about it
and killed him?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look, we know that Allie wired you money.
You've been on the run for two days.
Allie didn't kill him.
She could never. She...
She just told me
to lay low until the press dies down.
She gave me a place to stay,
paid for this appointment.
Well, your father thinks
you're not having this baby.
Yeah, well, I don't know how I'd
support it on my own. Don't you see?
Allie was kind enough
to make me an appointment here
to consider my options.
Kind enough?
She's not kind.
She's playing you.
If Felix is the father,
she'll have to share
half the estate with you.
And she's not gonna do that.
Okay, but Allie didn't kill him.
Then who did kill him?
Come on, Melissa. If you know
who killed him, you got to tell us.
I couldn't admit to him
that I'd had consensual sex,
so I told him Felix raped me, okay?
Like they said
he did to all the other girls.
When I told him, he said I was tainted.
He was more upset
than I had ever seen him, and...
Okay. Who is "he"?
Who is the "he" that killed Felix?
My father.
Hey.
Looking for Hector Rodriguez.
- Seen him?
- I don't know any Hector Rodriguez.
Says he don't know Hector.
Well, that's funny
'cause his daughter said
he practically lives here.
Yeah, I'm sorry. No Hector tonight.
So you do know Hector?
Hey! Talking to you.
Yeah, but he's not here.
Okay, play stupid.
Anybody want to point us in the
direction of Hector Rodriguez?
No? Okay.
Maybe we'll start checking
all your papers then, huh?
What do you say?
Hey. What the hell are you doing?
- Excuse me?
- What are you doing
right there with the button?
Where does the button ring?
Basement? Bathroom?
What?
Okay.
Step back.
You, move. Come on. Move!
All right.
Get back.
Hector?
- Hector! Hold it!
- Go! Go! Go!
Wait!
Hold it!
Hey!
Go!
Get your hands where I can see
'em right now! Get 'em up!
- All right. No, no, no, no.
- Hands up!
No, no, no, I got nothing.
Driver, get your hands up, too.
Keep 'em where
I can see 'em now! Hands up!
Out of the car. Come on.
Hands on the vehicle.
Right there.
I'm ready to atone for my sins.
I made a terrible mistake.
I didn't mean to hurt him,
but he called her a whore,
and laughing at me.
I'm so sorry.
Roth got what he deserved.
The judge'll decide what you get.
This morning,
the police arrested a suspect trying
to break in to one
of the witnesses' homes.
And this concerns me how?
The suspect is your client's
younger brother Michael.
He was found with Katie Gray's ID
and credit cards.
And he's not my client.
- His brother is.
- Wow.
- That's a fact.
- It's also
a fact that there's a direct line
from that witness list,
that you yourself took
from this office, to that suspect.
I had no idea.
Wasting people's time is a sin.
I am with you there.
But taking a flawed law
and using it
for your own personal gain...
That is a lot worse.
I am just doing what I'm paid for.
Said every coward ever. Now please leave.
All I did was review the list
of witnesses with my client.
- Get out.
- I didn't give...
Hello.
Now, what she did is
not wrong under the law.
All she did was
give her client the witness list
that we handed over.
So we'll fix it.
So, what are we gonna do?
Just give fake names and addresses?
Actually, that's not a bad idea.
Just feels like we keep pushing
the same mountain all the time.
Well, hey,
even if we only get an inch,
that's something, right?
We'll conduct a thorough investigation,
make sure this isn't a habit
he got covered up.
I watched the video.
He didn't just cross a line.
He drove right over it
- and then backed up again.
- No one just
wakes up one day
and decides to act like that.
Conner's our guy, too.
He deserves the benefit of the doubt.
Are you really still defending him?
He deserves due process.
No spin is gonna change what we saw.
Come on, guys. Whose
side are you on anyway?
Sid.
Boss?
Money and manpower on an investigation?
Seriously?
No?
No.
What's he got coming?
Um... you tell me.
No.
You tell me.
It's not for me to decide.
But I asked you.
Boss?
Lieutenant.
Place Detective Conner
on modified assignment
pending an investigation?
Slap on the wrist, given what we know.
Fleet services?
That kind of bad apple can do damage
we only learn about too late.
Better to be proactive.
Suspension, effective immediately.
Have the department advocate
prepare charges and specs.
Pretty harsh.
Yeah. Sends a message.
And that's your call?
Well... he left us no choice.
Then get on it.
Right away, boss.
Thanks for coming.
Jochens, what are you doing here?
You remember when I busted
my back at the Academy?
Of course.
Dr. Mehta's the one who got me
back on my feet.
All right, but that doesn't...
And remember when we took
that call at the Bedford Houses,
back when we were in the 12th?
Yeah, you went down pretty good.
- And I thought I wasn't gonna...
- Dr. Mehta
helped you recover.
- You starting to follow along?
- Yeah.
I understand
the doc here helped you all out,
but what you're doing is wrong.
Says who?
All we're doing is recommending a doc
we trust to people that
we helped out on the streets.
Actually, you're driving business
to the doc, using private information
that's entrusted to you
as NYPD police officers.
May I say something?
Shoot.
I could barely cover my rent already.
Then, last month,
they upped it on me again.
I was about to close up shop,
when these officers...
...got wind and came to my rescue.
You notice that fancy
- new urgent care next door?
- I'm sure
it doesn't help, but I can't
allow this to continue.
We came up with a compromise.
Which is?
We help him out the right way...
By recommending him
to friends, family, or
whoever we can get to listen.
No more using the reports.
And you expect me to just forget
about what went on up to now?
No, we... we don't expect it.
We... we're just asking for it.
No.
You never asked for it.
Copy that, boss.
Okay, nothing to see here.