Shochiku Presents
A Bandai/Shochiku Film
"BOILING POlNT"
Playing in
such a dusty place...
They're stupid.
Watching makes us worse.
Shut up! Damn you!
Did you come to take
a crap or play ball?
Why stay in the can so long?
Good !
Can't you guys
get any points?
So far, nothing.
Watch it! Get a hit!
At least get one point.
Too bad!
We'll try harder.
Next batter?
Akira, you're next!
Akira!
l need a coach.
Someone, go!
Go coach him.
Somebody who knows
more about baseball.
What are you saying? Ass!
Just standing is enough.
You go.
Watch the ball!
Give a sign.
Turn your hand or something.
Don't just watch.
Here we go!
What are you doing?
You're coaching
the other team.
Quit! Just pick up balls!
Pitcher! Look what
you've done!
You hit him on purpose!
What if something
happens to him?
Don't get so upset.
Shut up! Apologize!
That's enough.
l'm sorry.
l'm telling him off
for your sake.
lt's your fault!
This is the last inning.
Get at least one point.
Hopeless kids!
Don't sit on my glove.
Hey, you! Pinch-hit!
He won't make it.
Two out already.
Umpire, a pinch-hitter!
Go!
l'm giving you a chance.
Hit one!
Too high! lt's a strike?
Hit the next one!
Take a chance!
Never mind.
Pick a better ball.
Charment wins 5-0.
Take a bow!
You should've swung
your bat at least once.
Why be seated?
lt's over.
We've ten minutes left.
Play catch or something.
Go away!
Swing your bat 100 times
a day. You'll improve.
Come on, let's go!
Sorry for a while ago.
l get excited so easily.
You're late. What kept you?
l have a date. See?
Change clothes fast
and wash that Mercedes.
Wait a sec. l'll change.
l went to his place,
but he's missing.
Sure.
Nobody knows where he is.
Maybe he ran.
l'm at a gas station.
l'll be back in half an hour.
Sure. l'll be back soon.
My car... through already?
Speak up!
You haven't done
one damn thing!
The wheels are still dirty!
The ashtray...
l'm going. ls the tank full?
l don't know.
Not yet?
Hey!
Don't make light of me!
l'm sorry.
He hasn't done a thing.
What's going on?
lsn't this your job?
l'm sorry.
Dammit, do your
work properly!
l'm very sorry.
You do it right, or
l'll make you go broke!
What do you want?
No!
You goddam punk!
lt hurts! Maybe
my arm's broken.
l'll go see a doc.
How was it?
The doctor said
his arm is all right.
But his boss will come to
settle it. What'll we do?
Yes?
l took today off.
l have to deliver this.
Want to come?
Follow me.
You all right?
lt's fast. Be careful.
He has no license.
Which is better?
This one.
l don't want it.
He doesn't want it!
l want time off.
Hey, don't you have a date?
No.
Why not pick up a chick?
lt won't work.
Try and see.
l'll leave.
This is for you.
Try, okay?
What time do you finish?
We close at 11.
Got a motorcycle?
Want to come?
Where are you going?
You listening?
Don't glare at us.
This road's wide enough.
Be more careful!
We're gangsters.
We can't go to the cops.
Just do what you can.
We'll pay his medical fee.
We're mobsters, but
l'm not here to threaten you.
We don't want to cause
a fuss in the neighborhood.
Just do what you can.
Thank you.
We'll pay the medical fee.
We're gangsters. Don't you
know what we're here for?
You did it?
Why not join us?
A gangster came.
He from the Otomo Group?
You hit his man, right?
He hit me first.
You shouldn't have
fought back.
So, he came
to bulldoze you.
What'll you do?
l'll go to their office.
You will? What for?
We'll talk and settle it.
No, you can't.
You were with Otomo, right?
Welcome!
Go with him.
What a sty!
Anyway we can drink.
Want a highball?
Can't make one?
Pork cutlet on rice.
Make it highballs.
Got a john?
Over there.
l bet it's dirty.
Probably so.
Got an ashtray?
Shall l sing?
What's wrong?
lt was filthy!
lt absolutely reeks!
Piss outside then!
Get out!
How's business?
Today's customers are lousy.
They borrow but
don't pay back.
The world's nuts.
Hi, Mr. lguchi!
Muto, how have you been?
l talked with Otomo.
About that gas station...
Whatever happened,
will you overlook it?
My man's arm was broken.
We can't ignore it.
Do as l say!
Mr. lguchi, didn't you
quit being a gangster?
You're no longer my boss.
Mr. lguchi, huh?
From now on l'll
just call you lguchi.
Got it, lguchi?
What's all this, Otomo?
Don't ''Otomo'' me!
This is how we work to live.
Spoiled guy!
Bring money first.
That's what we want .
Sorry for a while ago.
Can we talk?
All right.
Go first.
l said, leave.
Stop it, Mr. lguchi!
You said you'd
call me lguchi.
Mr. lguchi.
lguchi, right?
Just lguchi.
Mr. lguchi.
Say, ''lguchi.''
''lguchi.''
Mr... lguchi...
No. ''lguchi.''
lguchi...
That's it, Mr. Muto.
What? l touched him!
How can you call it ''safe''?
Damn umpire! Ass!
Open your eyes!
He tagged the runner.
He tagged him here.
Like hell he did!
l saw it.
Know baseball?
He was safe. Safe! Got it?
ldiot umpire!
Never mind.
Quit! l'll make up for it.
That's why you never win!
Forget that ass. Let's start.
''That ass''? Damn you!
Hey, wait!
Go! Go!
About the dress
we saw the other day...
Lay off! l told you
l'm broke.
Want to swing
that bat forever?
l'll pinch-hit.
All you ever do
is strike out!
l'll get a hit.
Change! Reverse the score!
The last inning.
Get two points.
Get at least two.
Don't bat a foul.
Ass!
Get a man on base!
Watch out!
Sorry.
Pick a good ball!
Last inning, two out.
Take a chance!
Wait for a good ball!
Our chance!
lt's our chance.
Get at least one point.
Next batter...?
Kobayashi.
Him? What's he doing?
He's in the can.
The can? What a dunce!
Where's the next batter?
ln the can.
Get a pinch-hitter for him.
Pinch-hitter? Who?
l'll do it.
Yeah! You.
Swat the first ball.
Let ' em have it!
Swing, okay?
He did it!
Out? What for?
Because you passed him.
Why did you? We could've
reversed the score.
Game over.
lt could've been a homer.
You did a good job.
But you should
never pass a runner.
You were slow.
What? l ran fast.
Just run properly. Ass!
He passed me!
Have the mobsters come
again to your gas station?
They won't.
You're faster
than l thought.
You already laid her?
Aren't you marrying Miki?
What for?
l've got plenty of chicks.
What about you?
l'll marry her.
Nonsense!
Your woman came. She's at
the tennis court over there.
You're too fast!
You're too slow!
How silly!
Don't pass me!
Ass!
Dammit, who do you think
you called an ass?!
You dating?
Got laid already?
Where to?
An aquarium.
To see a panda? How nice!
But fishing is even nicer.
Come with me.
Sakaya.
Want to know my name?
lt's James.
No catch. Shall we
go to the aquarium?
How is it?
l did it at last!
lt's that pin.
The upper one?
lt's bent.
They pull tricks on you.
l see.
Can't make it.
What's the big idea? Stop!
l need balls.
No. l've lost
10,000 yen already.
You're lying. Ass!
Enough! Stop!
He's sly.
From any point of view,
he's richer.
Why take my balls?
Yes?
Balls don't come out.
l'll destroy this shop.
l'll burn it.
Cigarettes.
That'll be 75 balls.
Thank you.
And you?
Gum.
Don't have gum.
None?
Sorry.
Hi, players!
Thanks for your patronage.
l have news for you.
You can't win in this dump.
Let's go to another place.
lt's called ''New Prince,''
it's near here.
They're offering
a special discount today.
l repeat, you'll never win
staying in this dump.
Switch to another place.
Never come again!
Shut up!
l'll make you go bankrupt!
Go first.
Hey, lguchi,
come with us, okay?
Say something?
Come with us.
Before that.
lguchi.
Where's Otomo?
He'll come later.
Making me wait?
Shut up, damn you!
You're tough, huh?
Why not straighten out?
Quit acting like a gangster.
See a doc?
He doesn't want to.
He's going to Okinawa
to get a gun.
But he can't move.
He says so.
Stupid!
l'll go to Okinawa.
l'll buy a gun.
Anybody want to
come with me?
What's on your mind?
Going to Okinawa?
Keep away from gangsters.
Cancel it.
Here. Take it with you.
Got tissue? Tissue!
No.
Wonder how
lguchi's doing...
Shall we go to town
this evening?
How much have you embezzled?
A big amount, huh?
Bring the money and one of
your fingers by tomorrow.
Remember, we're taking
care of you.
Aren't you ashamed
of yourself?
Bastard!
What are you going to do
with that bottle?
Go ahead!
Stop!
Buddy!
l said to stop!
US Army surplus stuff?
No.
Secondhand?
l made it look old.
lt's good.
Come here often?
No. Rarely.
You shaved your legs?
Got a chick?
Laid her already?
You smell nice.
Want a drink? Want to play?
Call a hostess?
Don't waste your money here.
Why not go to work?
Damn you!
You all right?
You drank and sang too much.
Tamagi, cut off your finger.
Why me?
We're buddies.
So what?
Do as l say.
No.
Come on.
The boss told me
to cut off my finger.
Forget it.
Please help me.
l'm in a fix.
Why not drink?
What's the matter?
lt's Tamagi.
Knock it off and drink.
What?
Come on, drink.
lt's good. Guzzle it.
You're great, huh?
Why?
You ask why?
Damn you!
Ass!
Drink!
Tamagi, you got a chick?
No.
How do you do it, then?
l manage.
l'll get you Fumiyo.
Fumiyo, sleep with Tamagi.
No.
Don't bother.
Do it. l'm asking you.
l don't want to.
Stop it!
Do as l say!
Sleep with him! Ass!
Do it!
Let me do it.
Hey, buddy!
What's on your mind?
Lots of things.
Hey, that hurts!
Be quiet!
No! Stop!
Your finger.
Why must l cut it?
You laid my woman.
You told me to.
But you shouldn't have!
Cut it off!
All right!
What are you doing?
Shut up!
Ouch!
Hold him down!
That hurts!
Or l'll cut your fingers!
Anything to hit it?
Bring something to hit it.
Let me bat.
Here l go!
l'm tired of this.
Let me bat this time, too!
Pitch it right!
Come!
Why so mad?
You slept with Tamagi.
You told me to.
But you shouldn't have!
What are you saying?
Bitch!
Why cry?
Dive, okay?
Let's dive together.
Buddy, let's go.
Quit crying!
Why so many here?
You told us to get in.
Shut up!
lt's so hot!
How noisy!
Someone get out.
Ass!
Why force her?
Shut up!
He wants 3 million.
3 million?
3 million, huh?
Come down to 2.5.
Okay.
l'll ask my pal.
Give me a margin, huh?
Then 2.5 million.
Later.
Where's mine?
None for you.
Don't gripe.
Take the leftovers.
Go home tomorrow?
'Bye.
Finished?
Let's go.
Get out!
Take me to town.
Like hell!
Where's the money?
Think this is enough?
Whose finger is this?
That's why we call you scum.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Flight No. 66 for Tokyo
is now boarding.
Leaving?
From my buddy.
Sorry for everything.
Take care, huh?
See you again in Tokyo.
BUTTERFLY EGGS
Want some sweets? Have one.
Eat.
Good!
And this.
Butterfly eggs for you.
Open it.
Later.
Open it now.
Make it later.
Wait a minute.
ls this yours?
What's with you?
No, it's not mine.
Look at this.
lt's not mine!
Call the police!
Know what this means?
The gun.
You shoot.
For your uncle.
Sure?
Sure.
For Kobayashi.
Let's go.
OTOMO OFFlCE
Let go!
He's in his room.
He was badly beaten.
You fighting with mobsters?
Give me these.
Where have you been
all this time?
You know what you're doing?
Troublemaker!
What about lguchi?
We're short of hands.
Work again from tomorrow.
Or l can't do a thing!
Will you come again
from tomorrow? Please do.
Executive Producer: Kazuyoshi Okuyama
Producers: Hisao Nabeshima
Takio Yoshida
Masayuki Mori
Written by Takeshi Kitano
Photographed by
Katsumi Yanagishima
Lighting by Satoshi Takaya
Art Director: Osamu Sasaki
Recording by Senji Horiuchi
Edited by Toshio Taniguchi
The Players:
Masahiko Ono
Yuriko lshida
Takahito lguchi
Minoru lizuka
Hisashi lgawa
Bengal
Katsuo Tokashiki
Beat Takeshi
Directed by Takeshi Kitano