BABIES CRY
MATURE JENNY: Some Christmases
will always be more memorable
than others. More joyful, serene,
with blessings, with love.
"That," we will say,
"was the best Christmas ever."
BABY CRIES
We unbox our traditions,
year by year.
Each celebration must compete with
all of those that went before.
We set high standards...
Ho, ho, ho!
THEY LAUGH
..write long lists.
We cannot be ill,
we cannot afford to falter.
SHE SIGHS
Christmas becomes a challenge
we must rise to.
It is our duty to burnish it
and to make it shine.
We must do well.
We must BE well.
SHE COUGHS
We must do the best we can.
Urgh.
Father Christmas!Come on.
In we go.
CHILDREN LAUGH
Merry Christmas. Wave to Mummy.
HE LAUGHS
Here you go, Merry Christmas!
Come along, then, children.
Oh, hello, you!
HE CHUCKLES
Now, let me see
if I've got this right.
Er, you're Teddy,
you're May and you're Angela.
THEY GIGGLE
No.
Oh, silly Santa.
You're Angela and you're May.
THEY GIGGLE
And what do you want for Christmas?
Hmm?
SHE WHISPERS
You want Mummy and Daddy to get out
of bed and put some clothes on?
PHONE RINGS
Good afternoon. Dr Turner's surgery.
Miss Higgins.
I wondered how everything was.
I am only prepared
to say Dr Mukherjee
is proving...receptive to direction.
COUGHING IN BACKGROUND
Can I ask a favour?
Shelagh needs help
with some antlers.
Call me a stickler
for the Scriptures,
I don't recall any
reindeer in Bethlehem.
You can't be certain.
St Eustace himself
had a vision of Christ
between the antlers
of a stag, white as snow.
And there were mystics who believed
that our Lord himself
appeared to men in such a form.
Shake it all about for me,
there's a pet.
BELLS RING
Hello, love.I'm on my way
to give succour to invalids.
I require 3lb of oranges.
I imagine a modest discount
would be smiled upon
from the Celestial Realm.
SHE CHUCKLES
It's on me, love.
Oh.
Thank you.
This really is exceptionally
thoughtful of you, Mother Mildred.
I think this is the first thing
I've been able to smell
or taste for a week.
I did catch a whiff of Nurse Crane's
sugar and onion mixture.
I actually think I can smell it now.
Well, it's given my tubes
a good seeing-to.
And is probably why
I'm back in my slacks
and gearing up to
inspect my Rolodex!
So, Sister Hilda.
It appears that Nonnatus House
has been running on oiled wheels
during the recent crisis.
Reinforcements from
the Mother House
seemed to fill the
gaps quite nicely.
Once we showed them what to do
- and where everything was.
- Hmm.
It seems to me that with all
the posts so amply covered,
the best thing we can do
is to take almost all of
you away to convalesce.
You need a change of scene,
good food, sea air.
And I know precisely where
all three can be obtained.
I fear you evoke the
spectre of the Mother House.
Our esteemed Sister is incorrect.
I think that, on balance,
that I speak to
Sister Julienne alone.
We could go into my office.
I had just lit the paraffin stove
- so I could see to some paperwork.
- Sister.
It's best if we remain within
convenient distance
of the altar rail. By the time
I inform you of my plans,
we might both feel the need to pray.
I believe God is calling me
to open another branch house.
- Where?
- As ever, where good nursing
and skilled midwives
are desperately needed.
Where there is often no
doctor for many miles,
where the climate is our enemy
and water and electricity
both fickle friends at best.
Are you thinking of expanding
our operations in Africa?
No.
We're going to the Outer Hebrides.
The Outer Hebrides?!
I thought you'd approve,
being Scottish.
I'm not that sort of Scottish!
I grew up in a busy market town.
- The Hebrides are very remote.
- Precisely.
Some of the islands have
no access to a doctor,
and hospital help can be
two hours' drive away,
or travel by boat is required.
And you think the Order can help?
I'm convinced we can ALL help.
In the area in question,
the district nurse,
who is also the midwife,
has not only married,
but married the doctor,
and they've both
retreated to the mainland.
Support is required,
in the short term at least.
Ten days should suffice.
CHILDREN PLAY IN BACKGROUND
Far too often, the islands lose their
nurses because the ladies marry.
Religious sisters never let
their patients down in that regard.
For now, I merely propose
an advance excursion.
A fact-finding mission.
Call it what you will.
You and your good wife can
convalesce in the fresh air,
whilst helping the Order
to explore a call from God.
But we can't leave the children.
Nanny can't be here all the time.
A remonstrance I foresaw -
and can surmount.
Why have I got to mind
the Turner children?
I'd be much more use
in the Outer Hebrides.
I used to be a Queen's Guide.
You must not question
Mother Mildred's decision, Sister,
any more than I.
When we are called, we must listen.
Where we are called, we must go.
Unless we are called to go
somewhere and our Superior objects.
You really wanted to go, didn't you,
Sister Monica Joan?
At prayer, I received
a vision of our Lord himself
in altered form.
Do you mean a stag?
Like the legend of St Eustace?
Please do not use the term "legend".
It evokes a fantasy, a tale,
a fable conjured out of air.
When I speak of a vision,
I speak of something real.
A truth as tangible as...as flesh.
This is a lot of
trouble for ten days.
Argh, this isn't going to work.
I've got room for my rollers
or my lacquer, but not both.
You can't go without any lacquer.
You'll have to take
something else out.
I've already jettisoned three pairs
of shoes and my Lurex two-piece.
I'm limiting myself to one
all-purpose cocktail frock,
in case of emergencies.
The things we do to promote
the health of the deserving.
Behold. Beige or navy?
I rooted out some
convent-issue thermals,
left over from the Big Freeze.
I refer you to my
earlier remark.
SHE CHUCKLES
I'll have the beige
please, Phyllis.
It'll match my new vests.
Everything I ever
heard about Scotland
tells me they're
going to be essential.
GROANS
Vi, I think I melted the
collar on this shirt.
Well, that would be
because it's nylon.
And I'm not lifting a finger
to help you, so don't ask.
It's just a week, Vi.
The only building they might
be able to have as a convent
is some sort of abandoned church
they're now using as a youth hostel.
Mother Mildred just wants
to make sure it's viable.
I'll tell you what's not viable.
You just waltzing off
to the back of beyond,
just as Reggie comes
home for Christmas.
Well, I'll be back before Christmas.
It's three weeks away.
Violet.
What are you doing?!
I'm hiding Reggie's
Christmas presents
because I haven't got time
to wrap them!
And did you get him the sticky
strips to make the paper chains?
Because he looks forward to
doing that every Christmas.
I bought them down Chrisp Street,
they're in my coat pocket.
I promise you, Vi,
Mother Mildred said...
I do not wish to hear
that woman's name again!
MUSIC: JINGLE BELLS INTRO
♪ Just hear those
sleigh bells jingling
♪ Ring-ting tingle-ing too
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather for a
sleigh ride together with you... ♪
THEY SNIGGER
♪ Outside the snow is falling
and friends are calling yoo-hoo
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather for a
sleigh ride together with you... ♪
TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Our cheeks are nice and rosy
And comfy and cosy are we
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ We're snuggled up together like
two birds of a feather would be
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Let's take that road before us
And sing a chorus or two
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Come on, it's lovely weather for
a sleigh ride together with you
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding
♪ Ring-a-ling-a ding-dong-ding! ♪
Chips are lovely and hot!
If we're half a mile
past that phone box,
we must've come to
our left turn by now.
Have we missed the turning, perhaps?
I always read my maps upside down.
It's an absolutely infallible way
of working out left and right.
THUMP Oh!
If you're going to
slow to a dead stop
every time a specimen of the
local wildlife hoves into view,
we won't attain our objective
this side of Christmas.
I've got three packets of
Gypsy Creams in my holdall.
Do you think it's time
to break them open?
Oh, I hate cattle. Oooh.
- That's it. Hand this vehicle over.
- What?
I have additional keys and
I am prepared to use them.
VAN DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS
SHEEP BAA
So this is home
for the next ten days.
Come, Sister Julienne.
Let us approach on foot,
as pilgrims.
We have obtained our objective.
May the Lord guard
our comings and our goings,
and may he help us do the
jobs we do so well at home.
I detect an animal odour underfoot.
We would be wise to wipe our shoes.
Come and get your trees!
Right. Cup of tea and
a gingerbread Santa,
because I know you've never
been one for a mince pie.
So it's true, then?
What's true?
Fred's not here.
Oh, I wouldn't lie to you, Reggie.
And no, he's not here.
He's where he almost always is -
helping other people.
Except this time he's in Scotland,
which is why I need you
to be the man of the house
'til he gets back.
Can I sit in his chair?
Course you can.
Ahh...
Can I have some of his beer?
THEY LAUGH
You can have a shandy on Christmas
Day when Fred's back home.
Coats on the beds.
I haven't slept under
coats since I was a kid.
I wish I'd thought of that
when I first came to England.
I just used to lie in the
nurse's home and shiver.
Aww!
There must be 700 years
of mist, damp and misery
seeping out of these walls.
I persuaded Phyllis to
lend me her Fiery Jack.
Have you got lumbago?
No, I thought if we rubbed some
on ourselves, it might warm us up.
We'd need a gallon of it,
not a titchy little tin.
I'm dabbing it on my pulse points.
Or, as Madame Coco once
said of Chanel Number 5,
"It should be applied everywhere
a woman expects to be kissed."
Ah! Well, I won't bother, then.
CONGREGATION SINGING
MINA: Effie, will you
come back here?!
SHEEP BAA
Greetings, good sir.
We seek to make the acquaintance
of a Mrs...
Morag Norrie.
Third door on the right.
We don't generally labour
on the Lord's Day here.
We observe the Sabbath
according to the commandments.
Now...
..the cleanliness of
this hall falls to me.
So I hope there'll be
no additional dirt.
The only time the last nurse used
this hall was for her wedding.
Four weeks later,
I'm still sweeping up confetti.
Horseshoe.
Well, that might bring us some luck.
- You're Scots?
- Yes, I am.
A bheil Gaidhlig agad?
I asked if you spoke Gaelic.
There's no need to answer.
The nurse that just left,
she didn't speak it either.
There's some here that speak
nothing else on the island,
but we manage.
Are these your practice records?
As you requested.
Anything else you want from
the old surgery is in the store
and will have to be fetched.
These are on their way to Stornoway.
That's where the
nearest doctor is now.
But it took us two hours
to get here from Stornoway.
FLICKS SWITCH
The electric seems to
be playing the game.
If it goes off,
there's oil lamps in the store.
Hmm.
BELL RINGS
Hello, ladies.
I'm a midwife and a nurse,
and we are running a
clinic at the village hall.
That is the second time you've walked
out of singing practice in three weeks.
We're going to have the
minister round here again.
What do we say to him this time?
The psalms make my head ache.
- You're supposed to be uplifted by them.
- And improved?
You don't need to be improved,
Effie,
you just need to be kept steady.
We all do.
We've a new baby
coming in the spring.
I know you do.
COW MOOS
Hurry up. Your wee calf
needs his bed making.
Tell him to be patient.
I want Effie to see him.
KNOCK ON DOOR
Enter.
Ah, just the person.
You can help me sign
the Christmas cards.
I promised Sister Julienne
I'd do them while everyone was away.
We must submit to the
labours assigned us.
Yes, we must.
I even submitted to
Sister Julienne's request
for frugality and
bought a bargain box
of 50 on Chrisp Street market.
I'm afraid one or two of
them are on the saucy side.
- Sister Hilda.
- Mm?
Do you consider my mental
faculties to be diminished?
No, no, that wasn't why
I didn't show you the card.
You can see it if you like.
Oh, I...
I would not be able to deduce why
something is vulgar, or amusing.
My faculties always failed
me in that department.
Now others think my faculties
are mislaid altogether.
Oh, Sister, what can I tell you,
other than to say that
that is not so?
That we cherish you.
And if age has...
..cost you things,
it has replaced them
with gifts to us all.
It is not a gift to me
to be deemed too frail to journey
to a place where we are needed.
It is not a gift to me to,
to be fettered by an
ever-diminishing roster
of trivial tasks.
I... I'm sure you're more
than capable of extending
your daily routine,
if you feel up to it.
What if expenditure is required?
Senior sisters are licensed to
draw down from the petty cash,
but
I have not been allowed
to do so for some time.
I am overturning that.
Now.
Do you hear me?
Sister...
..do you consider me
to be of sound mind?
Yes.
I feel that the sacrifice
of the Gypsy Creams
was warranted.
It's a very hospitable
gesture, certainly.
But I'm afraid there are going
to be more midwives and nurses
on the welcoming committee,
than we will have people to welcome.
If I have heard the Almighty aright,
and he intends that we
establish a branch house here,
then the sisters in
residence will be few,
and their challenges immense.
There is no disgrace in savouring
our numbers whilst we may.
MAN:I told you,
it's the right place.
Do come in out of the cold.
Good morning.
Tea for the gentleman
and the lady, Nurse Dyer.
We have some rather
appealing biscuits
to accompany your beverage.
Mrs Turner will
take your details.
We wouldn't say no
to a cup of anything hot.
We've just rowed across
from the lighthouse.
Sister Julienne,
can you examine this lady
as soon as I've taken her details?
- Hello there.
- Thank you.
Right this way.
- Are we too late?
- The bus always goes the long way round.
I think you'll find you're
absolutely punctual.
Please take a seat.
The word was you were from London.
We're all from London...
..including me.
Do come through.
I think perhaps just one
Gypsy Cream apiece, Nurse Dyer.
Who can foretell the
hordes that may be upon us?
Is everything as it should be?
Everything is exactly as I like
to see it in a lady of eight months.
I keep thinking
something will go wrong.
Why should you think that?
I don't know.
I left the island for three years.
I went to Inverness
to work in a pharmacy.
My granny said it made me morbid.
- Your granny didn't approve of that?
- No!
She doesn't approve of much.
Her name is Mrs Norrie -
have you met her yet?
- Yes. We are acquainted.
- Ah.
Inverness is a very different
environment to this.
That's why I liked it...
..until I came home one
summer for a holiday
and met my Angus.
He came to work at the
lighthouse from the city
as a complete stranger.
When I saw my home
through his eyes, that's
when I realised I loved
it more than I ever had.
It's a very great gift in life,
to know where you belong.
Many spend a lifetime
hoping to find out.
SHE WINCES
Is that tender?
Mm.
It's just the wee one
kicking my bladder.
VEHICLE APPROACHES/HORN SOUNDS
HORN SOUNDS
I'll get them, OK? I'll get them.
Help! We need help! Help!
It's all right! It's all right!
It's my wife.
I'll fetch my bag.
Where was Baby born?
Here, in the truck.
I pulled over by the roadside
about half an hour ago.
Go into the hall while
we put things to rights.
Baby's still attached
to Mother by the cord.
We have brisk blood loss.
Have you felt any pain
since the baby arrived?
Anything to suggest that the
afterbirth is on its way?
No.
We need to get her inside
and give her Syntometrine.
BABY GRIZZLES
BABY CRIES
Is it... Is it coming yet? Is it?
Yes, Maggie, it is.
Placenta on its way.
Here it comes.
SHE GROANS
Thank you.
Thank you. SHE CRIES
My dear, every fragment
of endeavour has been yours.
We all commend you
for your fortitude.
Mother Mildred, could you
fetch Doctor, please?
There's a problem with the placenta.
We have a placenta,
but it's incomplete.
Mother needs an ambulance and
a blood transfusion, in that order.
You need to ring the
hospital in Stornoway.
I was going to order
some polio vaccine.
There's a round
of immunisations due.
We're also deficient in
analgesia for childbirth.
I shall ask for Trilene,
if we can't get gas and air.
If I stop massaging the
uterus, it relaxes.
We have to stabilise her now.
The ambulance is going to
take too long to get here.
It is nevertheless
already on its way.
Mother will be transfused as soon
as she's delivered to the hospital.
In about four hours' time.
I think it's been expelled.
Her uterus is contracting.
Placenta complete.
BABY CRIES
And a strong and healthy baby.
I'm sorry, but this is a completely
dreadful way to convalesce.
We're all dressed up as if
we've burgled a jumble sale...
THEY LAUGH
..and now we're peeling
our own potatoes. Ugh.
With absolutely no way
of turning them into chips.
May the Lord forgive
me, but right now
I'd kill for threepenny
worth of chips and a saveloy.
Hey, have we turned you
into a Cockney on the quiet?
I like to think so.
THEY LAUGH
Lucille, I heard what that woman
said to you in the clinic today.
Happens all the time at home.
I'm almost used to it.
But people like them
aren't used to people like me.
And I can't hate them for it,
because I come from an island too.
Not an island like this, though.
All islands are like this.
All islands have a boundary,
and you live your life within it,
and you love it, or you break out,
and make a life elsewhere.
And on every island in the world,
no matter how magnificent,
there are those who cannot leave,
and those who cannot stay.
And I was one of those
who could not stay.
PHONE RINGS
Good evening. Mrs Buckle's shop.
This is Reginald speaking.
Reggie? Is that you?
Violet's out.
Council meeting.
Oh. Oh, hang on. PIPS SOUND
Hang on. There you go.
COINS DROP INTO SLOT
- Did you get the tree up?
- Yep.
What is it? A spruce or a Nordmann?
- It's green.
- Oh!
We need to make the paper
chain, Fred.
Yeah. PIPS SOUND
Ugh. Wait, wait, wait...
Oh, I've run out of money!
Tell Violet I called.
DIAL TONE SOUNDS
HE SIGHS
♪ The Earth is the Lord's
♪ And all that therein is
♪ The compass of the world
And they that dwell therein
♪ For he hath founded it
upon the seas
♪ And prepared it
upon the floods... ♪
COW MOOS
The calf was on my lap,
and then it did its muck all over me.
Isla! You'll have to get changed
straight into your nightdress.
I've no other
clothes dry for you,
unless there's been some sort
of miracle out on the line.
Can I go back to the calf?
No! you stay in here now.
You smell high enough already, Isla.
Effie, can you get some more water?
We'll have to soak her
things in a bucket.
I'll soak you in a bucket.
Ugh. EFFIE LAUGHS
ON RADIO: Stormy conditions
in the Western Isles,
with heavy gales and rainfall.
STATION CHANGES
ON RADIO:
♪ With the hippy hippy shakes
♪ Yeah, it's in the bag
♪ Ooh! The hippy hippy shakes... ♪
ISLA LAUGHS
♪ Well now, you shake it to the left
You shake it to the right
♪ You do the hippy shake shake
With all your might
♪ Oh, baby
Yeah, come on and shake
♪ Oh, it's in the bag
♪ The hippy hippy shake
♪ Ohh... ♪
DISTANT SCREAM
SHE GASPS/SCREAMING CONTINUES
Isla!
MUSIC CONTINUES/SHE SCREAMS
ISLA CRIES
BICYCLE BELL RINGS
Angela, May,
watch out for Teddy on those steps.
Sister Frances,
might I have a word?
We've just come to
bathe Baby Jesus
and glue his arm back on so he's
ready for the crib at Christmas.
I have been following the
offices with my breviary.
It's not the following of
offices that concerns me.
ANGELA: Teddy,
you're not allowed in there.
"Since, according to
your own admission,
"I am deemed to be of sound mind..."
When did you say you thought
she was of sound mind?
When she implored me to!
I replied in the affirmative
because it seemed the kindest thing.
"..I have made the decision
"to travel to the Hebrides
independently."
Independently's underlined.
I know it's underlined!
"Please do not trouble
your conscience,
"or the constabulary."
I will trouble the constabulary,
I'm going to give
them this as evidence.
She won't get very far
without any money.
She's taken a pound note
and some loose change
out of the petty cash...
..with my permission.
Oh, you must feel terrible.
I wanted her to
have some dignity.
She's always got dignity. What she
really wanted was to see a stag.
But why would she go to
the Hebrides?
There are stags in Richmond Park.
She wanted to see a white one.
She believes she might
encounter Jesus Christ that way.
Oh!
Oh, don't tell the police that.
They'll think she's going mad.
Or that you are.
I don't care.
I'm calling them now,
and insisting that they alert
their counterparts in Scotland.
TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS
Ticket, please.
Tickets, please.
It is you and your colleagues who
deserve to be subject to scrutiny.
It is some considerable time
since any one of you has asked to
view my travel documents.
Tickets.
Please.
This ran out in Preston.
Only if you consider travel from
a strictly temporal perspective.
Mine is not merely a
terrestrial journey,
it is a spiritual quest...
..and God himself propels
this chariot of fire.
HE SIGHS
ISLA CRIES
Please, she's in here!
We can't stop her crying!
SHE WAILS
Have you put anything
on these yourself?
Only butter.
It's what you do - butter for burns.
It's flannelette, Nurse Crane.
One spark from the fire and it
would have gone up like a torch.
It's a peat fire.
Peat doesn't spark.
We'll need to check for
fragments of charred fabric
clinging to the skin. I can see
one or two pieces from here.
CRYING CONTINUES
Listen, Isla.
Isla.
Come on.
I need you to be a brave
little lass for me.
CRYING INTENSIFIES
We're going to wash your
poor legs with soapy water
to get the butter off,
and then bathe them
with lovely fresh antiseptic.
SHE WAILS
We'll need to calm her down.
Why didn't you put your wellies on?
Because we are heading
to town to collect
a significant quantity of drugs,
vaccines and other medical supplies,
and I'm of the view that office
wear is more appropriate.
This is like nowhere else
I've ever been on Earth.
Do you wish the
children could see it?
I wish the children could live it.
What?
You mean move here?
The island needs a doctor.
Permanently.
The vacancy is
already advertised,
and Mother Mildred says...
I don't want to know
what Mother Mildred says.
What I do want to know is
how she manages to wrap
half the men in Poplar
round her little finger.
It isn't just the men!
Mother Mildred wrapped YOU
round her little finger,
and we ended up with
our fourth child.
May changed our
lives for the better.
CHANGE changes our lives
for the better.
We're a family that thrives on it.
We don't stay still, Shelagh.
No, we don't.
And that's why
we're needed in Poplar.
With every year that passes,
we're faced with some new crisis
and some new way of
putting things to rights.
The system is improving
all the time.
There's a good system here.
They just don't have anyone
to run it for them.
I'm not even going to
discuss it with you.
HE SIGHS
SHE WINCES
I'll check your blood pressure
and urine when I'm done.
That'll save you
coming into the clinic
while you've Isla to take care of.
It's my fault that she's burned.
I shouldn't have turned my back.
Does she need to go to hospital?
With daily dressing changes,
she's better off at home with
her parents and her big sister.
Effie's her cousin.
My sister died.
I'm sorry.
My condolences.
She went to work as a chambermaid
in a hotel in Stornoway.
When she came back
with Effie in her arms,
the story was that
she had been widowed.
I take it this was
soon after the war?
1948.
The father was a submariner from
Norway, just passing through.
Long enough to leave
her with a child,
not long enough to leave
her with a wedding ring.
There were a lot of widows
of that type in those days.
Not here.
My sister died of TB.
I said I'd take Effie.
She was 12 when she came to me.
I already had Isla under my feet,
I thought it would be easy.
But she was a child then,
and now she's a woman,
and I cannot keep her reined.
Reined?
As in reined in?
Effie is the same as my sister.
She couldn't be
penned,
she couldn't be pinned down.
Young people always chafe,
Mrs MacLeod.
They chafe more now the
world's spinning faster.
I want what's best for my niece,
and that means that
she cannot go running free.
♪ Gathering winter fu-u-El. ♪
Fred, are you sure you can chop
a tree down just like that?
No-one ever stopped
me in Epping Forest.
Anyway,
it's to cheer the kiddies up,
and to take the edge
off their nerves
when they come for
their vaccinations.
They don't seem to really go to town
with their decorations round here.
Maybe they leave it
all to the last minute.
Have we got anything to put on it?
Don't worry,
it's all in hand.
I've got an idea...
..about some paper chains.
DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
Oh, Reggie!
That was supposed to be
a surprise for Christmas.
Fred was looking forward to
reading bits out loud with you.
Sorry.
But Fred isn't here, is he?
INDISTINCT CHATTER/BABIES CRY
And what is that pagan
monstrosity doing in this hall?!
I'm sure there was no intention
whatever of causing offence.
I have heard tell of such things
on the mainland,
and from my nephews in America,
but it is not the
custom in these islands!
It never was,
and it never shall be!
Mr Buckle wanted to do
something for the children.
And did the children ask for it?
Have the children here
ever needed such a thing?
It is to be removed
and disposed of
before any more harm is done!
THEY SIGH
- Take care now, sister.
- Bye!
- Thanks, Jim.
- I was headed down that road anyway.
Oh...
Oh!
It appears I am to travel
with precious cargo.
Yes. We've a great deal to
thank your colleagues for.
Would you oblige me by moving along?
I require an unimpeded view.
Angus!
SHE MOANS
I think it's started.
Come on.
I'm going to get you in the boat.
Mm-Mnn.
You can't leave the lighthouse
empty. You'll be dismissed.
I don't care.
Please, please,
let me get you in the boat.
I can't! It's...
Oh, it's coming too fast!
SHE GROANS
This is Fuar Glas Lighthouse,
Fuar Glas Lighthouse,
calling the coastguard, over.
OVER RADIO: This is
the coastguard, over.
I need medical
assistance for my wife.
It looks as if the
baby's on the way. Over.
THEY CHEER
Oh, she's here!
You may note that I have refrained
from contributing to this ovation.
Because I have broken
the Rule of Obedience.
No. Because you have caused
alarm to your sisters,
purloined convent funds
from the petty cash,
defrauded British Railways,
and been thrown upon
the mercy of the police.
I'm sure no further
discussion, or chastisement,
will take place before you have
recovered from your journey.
I will decide what
measures are required.
First, I must be
fortified with scones.
PHONE RINGS
Sit down.
Somebody else can answer that.
I've no desire for any further
contact with the authorities.
St Faelan's House.
How may I assist you?
It's the coastguard.
"Bobby Bushtail was a squirrel,
"and a naughty rascal too.
"Sometimes he was so..."
When the nurses arrive,
you make them a cup of tea
and tell them
I've had to go to work.
And for pity's sake, you put those
magazines away, they're months old.
If your uncle wasn't away thatching,
I'd leave him with Isla
and take you to waulk
the tweed with me.
It's time you learned how.
It's what old women do.
Not old, Effie.
Just women.
DOOR CLOSES
All I ask is that you row
the midwives and myself
across to the lighthouse.
It is the Lord's day.
I cannot undertake labour.
There's a lady on that
island with no choice
as to whether she undertakes labour.
She's having a baby.
She can't get over here,
so we have to get to her.
Would it make it better
if we paid you double?
It would make it worse!
What if we paid you nothing
and you did it just to oblige?
I obey the rules
that oblige the Lord,
and no other.
I imagine we both have equal
respect for the Almighty, sir.
Just lend us the boat.
Lend it to us,
and we'll row ourselves.
Or just turn your back
and let us steal it.
Just don't report us to the police
till we're halfway there.
I feel like one of us
should have a megaphone
to keep you both in time.
THEY LAUGH
Well, it's no worse than going round
Vicky Park boating lake
a couple of times, is it, Doc?
It's a shame we couldn't
have hired a pedalo
and got us all an ice cream.
THEY LAUGH
The lease of this building is not
going to be made available to us.
The local council would prefer it to
be used for secular purposes,
or not at all.
There will also be problems
with the village hall, apparently.
Is this because of Fred
and his Christmas tree?
The council take the view
that the denominational divide
between ourselves and the
Presbyterians is too great.
Sister, in Poplar we serve
Catholics, Methodists,
Jews and Muslims.
We serve atheists and Buddhists,
Sikhs and Hindus.
It does not matter who
or how they worship.
We treat them all alike,
and our faith is our own affair.
But there,
strangers come into OUR world,
and here,
we have come into theirs.
I fear I have not
heard the Lord aright.
I fear I acted in haste
and failed in humility
by presuming all the power
to give and to change
and to illuminate was ours...
..or mine.
What if you had failed in faith?
Sister...
Permit her to continue.
She's going to anyway.
I say only this -
what if He has not yet shown you
all that He intends?
Almost there.
Hurry!
- Thank you.
- She's getting worse.
Don't you worry, sir,
we'll be by your wife's side
before you know it.
This way. Quick.
MOANING
How often have the pains
been coming?
Mm,
on and off for a
couple of days now.
A couple of days?
Mm-hmm. Kept thinking
it was all getting going,
then it would just fade.
But once this started, this morning,
I knew there was no going back.
And it's more across my stomach,
as opposed to up to one side.
How do you mean, to one side?
Almost up by my ribs.
SHE CALLS OUT IN PAIN
There?
The mother's definitely pyrexic.
Her pulse is also very rapid.
How's her blood pressure?
That seems normal.
A routine urine test at the clinic
showed no sign of infection,
but Valerie's going to get a
sample, so we can check again.
WOMEN SING IN GAELIC
ISLA:"..when she tried
to brush his tail.
"And if she combed a little..."
I'm going to Cousin Lorna's.
She's got new magazines
come in the post.
Tell your mam I might stay the
night if the storm gets worse.
You're not meant to
leave me on my own!
The nurses will be here in a minute.
Mam'll be vexed with you.
She's always vexed with me.
What if the calf gets
scared in the storm?
The calf is perfectly happy.
SHE MOANS
Are you feeling you want to
push, chick?
I don't know.
I've never had a baby before.
I don't know what
pushing feels like.
I don't know how to do it.
I don't...
I don't know anything.
We do, Janet.
And we're here to help.
This is YOUR first baby,
but we do this all the time.
- THEY LAUGH
- Promise me.
JANET MOANS IN PAIN
You can come right in.
The height won't bite you.
It's not the height that bothers me.
It's the distance.
I'm not used to seeing
such a long way ahead.
You're a city dweller, then?
London.
I'm from Motherwell.
I never knew what distance
was, what space was.
Space like there
was room around you
where you could stretch
out and breathe.
There was nine of us
living in two rooms.
That sounds familiar.
Then I took to looking at the sky.
I saw something that had no limits,
but did not change.
And I wanted it.
The heavens belong to no
man, but this is mine.
This is my star.
But it would all mean
nothing without my Janet.
SHE MOANS
Good girl.
You tell me if you want
some Trilene for the pain.
No, the pain's all gone now.
It's more like power.
Like a force.
- SHE MOANS
- Here it comes.
Little pushes.
That's it.
There we go.
The head's out?
Give me your hand.
You feel that?
That's what that power
you spoke about can do.
Baby's turning.
SHE LAUGHS/BABY CRIES
You have a son, Janet.
He's the most beautiful
little boy you ever did see.
I wouldn't care if he wasn't.
He's ours.
And he belongs where he was born.
SCISSORS SNIP
CRYING CONTINUES
BABY SETTLES
Shh...
Can we open a window?
So he can hear the sea?
It's blowing a force
ten gale out there.
Do you want him to get sucked
right out into the storm?
How about we all just listen?
HEAVY WINDS BLOW
Do you hear that? Do you?
This is your home.
DOOR OPENS
Nurses!
Hello, Isla.
I don't want you!
Are you all on your own?
SHE CRIES
Isla, the more you fuss,
the longer this will take.
And I don't like to say this,
sweetheart,
but the more it will hurt.
It hurts anyway!
CRYING CONTINUES
We can't sedate her again.
It's not warranted.
When will he start smiling?
Bless you, Mr MacAskill.
You'll have to wait a
few more weeks for that.
Can I take him up
and show him the light?
We need to get him bathed,
properly dressed,
and try putting him to the breast.
After that, we might discuss it.
Afterbirth's all
present and correct.
Are you happy for me
to burn it in the stove?
Janet, precious.
Are you feeling unwell?
I think I'm going to be sick.
Would you go and ask Doctor
to step this way, please?
JANET VOMITS
All right.
ISLA CRIES
Do you know, Isla,
I've often had to put up with
some absolutely horrid things.
I've sometimes tried to
wish them away,
and sometimes
I've actually fought them,
but every single time,
the thing that's got me through
is the promise of a treat,
or a reward, after the pain is done.
The idea that there are better
things to come, if I'm brave enough.
What sort of better things?
Well, it might be something
like a special cake
or a new nail varnish.
Manicures are almost
my favourite thing.
My favourite thing's the calf.
No, please, no!
I'm sorry, Janet.
Am I going to have another baby?
No, you aren't.
You've got acute appendicitis.
DOOR OPENS
CALF MOOS
I'm sorry, but I have no choice
but to dislodge you
from your cosy little bed.
I will bring you back when
our mission is accomplished.
Oh!
You and I, young man,
are perilously close to falling out.
Coastguard,
can you arrange for
a medical evacuation? Over.
Advice - to remain in situ
until storm abates. Over.
This is the GP who
diagnosed the patient.
Her labour masked the symptoms,
and there is a risk
that the appendix
may now be at the point
of bursting. Over.
Coastguard. Are you able to remain
with the patient? Over.
I can't leave her,
but she needs urgent surgery.
Over.
Remain in situ.
Repeat - remain in situ
until the storm abates.
Over and out.
There, there. CLICKS TONGUE
There, there. There, there.
SHE GROANS
The pain stopped hurting
whilst I was having him.
Precious, that's because the act
of giving birth eclipses everything.
Hormones flood through the body,
sweeping everything else away.
Why can't they sweep this away?
Because you're not
having a baby now.
You're sick,
and we'll take care of you.
Dr Turner's going to
anaesthetise her with Trilene.
We have suture thread and needles,
but the clamps and the scalpel will
have to be sterilised by boiling.
Oh, the pan's coming up to simmer.
I've brought the gloves
we used in the delivery.
We need to boil them, too.
Then we want a pair of clean sheets,
to cover the table and the patient.
We'll hot iron them if there's time.
CRY OF PAIN
I'm coming right back.
Oh, that bulb's
playing silly beggars.
That's all we need.
Dr Turner's gown's on the back of
the chair. Scrub your hands,
rinse them off with the Dettol,
and then take it to him.
Sergeant Dyer's
got it all organised.
She's a right tartar
when she wants to be -
you can't half tell
she's been in the Army.
I was in the Army.
The last time I took an appendix
out was in Italy in 1944.
Something to do
with Monte Cassino?
He was a young artillery
gunner from Scunthorpe.
I had to fit him in
between two amputations,
with the sound of
gunfire in the distance
and hail on the roof
of the hospital tent.
Every single day, the thing
that scared me the most
was that my hands
would get too cold...
..that they'd freeze up.
Well, you don't want that when
you're working with precision tools.
It feels like old times.
My hands aren't warm.
I'm having to improvise.
And if I get it wrong,
a life gets cut short.
Come on.
You don't want to get on the
wrong side of Sergeant Dyer.
Shoulders back.
SHE GROANS
He knows I'm hurt!
I can see it in his eyes.
That's all we can hope
for, really, isn't it?
Someone who knows
when we're in pain.
THUNDER CRASHES
Your Mammy's got work to do.
Everybody's busy,
So you can help me do my job, eh?
DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
Are you not helping
with the operation?
Not really a spectator sport.
Scalpel.
Now, while the baby was in utero,
the appendix would have
been pushed upwards,
which is why the pain was
atypically high in the abdomen.
It should now have returned
to its usual position...
..so
I will make the
classic incision,
over McBurney's point.
Like...
so.
The electricity's gone off.
Clamp. Just find the clamp.
BABY CRIES
DOOR OPENS
The storm's blown the power out -
the keeper's gone up the tower.
We've got one oil lamp,
and one torch, and that's it.
It'll have to do.
And you'll have to hold them.
Tell me where to stand.
I shall be treating us both to
a pre-emptive dose of linctus
when we get back indoors.
We've not long seen off the flu, and
you're minus one of your stockings.
Are you sure you don't want to
cycle back and fetch it?
Oh, I'm never crossing
the threshold in that barn again.
I don't care if I have to paint my
other leg with dark gravy browning.
Oh, good God.
It's Effie!
I thought it was an animal.
Whatever's happened to the lass?
Gently does it.
Good grief.
- Was that normal?
- No.
It's about three
times the usual size,
it's full of pus,
and it would have burst by morning.
Swab.
I telephoned the Post Office,
and they're taking a
message to Effie's auntie.
I was suitably parsimonious
with the details.
We don't really have
any details ourselves,
except that it's whisky.
I can smell it seeping
through her skin.
Well, we'll leave her on her side.
I dare say we'll be deploying
the bucket again at some point.
Oh, lass.
Do you want to stand down?
Doesn't actually help that
she's wearing my pyjamas.
No. I don't suppose it does.
I've never quite got used to it,
as a nurse...
..the way you can suddenly see
yourself reflected back at you,
in a place, or a face,
where you least expect it.
If we allow ourselves
to think like that,
we'd be seeing ourselves
round every corner,
and not paying due
attention to our patients.
Go on.
You avail yourself of my bed...
..and I'll dance attendance
on our young delinquent.
Phyllis...
Effie didn't do this
because she's bad -
she did it because she's unhappy.
EFFIE WHIMPERS
Mum!
It's all right, lass.
You're looked after.
Oh!
I've come to see my granddaughter.
Donald the Ferry
wants his boat back,
at your convenience.
The word is you all had
quite the night of it.
It would appear
you've all been very resourceful.
We had no choice.
Other than to choose to do our best,
or panic and do nothing.
Ooh, panickers never
last long in these parts.
Neither do people with romantic
notions in their minds.
Pound to a penny, if they come here
and fall in love with the islands,
next thing they fall
in love with a man,
and run away.
We're not running away, Mrs Norrie.
- We're just going home to London.
- When?
At the end of the week,
but Nurse Dyer and I won't
leave you for a day or two.
I would've died without them.
I know you would.
You must all have been
missing your families,
with Christmas coming, and it
being so important where you live.
Nothing is more important than this,
Mrs Norrie.
Kippers?
I think they'll upset me.
Not as much as Nurse Franklin's
going to upset your auntie
when she fills her in on
last night's antics.
Aunt Mina doesn't need to know.
Yes, she does.
Because she needs to know you.
Oh, Reggie!
Oh, you do look smart,
but I don't think you
need to wear a tie.
You've got a hat on.
Yes, but I'm not going to
be packing Christmas parcels
with the youth club.
You're going to be one of them
this afternoon.
I'd rather do paper chains.
They'll still be here
when you get back.
Go and take the tie off,
and make yourself look "groovy".
The only way I'll make Aunt
Mina happy is if I stay here.
Live on a croft,
sing psalms every Sunday,
wearing Wellingtons.
I've no quarrel with
a good stout gumboot,
not in these climes.
I shall deposit this
in an appropriate dustbin.
I don't believe you
ever really wanted it.
My father worked on a submarine.
I never saw him, but...
..I imagine him sometimes,
under the water,
in the dark, with everything
locked tight shut above his head.
He can't get out...
..and neither can I.
Did you know...I was a bastard?
I know your mother wasn't married.
My mother wasn't married.
You say it as if you're not ashamed.
I was - so ashamed,
once upon a time.
I could smell it on my skin.
Not because I was dirty...
..but because we could only
afford the cheapest soap.
Mother and I were as clean
as we could make ourselves.
Oh, but we were lonely.
I never realised my
mother and I were lonely.
She always used to say,
"It's more fun, just us."
We used to take the
bus to a gospel hall
in another part of town.
My mother was the only fallen
woman in the congregation.
I think they quite liked
having her...
..so they could forgive...
..because one day
I suddenly realised
how proud I was of my mother.
Keeping me took courage...
..and I decided I'd
make her proud of me.
I've missed my chance there.
Being proud of yourself
would be a start.
Now, remember, ladies and gentlemen,
if the box you are filling
has scarlet tinsel on it,
it will be donated to
an elderly lady,
and we require the inclusion of
bath cubes and a miniature liqueur.
If it has gold tinsel embellishment,
it is destined for a gentleman,
so kindly incorporate a bottle of
pale ale and a chocolate tool set.
Well, I shall now hand
over to Councillor Buckle.
On your marks,
get set,
go!
MUSIC: Jingle Bell Rock
JINGLE BELL ROCK FADES
I can still smell
the drink on you.
From here.
It will pass.
And if she'd died from the cold,
that wouldn't have passed.
If she'd been hit by a car,
What would your mother say, Effie?
She isn't here to say anything.
I'm not her, Aunt Mina...
Neither am I.
I can't be what she was to you.
You've a child of your own...
..and another coming soon.
Do you think that means
I wouldn't have room for you?
- I don't know.
- Oh!
I just didn't want you
to make her mistakes.
I am the mistake.
Oh, no.
No.
You're the gift.
What was it I said about
seeing yourself reflected?
That you don't approve.
That was it.
How nice to see a young person
conducting themselves with decorum.
Do you require assistance?
Yes.
Glue tastes horrible.
When I was a child, we used to
make chains out of scrap paper
and flour-and-water paste.
It was remarkably compelling -
one never knew quite when to stop,
or indeed if one wanted to.
I may get in...
..the Guinness World Records book.
Oh, really?
What's that?
For the longest paper
chain in the world.
Sister Monica Joan?
Where are you going?
Where He leads me.
You are to stay here,
and you are to rest.
I undertook to follow our Sister!
And I will.
WIND BLOWS
Ohh...
I knew Him at once
from the love...
..in His glance.
He came...
..He looked...
..and He departed.
In that case,
we will accept His blessing,
and go to seek Him in another place.
Oh, good afternoon.
I wonder if you might
be able to advise.
I require a telephone
number for a publishing body
called The Guinness
World Records book?
Have a happy Christmas.
I bring Yuletide greetings,
- by hand.
- Oh!
So much more, er, personal.
Yes,
and it saves on the cost of a stamp.
Is Reggie at home?
I've some rather
splendid news for him.
I didn't know what to say, Fred.
She presented it as a fait accompli.
What do you mean, a fait accompli?
She had it all planned out.
The youth club are
making paper chains,
the Townswomen's Guild
and Miss Nadine's Dancing School
are making paper chains,
and then they're all going to
be stuck together
so that Reggie can apply to be
in the Guinness World Records book.
Well, I bet that put him
in the Christmas spirit.
He's as bright and as happy
as a robin on a postbox.
PIPS SOUND Whoa, whoa. Hang on!
Well, that's what we want, innit?
Yes, it is - always.
I don't want him to be let down,
or disappointed, or embarrassed.
No, he won't be.
No - I promise.
It's easy for you to say.
You're still over 700 miles away.
Hang on.
COINS DROP
Hello?
Damn!
Mother Mildred is adamant.
This isn't the place for the Order.
The health authorities are
recruiting staff in the usual way.
The doctor will be a very lucky man.
I don't envy him.
I wish I'd been there with
you for the operation.
You'd have got a glimpse
of me as a younger man.
Oh, really? And what was he like?
Scared.
Competent, but scared.
My hands are always warm now.
I know what I'm doing...
..and I know where I belong.
Are they not feeding you enough?
You look as though you're
scavenging for scraps.
I'm scavenging for something...
..and I just hope Mrs
Norrie don't catch me.
I heard about that.
I think it was the tree
that she was at war with,
not something that would
make a child smile.
Are you trying to make
a child smile now?
Not a child,
but someone very special.
- You're packing up?
- Yes.
A new district nurse
arrives in the New Year.
Well, the pleasure of your
company has been requested.
Hi.
So, they can take these
back home after the party.
BAGPIPES PLAY
Thank you, Sister.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
♪ In the bleak midwinter
♪ Frosty wind made moan
♪ Earth stood hard as iron
♪ Water like a stone
♪ In the bleak midwinter
♪ A stable place sufficed
♪ The Lord God almighty
♪ Jesus Christ. ♪
TRAIN HORN BLOWS
I found Nurse Crane's whistle -
she left it on her mantelpiece.
Many thanks.
I have in fact secured the
loan of Mrs Buckle's bell.
MATURE JENNY: Some Christmases
will always be
more memorable than others.
Not because they surpass
all the others we've known,
but because the light shines
from a different source.
We're warmed, but made wiser,
welcomed in and given something new.
Christmas is not a competition,
but the prize itself.
The gathering and the sharing
of the things that matter most.
It is of no consequence
whether we are the
biggest or the brightest,
whether we're the strongest, the
bravest or the most inclined to win.
THEY CHEER
It is the smallest things
that have the highest value.
The glance that sees,
the ear that hears,
the thought made deed...
..and the links in the chain
of love that bind us all.
Merry Christmas!
Synced and corrected by Pindiu
- www.addic7ed.com -