Previously on "Dare Me"...
Colette French?
Some fancy new coach
from across the state
thinks she can come and run my squad?
What do I see? Spray tans.
Gummy bear thighs. Backyard tumblers.
I don't see a squad.
And I do not see my top girl.
- I'm the captain.
- We're not doing captains anymore.
- No, I'm captain. This is my squad.
- Wrong.
You're not like the others.
You know that, don't you?
[TENSE MUSIC]
- He's back.
- Sarge Will.
Wonder what he did all summer.
- [GUNSHOT]
- What the hell, B?
Beth, put the fucking gun down!
Beth, come on.
Just you and me, like the old days.
♪♪
Beth!
[LAUGHING]
♪♪
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
Do you know what desire is?
[SHOES SQUISHING WETLY]
Mutually assured destruction.
♪♪
[RASPING, SCRUBBING]
Coach told me that once.
♪♪
You know each other's secrets.
You've laid yourself bare.
♪♪
You both have everything to lose.
[LOCKER DOOR SLAMS]
Hurry up.
It's time.
[TENSE MUSIC]
Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com
[INTENSE RHYTHMIC MUSIC]
♪♪
You all look rode hard and put up wet,
like maybe you were up
to no good last night.
Okay, stop.
[ALL BREATHING HEAVILY]
Go home. Sleep it off.
You two, my office.
[DRAWER CLOSES]
What you saw last night was a mistake.
It's not gonna happen again.
So, I would appreciate it if you
could keep it to yourselves.
[MUTED CHATTER]
I don't interfere in
your personal lives, and...
I hope I can expect the same from you.
The squad needs to
have each other's back.
Are we good?
Sure, Coach. We good.
Squad deep.
I mean, even if we did want to tell...
Which we don't.
Look at you...
Wife,
mother,
star coach.
Who would ever believe
anything so lurid,
especially from a pair of teenage girls?
I mean, not even teenage
girls believe teenage girls.
That's not what this is about.
- We know.
- We do.
It's about the squad, just like you say.
Support your girl.
Stay tight. Legs together.
Lock your knees.
♪♪
Don't worry, Coach. We got your back.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[ROCK MUSIC]
♪ I'm not your mother ♪
♪ I'm not your bitch ♪
♪ D-did I stutter? ♪
- [GASPS]
- "We got your back, Coach."
Boy, one eyeful of her rosy tits,
and it's like you're hypnotized.
I was right, you know.
Right...?
She is a liar...
and a cheater,
and an appallingly bad one.
And since when are you
the morality police?
You were firing off rounds
last night like Tony Montana.
[MIMICS GUNSHOT]
It was hot.
People are already talking.
They better be.
Not everything is a game.
But it could be.
We play our cards
right, we may never have
to do another bleacher sprint.
[SCOFFS] Yeah, or make it to regionals.
Seriously, you care that
much about her personal life?
I care about a lot of things.
Yeah, till you don't anymore...
till you get bored.
There's nothing boring about
lusty Coach's warped fetish
for the wounded warrior.
It's just a shame that we
don't have it in living color.
Beth...
last night, you didn't.
How could I?
You knocked my phone out of my hand
like it was a goddamn grenade.
And you know the rules...
Pics, or it didn't happen.
Good.
Then it didn't happen.
If you say so.
I'm handling it. It's fine.
They're my girls.
[CHUCKLES] I don't know.
You didn't see what I saw at the party.
They're wild.
All girls that age are wild.
They don't know anything yet. It's easy.
But you weren't like that.
You were, um, so serious.
You used to come into the Esso
and get your bike tires filled.
You, uh... you had old eyes.
[SCOFFS] Is that supposed
to be a compliment?
Well, your eyes are younger now.
I should have never taken you up there.
Yeah, well, I shouldn't have gone.
[CLEARS THROAT]
So this is that kind of talk, huh?
Cool it before anybody gets hurt,
straighten up and fly right?
[TENSE MUSIC]
[SIGHS]
♪♪
I have a lot of eyes on me,
a lot of people watching,
all these expectations.
I can't take any more chances right now.
♪♪
Chest up. Eyes up.
- Everything tight.
- That's how it's done.
It is.
And now we will do it again...
[CLEARS THROAT]
with Tacy.
You heard me. Elevator her up.
Why?
If Beth's the better top girl,
aren't we just wasting time?
Listen up, all of you.
Getting to regionals
isn't about one girl.
It's about one squad,
regardless of who's on top.
Coach is right.
You remember what she said.
Top girl is a girl that
can control herself.
And last Friday night,
I didn't see a lot of self-control.
Self-control's just the beginning.
What I need to see is hard work,
sacrifice, trust.
If we can't count on each other,
we fail.
If we can't trust, we lose.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪♪
Now let's go.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
Hey.
You survived.
Uh, yeah.
Booster moms,
with J. J. Curtis leading the assault.
[CHUCKLES]
Bert swore if I had just
one drink with them...
Can you get PTSD from happy hour?
Well, having survived a J. J. ambush...
Mm.
I never really thanked you.
I didn't buy them to be thanked.
I know why you bought them.
And now I want the present
that comes after the present.
♪♪
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[BOTH LAUGH]
♪♪
[DRINK CAN POPS]
[CAN CRUMPLING]
♪ Coming up hard like '88,
make a bitch levitate ♪
♪ Babyface savage, bitch,
I don't play patty-cake ♪
♪ Charms in the carrot cake
carats in the Patek face ♪
♪ Cop a new coupe,
no top that's the Cali way ♪
♪ Drop a lil check, everybody lit ♪
- ♪ Lit ♪
- ♪ Drop a little check ♪
- ♪ Everybody rich
- ♪ Rich ♪
♪ Drop a little check, everybody slide ♪
Best control your little friend,
unless you want me to.
Oh, man. Look who's back.
Sarge Stud's never been here
two weeks in a row before.
He must love us.
♪♪
- Cold.
- At ease, boys.
After everything we shared Friday night.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
[UPBEAT POP MUSIC]
♪♪
Okay, everybody. Huddle up.
[INDISTINCT CHEERING]
Tight, clean, perfect.
This is Jeff East, my last squad,
the bid video that got
them into regionals
and then all the way to states.
Where they came in fifth.
[INDISTINCT CHEERING CONTINUES]
They wanted it. They worked for it.
It happened.
And it could be you...
now that you've been invited to submit.
- What?
- [EXCITED CHATTER, LAUGHTER]
That's why for the next two weeks,
everything that we do in
practice is about our video.
Forget football games.
Forget sideline cheer.
The video is the only
thing that matters.
Okay, let's get started
on that tumbling.
Hanlon, a word.
Not much of a team player, is she?
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
She wants this. She wants to win.
She wants those state rings.
As much as you do?
She'll do what's right for the squad.
I'll...
talk to her again.
It's not how it looks, Addy.
Me and him, it's...
It's not like that.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪♪
Like, I don't want to be seen with you
if you're, like, all bloaty here.
- Thirsty.
- Look at how big they are.
And it's only been, like, two weeks,
so I can't wait to see what
they're like three weeks...
Fetus, keep this flyswatter in check.
[SHOWER WATER RUNNING]
[WHISPERS] Bitch.
You know, when we make it to regionals,
it'll be you up there.
Regionals, regionals, regionals.
You know what you
should be worried about?
That video.
Of course I'm worried about the video.
Everyone wants it to be good.
Sorry, I meant the other video,
the one we almost got Friday night...
You know, Coach lap-banging Soldier Boy.
Beth.
Which sadly doesn't exist.
Like I said...
Pics, or it didn't happen.
Beth, stop fucking with me.
You don't have that video, right?
Coach is right. Trust is vital.
You know, I remember
a time way back when
when my best girl never doubted me.
Of course, if that's changed,
check for yourself.
You know you want to...
Mom.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
Forget it.
I believe you.
♪♪
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[UNEASY MUSIC]
♪♪
[BOTH LAUGHING]
[ZIPPER CLOSES]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC]
♪♪
- _
- [KEYBOARD CLICKING]
[PHONE BUZZES]
♪♪
- _
- [KEYBOARD CLICKING]
[PHONE BUZZES]
[GUN COCKING]
♪♪
[KEYBOARD CLICKING]
[BOTH LAUGHING]
- [SCREAMS]
- Oh, shit. Oh, sh...
[BOTH LAUGHING WILDLY]
♪♪
[CELL PHONE CHIMES, BEEPS]
[BEEPS] Hiderhole, Hiderhole.
♪♪
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]
- _
- Ew.
_
[KEYBOARD CLICKING]
[PHONE SWOOPS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Hey.
[TENSE MUSIC]
♪♪
Okay, it's not in my car. I checked.
Can't you just ask Sugar Daddy
Bert to get you a new one?
That's not what sugar daddy means.
- She lost her phone.
- Lost?
Strange, right?
I mean, considering
it's never out of my sight.
- You lost it the other night.
- Did I?
Remind me.
You know, I bet it's in the Jeep.
Once, I found mine
melted to my dashboard.
It looked like lava.
Couldn't even tell it was a phone.
Maybe.
Or maybe it went missing before that.
- What, like at practice?
- Yeah.
Here's an idea...
Buy a new one.
Mm, buy a new one, terrorists win.
Besides, I think
I'm gonna get that phone back.
Here...
use mine.
I don't want your phone.
So you're just gonna
live without a phone?
No.
You are.
[TENSE MUSIC]
♪♪
[BELL RINGS]
I want this timeline to work,
too, but the permits...
You worry too much.
It gives you wrinkles.
We got this. Oh, there she is.
Sweetie, this is...
This is Mr. Coach himself,
Matt French.
- Uh, Coach isn't married.
- [BOTH LAUGH]
Sure is. Four years and counting.
Oh, wow.
Um, she just doesn't...
She doesn't give off a big wife vibe.
She seems so...
free.
Well, uh, I should get going.
- Hey.
- Oh, thanks.
[CLEARS THROAT]
That's how you got her here.
Well, remember, sweet peach,
I got her here for you.
[SIGHS] Hey.
How you doing on gas money?
Or... or you know what? Better yet.
Spankin' new coach means you should have
spankin' new cheer shoes, am I right?
- Here.
- More.
More.
Someone stole my phone.
Wow, surrounded by thieves and traitors.
Ah, I get it.
Listen, Elizabeth Ann...
I love you. You know that.
You're always shooting for that
"number one dad" mug, aren't you?
And I'm sorry about Friday.
- Uh, your mother...
- Let me guess.
It was a mistake.
It'll never happen again.
Hey, that's a promise, angel face.
Uh-huh.
[LEIKELI47'S "MONEY"]
♪ All my life,
I had to grind and hustle ♪
♪ I had to work like Kobe just to... ♪
Told you.
I knew he'd pay up.
- You have many talents.
- [LAUGHS]
♪ They say, damn you changed ♪
♪ I'm like, "Show you money,"
I got money ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
[CAR HORN HONKS]
You sure you don't mind closing?
I mind.
Just don't come back with a shaved head.
It's just talking,
just getting some tips.
Sergeant Will used to
play back in the day.
I know. He told me.
- He recruiting you, too?
- No.
- He gave us a ride Friday night.
- Oh, shit.
Home from Lanvers?
I heard Beth was in fine form,
making moves like a gangsta.
No comment.
[CHUCKLES] She's the
one they should recruit.
- [GROANS]
- [LAUGHS]
[DOORBELL DINGS]
- Hey, you.
- Hey.
So, if you were to sign up...
and I'm not saying you should...
it'd be a hell of a lot easier
than what you're doing now...
Practice before school,
lifting, conditioning.
I mean, you've already
got the self-discipline.
Hell of a lot more than I
had when I was your age.
- You played quarterback?
- No.
[CHUCKLES] No, I played fullback.
I wasn't really that
good, but I loved it.
Dislocated my shoulder,
knocked three of my front teeth out.
The pain was all worth it, you know?
It always is.
It's like we say on the T-shirt...
"Pain is fear leaving the body."
Always stumping for the Marines, huh?
[CHUCKLES]
The Corp got me out
of my old man's house,
showed me the world, gave me structure.
But I didn't have your arm, so I get it.
You don't want to let that go.
At your age, there's gonna be
a lot of things that you want...
and you've got to try to get them.
You'll regret it if you don't.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
♪♪
[SOFT MUSIC]
Hey, so I know it's late,
but I think I'm actually
gonna drive over to Sterling Heights
and cosign that lease for my mom.
I don't want her calling again.
She's easier in the
evenings after she's had
- that third Kahlua and cream.
- [CHUCKLES]
She still, uh, living with that guy,
that bail bondsman?
- What's his name?
- Izzy.
Yeah, they're all named Izzy.
- [SMALL LAUGH]
- But if I get it over with...
[CLEARS THROAT]
She drives you crazy.
You really want to do that to yourself?
Just stay here with us.
I'd love to,
but if I don't go see her...
- She'll come see us.
- Yep.
Sold.
[KEYS JINGLE, CAR ALARM BEEPS]
[CAR ENGINE TURNS OVER]
[THE RAVEONETTES' "WINE"]
♪ Stars ♪
♪ Asleep ♪
♪ Lone ♪
- _
- ♪ Roads ♪
♪ Sprinkled ♪
♪ With tears ♪
♪ Don't ♪
♪ Self-destruct ♪
♪ Kill time ♪
♪ With a baseball bat ♪
♪ And it makes me cry, makes me cry ♪
♪ Summer threw our love away ♪
♪ Makes me cry, makes me cry ♪
♪ Threw our love away... ♪
Really? It's gonna take that long?
Dude says, like, 30 minutes for takeout.
- It's insane.
- [GROANS]
This is boring. I'm bored.
You want to stomp it out?
Phone.
You, film this.
Lock up your sons!
- Lock up your boys.
- [BOTH POUND HANDS]
BOTH: Lock up your sons.
Lock up your boys.
- Mom and Dad.
- BOTH: Lock up your sons.
- Lock up your boys.
- Mom and Dad.
Lock up your sons.
Lock up your boys, Mom and Dad.
Ready? Let's stomp.
- [BOTH STOMPING]
- Stomp, stomp, stomp,
stomp it out.
Stomp, stomp, stomp, stomp it out.
Lock up your chastity belt.
We're coming for you.
We're gonna stomp it out.
Lock up your chastity belt.
We're coming for you.
We're gonna stomp it out.
Lock up your chastity belt.
We're coming for you.
We're gonna stomp it out.
- [CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
- [SCREAMS]
Hiderhole, Hiderhole.
Whatever Beth Cassidy has on you,
she probably already
uploaded it somewhere.
You don't get it.
That's not how we work.
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]
What is it? I need to see.
BOTH: Lock up your chastity belts.
We're coming for you.
We're gonna stomp it out.
Lock up your chastity belt.
We're coming for you.
We're gonna stomp it out.
- _
- [PHONE CHIMES]
Wait, Hanlon?
She knows you have her phone?
See? This is how we work.
[BALI BABY'S "PROFESSOR
FINESSOR" PLAYING]
♪ Professor finessor,
she jukin' out the Tesla ♪
♪ Professor finessor ♪
♪ Yeah, I'll apply the pressure ♪
♪ Professor finessor,
I say my name Vanessa ♪
♪ Yeah, coming in heavy, shoot ♪
♪ What a superstar do, yeah ♪
♪ Superstar coming in too hot ♪
♪ Superstar, superstar move ♪
♪ Yeah, hit them with the Euro step ♪
[BOTH LAUGHING]
So you're Sarge Stud's new lapdog?
The Sergeant needed some help
- with all you wild things.
- Right.
Well, hell,
why don't you invite him over?
Not gonna happen, pretty girl.
Why so interested in the Boy Scout?
Maybe I have some classified
information about him.
Yeah? What's that?
- Not such a Boy Scout.
- [LAUGHS]
Maybe not,
but he's still not gonna play with you,
and I thought you were here to play,
at least till your mama comes home.
[LAUGHS] Or wakes up.
Still nothing?
You, uh, want my help with the trash?
The trash. The trash!
Oh, shit, yeah!
Beth, you unbearable tease.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
♪♪
♪ He hit me ♪
♪ But it felt like a kiss ♪
♪♪
♪ He hit me ♪
♪ But I knew he loved me ♪
♪♪
♪ And if he didn't care for me ♪
♪ It would have never made him mad ♪
♪ But he kissed me ♪
♪ And I was glad ♪
♪♪
[MAGIC ISLAND'S "LIKE WATER"]
♪ The lights, they fall ♪
♪ Cover your head ♪
♪ We thought we live ♪
♪ But still we're dead ♪
♪ I'm waiting up, I'm waiting up ♪
♪ I'm waiting for you ♪
♪ The lights, they fall ♪
- Thanks, Sarge.
- Of course.
- Have a good night.
- You too.
We meet again.
Hey, look,
your friend from the other night,
she's okay, right?
Yeah.
That's just a Friday night for Beth.
You know, Colette and I...
Coach French,
I don't know if she told you,
but we go way back.
Um... no.
She didn't.
Yeah, our paths used to cross
all the time in high school.
They kept crossing.
- You went to school together?
- Same parties.
[CHUCKLES]
I remember one time,
we ended up out at Rattlesnake Point.
Cops came.
We all piled in my cousin's car, and...
somehow, she wound up on my lap.
She was so shy,
maybe even, uh, regal,
if that makes sense.
But she wasn't like anyone else.
So, when I saw her a few months later
standing under one of those
glittery balls at some dance,
I wasn't gonna miss my chance twice.
I mean, what happened?
You guys didn't end up together.
She had places she wanted to go.
So did I.
I guess it's like my
old man used to say...
"The past is never where you left it."
Would you do me a favor?
I always liked her hair down.
But, uh...
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪♪
Yeah.
Thank you.
♪♪
[CAR DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[CAR ENGINE TURNS OVER]
Tell me that was a Jehovah Witness.
He's just a recruiter from school.
He was here for Slocum.
[TENSE MUSIC]
♪♪
Hey.
You have fun with RiRi last night?
Mm, just as it was starting
to get interesting,
J.J. pulled the plug.
Well, I've got some good news.
Here.
You wouldn't believe where I found it.
Your panties?
Locker room.
It must have slipped between the towels.
[TENSE MUSIC]
Did you look inside?
Why would I do that?
Don't you want to peer into the secrets
of my black old heart?
I guess I already know all your secrets.
♪♪
Don't be so sure.
[DOG BARKING IN THE DISTANCE]
- Oh, hey.
- Hi. Um, Mr. French?
Matt. You're... Oh, you're...
of Colette's mighty
band of warriors, huh?
Yeah, Addy. Um, I was just...
Yeah, I-I'm late for a work thing,
but go on in.
- [CAR ALARM BEEPS]
- Okay.
[BABY CRYING DISTANTLY]
Hey, what are you doing?
Uh, come in. Come in.
[BABY CRYING OVER MONITOR]
Glamorous, right? [SCOFFS]
Some day all this can be yours.
[CRYING CONTINUES OVER MONITOR]
[LULLABY PLAYING]
♪♪
She must have had a bad dream.
She's beautiful.
♪♪
She is.
She really is.
♪♪
[DOOR CLICKS CLOSED]
Go on.
[TENSE MUSIC]
This is my favorite room.
When I was a kid,
I used to always have to share
a room with my brother.
Then the day I got my first period,
my mom hung a sheet up in
the middle of the room.
The wall of privacy was
what she called that.
All I ever wanted was my own room.
And now you have it.
It's important to make things
happen for yourself, Addy.
Don't wait for things.
Make them yours.
I will.
There are a lot of things that I want.
Every morning,
I put all of these little pillows
back on the bed.
And every night...
[BOTH LAUGH]
[GIGGLES]
Italian.
1,200 thread count.
You should feel it on your skin.
Sit.
♪♪
[CHUCKLES]
Come on, touch it.
♪♪
Oh. [SCOFFS]
I almost forgot.
- Where did you...
- He gave it to me.
Sarge Will.
You saw Will?
Yeah.
He said things about you,
about how you were.
The way he talked about you...
Must be something...
Someone wanting you like that.
♪♪
You should go to him.
What?
No... no.
♪♪
Look, I know that you think
that this is easy,
but it... it's not. I...
I can't.
Don't miss your chance twice.
Addy...
Go.
I'll stay here, okay?
I'll watch your kid.
We could have moved, you know?
At any point.
And let them win?
Never.
♪♪
[IDLES' "COLOSSUS"]
♪ I was done in on the weekend ♪
♪ The weekend lasted 20 years ♪
It's strange to look back,
to see the person you thought you were.
[MOANS]
♪ Tender, violent, and queer ♪
There were things I did,
bad things.
I'd like to say I had to...
that I had no choice.
♪ My body full of pins ♪
♪ I've danced till dawn ♪
♪ With splintered shins ♪
But we always have a choice...
and those choices can
lead us to dark places.
♪♪
♪ Forgive me, Father ♪
♪ I have sinned ♪
♪ I've drained my body full of pins ♪
♪ I've danced till dawn ♪
♪ With splintered shins ♪
♪ Full of pins ♪
♪ Goes, and it goes and it goes,
♪ Goes, and it goes, and it goes ♪
♪ Go, go, go, go, go, go ♪
♪♪
The truth is, it was like
I was living for the first time.
And once you feel that,
you'll do anything to keep feeling it.
♪ It's coming ♪
Anything.
- [HEAVY BREATHING]
- ♪ It's coming ♪
♪ It's coming ♪
[GASPS]
Synced & corrected by QueenMaddie
www.addic7ed.com