(Siren)
- We set up
fair-trade agreements
with women's organizations
in poverty-stricken areas
of Turkey, Morocco
and Indonesia,
with future
development scheduled
for India and central
and southern Africa.
- So tell us,
how does this work exactly?
- Being properly compensated
for their labour and their goods
enables them, in turn,
to support their families,
educate their children,
create local industry
and build economic growth.
- And your partners?
I mean, Fyne Designs is not
just Sophie Fyne. Is it?
- No, we are 3 equal partners
with 3 very specific talents.
- Ian Jameson,
for example,
he's had a lot of
international recognition
for his innovative
development strategies.
A bit of a whiz kid,
would you say?
- No, he definitely is.
And Adam Fyne brilliantly
manages our finances,
which enables both Ian and I
to do what we do best.
- And what is it
that you do best, Sophie?
- Using regional and
sustainable materials,
I try to design clothing
and accessories
that reflect the strength
and resilience of women...
(Goat bleating
and bell tinkling)
...honouring their cultural
skills and craftsmanship
and celebrating their beauty.
-
Wonderful.
Now, with only a few
select retailers
carrying the
Fyne Designs label,
to now launching
your very own store
in Manhattan's coveted
Lower East Side,
how do you feel?
- Positive.
Exhilarated. Um...
(Chuckling)
Mostly terrified.
(Bucket clattering)
(Goat bleating)
(Gasps)
- But let's talk
a little bit about
your highly-anticipated
ad campaign.
It's expected to be
very cutting edge,
to really make a statement.
Tell us.
- It's called Empower,
stressing how women should not
be victimized by fashion.
That means those wearing it,
buying it or making it.
- Great. Thank you so much for
taking time out to speak to us
and, uh, we wish you
all the best.
With the opening
just 7 days away,
we'll be
following closely.
- Thank you.
- I'm Megan Harris
for
Fashion Uncovered.
♪♪ Come on, let's go
- Gorgeous! Very pretty.
♪ Baby
I love that.
Don't move, Danielle.
All right.
Little more to the right
and shove a little bit right.
Great look.
♪ I am free now, baby... ♪
Chin up, girls.
Gorgeous.
So hot.
(Chuckles)
Very pretty.
Love it!
We're almost there, girls.
Just a few more.
Oh, for god sake!
What now?
- No, seriously,
like, my arm is killing me.
- Yeah, well...
Let's take 20.
- Thank you, everybody.
It looks amazing.
(Models sighing)
(Sighing)
- I don't know about you, but
I'm kind of turned on right now.
- Yeah, that would be
why I hired you
and why I would
never sleep with you.
(Chuckles)
- Are sure about this?
I mean, an ad campaign
about a clothing line
without any clothes.
I mean, I've done some pretty
out-there stuff, believe me.
- We talking personally
or professionally?
- Is there a difference?
- No, I've got something
important to say
and I've got a rare
opportunity to do it.
So with your help, we can get
somebody to hear what it is
and maybe even do
something about it.
- So you think there's
actually more to life
than satisfying
your own needs and desires?
Nah.
(Giggling)
- Get out of here!
(Ringing)
Hey, honey!
-
Hey, Mom.
- Home from school?
-
Not yet. I was gonna
stop by the studio
and maybe help out
with the photo shoot.
- Spencer.
-
I wanna show you
I can do it. I'm ready.
- How many times do we have
to have this conversation?
It's not gonna happen.
-
I don't get it.
You work in fashion
and with models who are
younger than me.
What's the difference?
- If you had to pay
for oxygen,
you wouldn't waste
so much of it on this.
-It's not fair.
Daddy would let me.
- We'll talk about this
when I'll get home.
-Fine.
- (Woman):
Well, I tried to order...
(Clears throat)
(Siren and honking in distance)
- Oh!
- Hi.
- Mmm!
I missed you.
- I missed you too.
(Giggling)
Won't need this either.
- Ah!
- Ooh! What's wrong?
Are you OK?
- I'm just great.
(Sighing)
♪♪ This time it's also here
♪ You came to me again
♪ Making me stronger
♪ We're moving up
♪ Keep the flame
burning longer ♪
♪ You're making it stronger
♪ It's building up higher ♪
(Boat horn honking)
- Corner loft, 5110.
Mm-hmm.
No, the key just snapped off
in the lock.
OK, I'll see you
in an hour. Thanks.
My god! What happened?
- Huh? Oh!
- What is that?
- Your extremely
clumsy husband tripped
and was impaled on
a bead-carving tool
in one of the workshops.
- Did you see a doctor?
- I did, but there was a woman
there who fixed me up good.
Looks vicious,
but it's better than it was.
(Sophie scoffing)
It's nothing, come on!
- Yeah, it doesn't
look like nothing.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey.
Wow! Remind me to
go away more often
if that is the welcome I get
from my beautiful daughter
when I get home.
- She's saving money on oxygen.
- I bet. Come on.
- I missed you.
- Yes, I missed you too.
And you're late.
Come eat.
- Models don't eat.
- Spencer, sweetheart,
you will model
over my dead body.
You're too young.
Besides, 6 months ago, you were
ripping up fashion magazines
protesting the
exploitation of women.
Now all of a sudden
you want to be a model.
- It's a woman's privilege
to change her mind.
- Yes. Yes, it is.
Except you are not
a woman yet.
- Daddy!
- Legally, your mom's
got a point.
My point is if you
declare your womanhood,
it weakens your argument to
be calling to Daddy for help.
Huh?
- Hey! Not near
the Chanel, Spencer!
- Sometimes I think
you care more
about that stupid
sketch book than me.
(Scoffing)
- Ouch!
(Clearing throat)
What's going on
with you two?
- It's been
3 weeks of that.
- Oh yeah?
What prompted it?
- Her 16th birthday.
- Huh!
- So, how was the trip?
- Oh! Well, after
jumping through
way too many frustrating
hoops and time zones,
everything is finally
arranged and on schedule.
- Good. Did you bring samples of
the beaded garments with you?
- Ian's got them.
- I'll get them later.
- Well, he's not back yet.
- What? Is there a problem?
You just said
everything was on track.
- Everything is
on track, Sophie.
You know Ian.
He's thorough.
He decided to head back to Fez
to triple-check everything.
- Oh! Reminds me.
Did you see this about Ian?
- Yes. I did.
Nice.
- It's good, right?
- Sure getting a lot
of press, isn't he?
- For our company.
- I know. I just...
I know.
He'll be back in a few days.
Just in time for the opening.
- I'm glad you're home.
- Glad to be home.
(Both sighing)
- Spencer! You're gonna
be late for school!
- Huh!
(Chuckles)
Oh, hey!
You know, I heard this
rumour that models don't eat,
but students do.
- Have a
good day, sweetie.
(Sophie chuckles)
- Oh!
Well, you know, we made it
through the terrible twos.
This is gonna
be a breeze.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
(Clears throat)
(Honking)
(Siren in distance)
(Talking, indistinct)
- Sophie, we've got
a problem.
- Uh, "challenge," Alexa,
not "problem".
- The colour of the fabric dyed
at the workshop in Fez
doesn't match our
finished purse style SF1227.
But they said it
turned out nice anyway.
So the problem is-- Sorry.
The challenge is if you need
to see the colour for approval,
it'll delay getting to
the embroiderers,
the beaders and the sewers,
postponing the
scheduled completion
and shipping date
for the bags.
- Right. I'll take care of it.
Thank you.
- (Man 1): That one?
- (Man 2): Yes. Here.
(Talking, indistinct)
- Come on!
- (Man 2): Jeff!
Jeff, come here.
(Cell phone ringing)
- Hope all this publicity isn't
going to your handsome head.
-
Excuse me?
Oh, hey, Adam.
I thought you were
Ian calling me back.
- Networks are a little spotty
in the more remote villages.
So what's up?
-You said he was going
back to Fez, right?
- Yeah, that's right.
- We've got a dye-lot question
that needs an answer,
so I thought maybe--
- Perhaps he can take
his handsome head
and check in with
Mrs. Bashiri, right?
- Exactly.
- If I can reach him,
I will ask.
- Thank you. Bye.
- See ya.
(Honking)
- And how's life
in the art world?
- It's insane. The worse
the economy gets,
the more people need
to sell their collections.
It's actually brought some
amazing pieces to the market.
I'm overseeing this huge
auction this week...
You OK?
- Oh, sorry, Drea.
It's just Spencer.
Wish there was way
to make her understand
that her mother does know
what's good for her.
- Well, if you figure it out
you'll revolutionize parenting.
Listen, you are a fantastic
mother who loves her daughter.
You guys are gonna
figure this out.
By the time she's
40 at the latest.
- Oh great!
Thank you so much.
Oh, and the deadline for the
opening isn't exactly helping.
It's 5 days away.
I don't know
if our shipment
is going to get
here in time.
Everything we have
is riding on this.
Oh! It's my turn.
- Oh. Thanks.
- Thank you.
(Sighing)
It's just a lot, you know.
- Yeah.
-
Mesdames.
- Claudio.
- Hi.
- Your whole
saving-the world-
one-designer-outfit-
at-a-time thing
is literally starting
to wear thin.
There's a certain way
that the fashion business
has always been done
and will continue
to be done.
You're getting to be too good
at making us all look very bad.
- You don't need
Sophie for that.
- You can change the way
you run your company.
- Oh?
- Enable everybody
involved to benefit,
rather then just
a select few.
Or you can stick to your
old ways and take and take
and never
give anything back.
This way, I can
sleep at night.
There's a lot
of amazing women
all over the world
working with us,
who can do
the same thing.
- Rest assured, Sophie, dear.
I sleep like a baby.
Besides, you should never
mess with a classic.
Speaking of which, any chance
you're ready to part
with that beloved
Chanel book of yours?
- No, Claudio.
- A word to the wise:
Fashion has its price
and it's very, very high.
- Um, I'm sorry, Ms. Fyne.
But there seems to be a problem
with your credit card.
- Oh.
- Like I said, very high.
- That's impossible. I'm sorry,
would you mind running it again?
- Um, I already did.
- Next time.
(Sighing)
(Scoffs)
- He just keeps
getting older
while his playmates
stay the same age.
- Maybe he's taking up
babysitting.
Probably needs cash after
the rotten year he's had.
- See? Maybe karma
does exist.
(Laughing)
- Oh!
(Sophie laughing)
- Well, give Spencer
a hug for me, huh?
- I'll try.
- (Both): Bye.
- Hey, Mike, it's lunch time.
Let's go grab a bite.
(Creaking)
Look out!
- Listen, if we don't
have it this week,
my guys are gonna
be delayed.
There's no way
we can finish on time.
- Listen, we'll finish
this later. OK, Jerry?
Thank you.
I promise.
Hey! How was lunch?
- It was OK,
except why would
my credit card
be declined?
- What? Um, I don't know.
It's strange.
I'll give them a call.
- And did you get a hold
of Ian about the dye lot?
- I did, so the purses
can be sized and cut
before heading out to Meknes
for embroidery, beading
and finishing.
Yes, I did.
- Thank you.
And when's he coming back?
- Actually, he's in Tunisia,
checking out some new suppliers.
- The opening's in 5 days!
We need everybody here,
not Tunisia.
That's not best use
of his time.
- I'll call him.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Hey! Is that my key?
- Yes, your new copy.
- Yes, thank you.
(Cell phone ringing)
Oh!
(Clears throat)
Hello?
OK. Thanks.
Customs.
- Our shipment?
That would be really good.
(Giggling)
- See ya. Bye.
- Bye.
Hello.
- Sophie,
we really gotta go.
Katif's waiting
in the studio.
- Oh! Yeah. Thanks.
(Car honking)
- The dried fibres of the lokta
bark woven into the fabric
gives it more body
and texture.
- These are
exquisite, Katif.
So the lokta plant
is sustainable?
- Oh, we harvest just
the bark, which regenerates.
(Clears throat)
- I can already think
of a dozen designs
for the next
collection with this.
Let's add, um...
Let's add a 20-yard cut
of this one to my order.
You know what?
- Mm-hmm?
- One each of this
and the grey.
- Always a pleasure.
Um, uh, Sophie.
I do have to talk
to you about something
that isn't sustainable.
- Of course.
- Our payment terms.
We need to
switch to COD.
- Don't be ridiculous.
As long as we've
known each other,
you know we have
impeccable credit.
- Word on the street
right now is otherwise.
Big city, small street.
- Ka-- Katif, there's gotta
be some kind of mistake.
- I'm sorry, Sophie.
It's business.
(Boys laughing and talking)
- (Boy): Yo, yo!
- You're totally worth it.
No!
(Girl talking, indistinct)
- (Boy): Yo! Hold up!
(Many voices talking)
- (Justin):
...especially in the summer.
- Exactly.
- It's like a nice...
- Hey, Justin!
- Hi. Yeah, nice...
(Talking, indistinct)
- (Boy):
Hey, pass it here!
- (Girl):
Good! You know it!
(♪ Muted music
in earphones ♪)
- Adam, I just met with Katif.
He wants payment on delivery.
Do we have a problem?
- Yeah, we do.
Mr. Fyne! Please.
- I gotta go.
(Man on CB, indistinct)
- Have a look.
- Oh!
(Fly buzzing)
(Exhaling)
- I'm FBI Agent Fincher.
Thank you both for coming down.
With high temperatures
this time of year,
"decomp" was severely
accelerated,
so making time of death almost
impossible to determine.
We do know the "vic" is female
and was most likely strangled.
- I'm--I'm sorry.
I'm not sure I understand.
Aside from the fact
that an article of
our clothing was found,
what does this have
to do with us?
The tracking label was fake,
but the delivery address
of the container was yours,
so anyway you look at it
we'd talk to you
about this body.
All the other ID, shipping
documents, country of origin,
all has to be verified.
She could have
been placed inside
at any point
along the way.
- Was there
anything else
found in the container?
- Nothing. Any idea
who she might be?
- No.
- Hmm... Do you
know of anyone
who might have something
against your company,
trying to send you
a message of some sort?
- (Whispering): No.
No. No?
- Our company's
philosophy differs
from a lot of
our competitors.
Some have expressed their
displeasure vocally,
but, I mean, none of them
would do it this far.
- No.
- Well, there's more questions
than answers at this point.
We'll contact you
when we know more.
And please let us know
if anything else out of
the ordinary comes up.
- OK. Anything we can
do to help.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
(Door closing)
(Sighing)
(Siren)
- What was that, Adam?
I mean, that was clearly
our label, our fabric.
Who would do
something like this?
- I don't know.
- And why?
- I don't know, Sophie.
Maybe we got caught up
in something we have
nothing to do with.
- It's no random incident.
How is this connected to us?
Oh!
God, what is
wrong with me?
- What?
- This could be somebody's
mother, somebody's daughter.
(Fire engine honking)
(Sighing)
- Listen, we'll know
more when they do.
And then we'll deal
with it, together, OK?
(Honking)
-
A near-tragedy at New York's
Port Authority earlier today
led to the discovery of another
tragedy bizarrely interwoven
with fledgling enviro-design
company Fyne Designs.
Question now is how will fair
trade becoming fear trade
affect their
highly anticipated
flagship store opening
just 5 days away?
- Have to prepare
a statement.
- Saying what?
- I don't know, Adam,
We have to say something.
We gotta take control
of the situation.
- No, we gotta stay
focused on the things
that we actually
can control.
- Trying to make their lives
better and look what happens.
(Sighing)
- Listen, we don't even
know what happen to her.
- What about Katif, and probably
other suppliers, asking for COD?
How do we control that?
- It's just simple math,
more money going out
than coming in
right now, that's all.
Oh.
Uh... here.
It's all straightened out.
Sophie, listen to me.
It's just like this
in the beginning.
The work at the store, it's
never ever what it's quoted.
That's what I was
talking to Jerry about.
And the ad campaign,
I mean...
it's great...
but it's a lot.
- When did you say the shipment
is coming in? Our shipment?
- Yeah. The flight's
coming in day after next.
- Nothing like
cutting it close.
- It's gonna be OK.
(Sighing)
(Telephone ringing)
- Hmm...
(Ringing)
- Thank you.
Hello.
(Sighing)
Yeah, got your message.
Yeah, I got a sample.
We're gonna have to
talk about new pricing.
(Honking and sirens)
Hey.
(Sighing)
Can't sleep?
- (Spencer): No.
- Did you see it
in the news?
- I was tweeted.
- Listen, um,
everything's gonna be OK.
There's nothing to
worry about, all right?
(Chuckles)
- Dad?
- Mm-hmm?
- What did mom do
to make you like her...
love her?
- What do you mean,
what did she do?
- I mean, when
you guys first met,
did she talk or dress
in a certain way
that made you notice her?
- Oh! Um...
when I first met
your mother, it was, uh...
- Love at first sight?
- Oh no.
(Chuckling):
No, no, no, no.
It was more like
loathe at first sight.
- What do you mean?
- It was the first
few days of our design school
and we were put in the same
group in marketing class,
and our job-- our job was
just to make a business plan.
That's it. But your mother--
Your mother, she was--
Well, you know, she's idealistic
and she's--she's stubborn.
- I must get the stubborn
part from her then.
- For the record, you said that.
I did not say that.
- Yeah.
- OK.
Those things at first,
they just-- They drove me nuts.
But those were the things that
made up who she was.
Who she is.
An independent-thinking,
determined woman
who will never ever
take no for an answer
if there's even the slightest
possibility of a yes.
So no, she never had to say
anything or do anything
or be anything other
than exactly what she was,
because that's the person
I fell in love with.
(Chuckles)
So is there a reason
you're asking, or...
- No reason.
- No. No, no reason.
Of course not.
Mm-hmm?
(Giggles)
- I love you, Daddy.
- I love you too.
Good night.
- Can you leave that on?
- Yeah, sure.
- Thanks.
- Spencer, honey, wait up.
I'm going your way.
(♪ Muted music on earphones )
So when is there a moratorium
on hating her mother?
- Oh, she doesn't hate you.
How can she?
She's just like you.
She's determined,
she's a perfectionist.
- Really?
- Absolutely.
And right now
she's determined
to make your life
a perfect hell.
(♪ Muted music )
- Coming to work?
- I gotta run errands
for the opening.
- Oh. Uh-huh.
(Cell phone beeping)
- She might get her
determination from me
but the ability to
tune me out is from you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Spencer!
Spencer!
Spencer?
Spencer.
You OK?
- What?
- Oh god!
- I'm fine! Why?
- Honey, you were
almost run over!
- What?
- Honey,
you can't walk around
in your own
little bubble.
- We're serious
about this.
- OK! I'm sorry.
- Oh honey!
(Panting)
(Honking)
- Did you catch
the license plate number?
- No.
- No. No.
- The make of the car?
- Um, black SUV.
American.
- I might recognize the driver
if I saw him again.
- Listen, it just
happened so fast.
- Can't you do something?
Whoever this was, was trying
to run down our daughter.
- You're not giving me
a lot to go on here.
Maybe it wasn't intentional.
(Both sighing)
Well, if any other details
come to mind, let me know.
We'll see what we can do.
(Pen clicking)
Would you mind if
I took some of these?
They'll be returned.
- Yeah, of course.
- Thank you.
(Honking)
- No! Crap!
(Sighing)
- Sophie.
- Claudio.
- Feeling the pressure of
a deadline, are we?
Or perhaps dead bodies?
- Well, that's a little nasty
even for you, isn't it?
- Hmm...
The quicker you rise
the faster you fall, my dear.
The trick is not
to look down.
- Fortunately, I'm not
afraid of heights, Claudio.
- You can design
a new wheel, Sophie,
but you can never
re-invent it.
Best not to die trying.
(Sighing)
- Hmm...
What the--
No. What the heck?
(Honking in distance)
- They're in!
- What's in?
- The proofs
from the photo shoot.
- Oh!
Oh, these are good.
These are really good.
Oh my god!
(Sighing)
Spencer.
Spencer!
- Hey! What's going on?
- This!
- Oh.
(Door opening)
- Spencer,
get over here now.
- What's going on?
Why are you yelling?
- Recognize these?
- Look. I know what
you're thinking.
But I was fully dressed.
- (Adam):
Doesn't look that way.
- Your photographer thought
it would be fun.
He used his computer
to put me in the picture.
- Why, Spencer?
- To shock you into seeing how
good a model I could be.
- Shock me?
That's great!
Why haven't you
answered your phone?
I've been calling.
- I fainted.
- What? Have you eaten anything?
- I had an apple.
I came home earlier
but my keys didn't work.
I was feeling kind of woozy,
so I went to the park to sit
down and I guess I fainted.
Next thing I know,
a man helps me up
and insists on
taking me home.
- Whoa. What man?
- He said he knew you
through business.
A Mr. Cassadrian or something.
He's out front.
He said he would wait
to make sure I got in OK.
(Inaudible)
- You're not eating to
the point of passing out,
and now this photo
stunt you pulled!
What are you
thinking, Spencer?
You're so grounded.
Give me the cell phone.
- What?
- Cell phone.
- Daddy!
(Scoffing)
(Sighing)
(Slams)
- Maybe we should cut her
a little slack, huh?
- She's starving herself.
- I know.
- She went behind
my back to model
and now she could have
ended up with God knows who?
She's smarter
than this.
- Yes, she is.
She's just trying to find
a way to get what she wants.
It's not so bad.
(Sighing)
- I don't know anyone
named Cassadrian, do you?
- No.
(♪ Rock on stereo )
(Sighing)
- I'll handle it.
- Thank you.
- OK.
- Hey!
- All right.
Hey, is there
any word from Ian yet?
- Yeah. He's on
his way back.
- When?
- Any day now.
- Any day?
How non-committal is that?
He's gonna be here
for the show, right?
- Yes.
He will be here
for the show.
I gotta go check
on some customs specs
and then I got
a meeting at the bank.
- OK.
- See you tonight?
- All right.
- Sophie, I've been
getting calls
from the press.
Would you have time to go over
the seating arrangements?
- Wait! Sorry, sorry.
Adam, Adam!
- But they're
calling me. I can't--
Adam!
- Thank you.
(Both laughing)
- Very appreciative.
- See ya later.
- Bye.
Oh, for god sake!
Hey!
Who the hell are you and why
have you been following me?
- He's with me.
- Agent Marks. FBI.
- You want something?
- No.
- Two coffees.
Thank you.
- What is your relationship
with Mr. Ian Jameson?
He's our business partner
and friend.
- Is that all?
- Why have you been stalking me?
- Oh, just wanted to see
if you'd had any
contact with Mr. Jameson.
- And what did you see?
- That you didn't...
physically.
- Does Ian have
something to do
with the body that
was in the container?
- This situation has become
a little complicated
and we thought you could
help us clarify a few things.
- Thank you.
How about Mr. Jameson
and your husband?
How do they get along?
- Like brothers, with the
occasional rivalry.
Men and their egos.
But they make a good team.
All 3 of us do.
- Any conflicts?
- We're partners
with the demands
of a growing business
in a competitive industry.
Of course there are conflicts,
but there are resolutions.
- Any reason to
think otherwise?
- We each have certain strengths
and weaknesses. Don't you?
- How involved are you in each
other's sides of the company?
- We consult and
keep each other informed
on the overall activities,
but we each have clearly
our day-to-day
responsibilities and tasks.
I mean, if we kept our hands in
each other's work all the time,
we'd never get
anything done, would we?
- Has your husband had any
dealings with anyone new?
- My husband handles
our finances.
He's constantly dealing
with people I don't know.
Look, we're both
extremely busy.
I don't keep tabs on every
person my husband deals with
while managing our accounts
and balancing our books.
Nor does he check to see
which buttons I choose.
We trust each other.
- Do you know if
your husband's heard
from Mr. Jameson
since their trip?
- Why don't you
ask my husband that?
Do I need to
call my lawyer?
- No.
- Then I'm free to go?
(Sighing)
- If you do come across
anything else unexpected,
it would be in the best interest
of you and your family
to give us a call.
- Just be careful
who you trust, Ms. Fyne.
- Adam, we need to talk.
Fine, but don't be home
too late, all right?
I'll see you there.
(Approaching footsteps)
Spencer...
Come here.
Sit with me.
Please.
Sit.
I know I've been really hard
on you the last few weeks.
God knows you've
given me reason.
But...
there's a lot going on
with us right now.
But I've had no right to take
that frustration out on you.
So I'm sorry.
- There's this boy
at school, Justin.
We're always joking
around and texting and...
- And?
- He asked Melanie to
the end-of-the-year dance.
- And Melanie is...
- A model.
- So you think
if you model,
that'll get Justin
to ask you out?
- Whatever. I don't know.
(Chuckles)
- Your great-great-
grandmother, Ella,
used to clean Coco Chanel's
studio at night.
And she would pull the
sketches out of the trash can
and collect them.
Eventually,
Chanel caught on,
so she started leaving
her discarded sketches
out on purpose
in a nice,
neat pile for her.
And these were
Ella's favourites.
- I've heard that story,
a hundred times.
- Not this part.
In France, at that time, once
you were considered one thing,
it was almost impossible
to become something else.
Ella wanted to be a designer,
but she never had that choice.
So when I became
a designer,
it was in part to honour
my great-grandmother,
but mostly,
the choice was mine.
(Chuckling)
That photo stunt you pulled,
it showed your creativity...
(Clears throat)
...and a hell of
a lot of chutzpah.
And those are exceptional
qualities at any age,
impressively so at yours.
So for the show,
you can model.
But it has to be a choice
that you're making for you,
not for Justin,
or anybody else.
And...
Oh, but part of the deal,
you have to start eating again.
- Deal.
- OK.
(Chuckling)
(Knocking)
Let me get that.
Knocking on doors now,
instead of hiding behind them?
- Ms. Fyne.
Sorry to bother you.
May we come in?
- Thank you.
- So what time do you
expect him home?
- He should be
here any minute.
I-- I'm sorry.
Why are you here?
- The female "vic"
from that container,
name's Riyana Mingell.
Any idea why we found
your husband's DNA
under her finger nails?
- Hey!
(Siren)
- And how did you get
my clients' DNA
without their knowledge
or co-operation?
- They sipped water
and left their glasses.
It's discarded
genetic material.
With reasonable doubt,
we can do whatever.
- Surreptitious
sampling violates
their constitutional
right to privacy.
- When people don't clean up
after themselves, we do.
I just happened to take
a closer look at the garbage.
- I can explain this.
- No, Adam!
- I can explain.
I tripped.
I fell backward onto a textile
tool and it punctured me.
Right here.
She helped clean me up.
That's probably why my DNA
was under her finger nails.
That's it.
- Yeah? Prove it.
(Scoffs)
- No. Look, he doesn't have
to show you anything, OK?
- I never took
home-ec in school,
but you obviously did.
I just don't get how
you'd sew your own label
into the same fabric
you used to kill her.
- OK, you're out
of line, Fincher.
- She worked for us.
That's it.
I had no reason
to kill her.
And whoever did obviously did
it shortly after she helped me.
That's all.
- Are you prepared
to press charges?
- There are
witnesses to this?
- About 35 very
hard-working women
at our dye factory in Marrakesh,
near Riyana's village.
- You gonna collect DNA
from their garbage as well?
- Either you're
extremely clumsy
or one hell of a liar.
You can go,
but not too far.
- Listen, if they
call you again,
you don't talk to them, OK?
You call me first.
(Sighing)
(Car alarm in distance)
- Thank you. Thank you
for your support in there.
Thank you
for believing me.
- I'm just not sure what
I believe right now
with everything
that's going on.
We're trying so hard
to do things in
a new way, the right way,
and this goes against
everything we stand for.
- There's gotta be
some logical explanation.
- There's nothing logical about
this, Adam. Riyana's dead.
(Sighing)
You know the FBI came
to see me earlier today too,
asking questions about you
and the company and Ian,
and that's what
I wanted to talk to you about.
And then this happened.
Like, just--
What is going on, Adam?
- I don't know, Sophie,
but I will figure this out.
I promise you.
I need more time.
(Car honking in distance)
Trust me, I'm doing
everything I possibly can
to keep our family safe.
- Safe from who?
- Sophie... please.
Trust me.
(Cell phone ringing)
- Why aren't you answering?
- Listen,
It's not important.
Come on, let's...
Let's go.
(Cars honking in distance)
-
Endangering the very same
women they're trying to help,
as C.F.O. Adam Fyne remains
the prime suspect
in the death of one of their
company's fair-trade workers.
So with their inaugural
fashion show and flagship store
opening just 2 days away,
will Fyne Designs
be shutting their doors
before they even open at all?
(Sighing)
- Alexa, can you please try
to reach Mrs. Bashiri
in Fez for me, please?
- Of course.
(Drill whirring)
- The rice-paper
price tickets arrived.
- Is Adam here?
- He stepped out
for a few minutes.
Said he'd be right back.
- Thanks.
(Man talking, indistinct)
- Excuse me.
- Sophie, I have
Mrs. Bashiri on line one.
- Thank you.
(Talking, indistinct)
- Mrs. Bashiri,
it's Sophie Fyne.
Please extend our
condolences to Riyana's family
and let us know if there's
anything that we can do.
No, I just wish that Ian had
mentioned that she was missing
when he was there to talk
to you about the dye lots.
(Hammering)
I'm sorry?
He wasn't there?
I'm sorry.
Uh, I-- I have to go.
(Line ringing)
(Cell phone ringing)
(Line ringing
and cell phone ringing)
- Hey!
It's missing.
Our container is missing.
There was a document error.
It was rerouted and
now we cannot locate it.
- Ian never went back to Fez.
Why did you tell me he did?
- I told you he'd try.
Turns out he didn't have time,
so he sent in his approval
based on Mrs. Bashiri's opinion.
Simple as that.
- Why isn't
he here now?
- He's on his way back.
- Is he walking back?
- Sophie, come on.
- Adam, Why do you
have Ian's cell phone?
- You all right?
- You OK?
You all right?
- Yeah.
- (Man): The guy's
working on it.
- OK. All right.
- What happened?
(Many men shouting)
- I'm gonna check
the main panel.
- Wow. You're going to
the hospital, all right?
Come on.
You're coming too.
- Adam--
- Call 911.
- Check to make sure
no one else is hurt.
(Approaching siren)
- (Police officer): All right,
behind the yellow line, please.
- Thank you.
- (Officer):
Just stay back.
- What are we gonna do?
- What we're not gonna
do is panic, all right?
The press needs to know that
everything is on schedule.
We're opening
as planned.
- OK.
(Sighing)
- He seems OK.
- Excuse me.
- Spencer!
(Tires squealing)
(Inaudible)
(Clattering)
(Sighing)
Oh, Jerry.
- Mrs. Fyne.
You shouldn't be in here.
It's dangerous.
- So they think
the explosion was caused
by an electrical problem
with the old wiring?
- I've been a licensed
electrician for over 26 years,
and I can tell you
there's nothing wrong
with the wiring
in this building.
- Accidents can
happen, right?
- This was not
an accident.
- Jerry, I'm so sorry
about your guys,
but you know
our situation.
Is there any way that
you can still get
the store done
in time for
the opening?
- Well, my team was lightened
by 2... 2 of my best.
Listen, the way
that things are going
in this city
at the moment,
I could get 2 more men.
In fact, I could get you
10 more men.
You know, they'd be
hard-working and eager.
- Great.
- But I won't.
- What?
- I like you, Mrs. Fyne,
but, uh, none of us
have been paid in weeks.
So we won't be hammering
anymore nails here,
or hanging anymore sheetrock
till we see some money.
(Cell phone ringing)
(Sighing)
(Ringing)
- Hello.
-Ms. Fyne? This is Mrs. Lawson
from Liberty Mutual.
We can't seem
to reach your husband
and there seems to be
a bit of a problem.
- I-- I don't understand.
- Company credit line
is fully drawn,
as well as the personal
lines of credit
in your name and Mr. Fyne's.
- That can't be. The company
line, I understand.
We've had a lot
of expenses.
You have more credit cards
than just the 2
with this institution.
These are difficult
times for everyone.
Your situation isn't
different from other people--
- Could you check
our retirement funds?
- I have.
There's nothing there.
- How is that possible?
I see that all
processed transactions
included the
3 required signatures:
yours, your husband's
and Mr. Jameson's.
May I see some of
these documents, please?
- I never signed that. I--
Or that.
- But this is your signature?
- Yeah.
And your loft.
You are aware that the bank
has put a lien on it?
A mortgage default,
past 4 months.
Strange. Oh, it seems an
extremely large deposit
was made into one
of your accounts
and then almost
immediately withdrawn.
- How large?
- $2 million.
- What?
- The transaction
happened too quickly
to have been red-flagged.
But an amount this substantial
does warrant an investigation,
especially if it's
no longer there.
(Sighing)
(Keys turning in door)
- Where is it, Adam?
Where's the damn money?
(Sighing)
- Ian took it.
He took the whole thing.
- What?
- That's why
he disappeared.
He did the bank
transactions online
and he forged the originals,
couriered them back and forth.
And then he disappeared.
I backtracked, went back to
his hotel room, looking for him.
All I found
was his cell phone.
That was it.
I've had it ever since.
- Doesn't make any sense.
Why would Ian do that?
- I don't know.
- It's Cassadrian,
isn't it?
Armand Cassadrian, the man who
helped Spencer in the park.
The driver that tried
to run her over,
he had something to do
with the blast in the store.
He was with Cassadrian
right after.
Is this connected
to Riyana's death?
Is this-- Is Ian
involved in this?
- I don't know, Sophie.
I don't know.
(Sighing)
- And the $2 million?
- The $2 million, it was
deposited and withdrawn
in a blink.
I don't know
where it came from.
where it went.
(Sighing)
- They're investigating.
- I know. Lawson called me
after she talked to you.
- You should have told me.
You should have told me.
(Sighing)
- Come on. Give me some
good news, Phil. Please.
-
They got it. Eye-witness
testimony backing your story.
Investigation's
being transferred
to the local authorities.
It's probably
a domestic situation:
husband mad at
his wife for working
or mad at the company
for allowing women
to be independent, what--
Anyway, everyone
saw her help  you
and no one
saw her get killed.
- Great. Thanks Phil.
(Beep)
- I know that's supposed to be
comforting information,
but it's not.
- Sophie, we cannot save
the entire world
with one sewing job.
(Sighing)
You know, maybe we should
just cancel the show,
you know,
delay the opening.
- Hey, we have done
nothing wrong, all right?
We've worked too hard and
come too far to just give up.
The timing is crucial to
the launch of the ad campaign.
Listen,
Ian took the money.
You know what?
It's replaceable.
Opportunities like this aren't.
We got one chance
to make a first impression
on the fashion world
and make it an unforgettable.
- With what, huh?
No merchandise.
Our store is a wreck.
We don't have any money
to pay Jerry to fix it--
- Hey.
(Sighing)
OK, I'll rearrange
for the second shipment
to arrive by plane.
With any luck, maybe it'll
arrive today. Right?
And the broker might be able
to expedite clearance,
get it to the warehouse
by this afternoon.
And then I could
go to the bank
and I can plead for some
emergency bridge financing.
And...
(Sighing)
- We're gonna make this work
and we're gonna be OK.
Don't shut me
out again.
Right?
- OK.
- Mom, have you
seen my bag?
- It's by to the couch
where you--
- Oh, where I left it.
Are you OK?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine.
- You're a great designer.
And for the most part,
you're a pretty decent mom,
but you're not much
of a liar.
- And that's a bad thing?
- Is everything all right
with you and Dad?
- Oh, you heard us
arguing last night.
- No.
Kind of.
Yeah.
- We're fine.
- Oh, I gotta go.
- Bye.
- Eating!
Bye, Mom.
(Birds chirping)
- Drea.
Hey, it's me.
Yeah, I need a favour.
- $200,000.
Going once...
going twice...
(Gavel hitting podium)
And lot number 51
is sold for $200,000.
Next on the block
is a unique collection
of original fashion
sketches by Coco Chanel.
Dating 1925 to 1932.
Opening bid:
$150,000.
We have an offer
of $150,000.
Do we have an offer
of $200,000?
We have an offer
of $200,000.
Do we have an offer
of $250,000?
We have an offer
of $250,000.
Do we have an offer
of $300,000?
- OK.
- We have an offer
of $300,000.
Do we have an offer
of $350,000?
We have an offer of $350,000.
Do we have an offer
of $400,000?
$350,000, going once,
going twice...
And the Chanel collection
of original sketches
is sold for $350,000.
(Sighing)
- You didn't have to
give up your book.
We could have
found another way.
Not in time, we couldn't.
I gotta go.
I'll talk you later.
- "Success is often achieved
"by those who don't know
that failure is inevitable."
Coco Chanel.
- Thank you.
- No, thank you.
(Sighing)
- I called Claudio
right after you called me.
- Who was bidding
against him?
- Rufus Winthrop. He's often
hired as a buyer's rep.
I asked him to come
to up Claudio's bid,
which I could
so lose my job over.
- Thank you.
Oh, I can't believe
I sold it, Dre, and to him.
- Please. Regardless of
how much you dislike the man
and everything
he represents,
the book is gonna
be well taken care of.
He's probably gonna build
a shrine around it.
And you got more than you hoped
for and you need it. All right?
- Yeah.
- Listen, I gotta go if
I'm gonna catch my flight.
- Does that mean you won't
be back for the opening?
- I fly back that same night.
Oh, I am just so sorry
I'm not gonna be there
to tell you how great it was
and how proud I am of you.
- Thank you for
all your help.
Hmm!
Thanks.
(Sighing)
(Siren)
- (Man): Johnny, I need
a rivet here.
(Men talking, indistinct)
(Inaudible)
- Did you see it?
-
I see it. I'd have to be
blind to miss it.
(Adam laughing)
It's incredible, Soph.
Hey, they've zeroed in
on the shipment.
I'll keep you posted.
- Oh! That's great.
Thanks.
- I'll take 5.
(Men talking, indistinct)
-
So with all
this attention,
they can now show
their audience
what their innovative
company stands for.
Though, hard not to question
if their dead fair-trade worker
will overshadow any message
they might want you to hear.
- You know what?
Call it good press or bad,
the phone's ringing
off the hook.
Almost as many complaints
as congratulations,
but everyone wants tickets
to tomorrow's opening.
- Yeah, if there
is an opening.
- Did you ever have a chance
to pick up the gold thread?
- No, no. I got there too late.
They were closed for vacation.
- I'm sure we had
some of that at some point.
- You're right, we did.
It must still be at
the warehouse, right?
- That's great. I'll go
look for it right now.
- I'll go. I think I remember
where it might be.
I need some air anyway.
(Telephone ringing)
- Fyne Designs.
Yeah, of course.
Just one second.
(Cell phone ringing)
- Hey, Sophie. Guess what?
It's in.
The shipment as arrived.
Alexa tells me
you're down at warehouse?
Well, the truck is waiting
at the loading dock.
- Oh, that is great news, Adam.
-
Yes, it is.
I'll be right down.
- I'm here. Just send some
staff to meet me.
We'll get it unloaded.
Jerry could use
your help  at the store.
-
OK. Sure.
I'll see you soon.
Oh!
Hey, we might just
pull this off, right?
- Yeah, we actually might.
-Bye.
- See ya.
- Yes! All right.
(Scoffs)
You gotta be kidding me.
(Chuckles)
(Women talking, indistinct)
(Honking)
(Woman talking, indistinct)
- Good.
- That's it.
She changed the order.
- Dress rehearsal in 6 hours!
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- Uh, a little tired.
- Mm-hmm?
- Nervous.
(Chuckling)
- And you are one
exceptional designer.
(Both chuckling)
Listen, I'm gonna head
back to the store,
help Jerry finish
setting up, OK?
- OK.
- We're almost there.
- Here we go.
- Yeah, here we go.
(Honking)
(All chattering)
(Women chattering)
- You OK?
Come over this way.
All right!
Take care of her.
- I will.
- Looking great, kiddo.
- (Spencer): Thanks.
(Giggles)
Mom... thanks.
- You're gonna be great.
(♪ Trip hop )
- Hey! Thank you
for coming out.
See you.
Thanks. Hey!
(Talking, indistinct)
- (Man): It's all right.
- (Woman): OK.
(♪ Pop )
(Cameras clicking)
- (Woman on stereo):
♪♪ You love me, baby
♪ You make me hot, baby
♪ I'll teach you, honey
♪ I can't get
enough of you... ♪
- You know,
for a patient man, my...
my reserves are getting
dangerously low.
- Yeah.
- You won't want
to see me on empty.
- Listen, I just need to get
everything ready for tonight.
I'll have-- I'll have everything
all set-up for tomorrow, OK?
(Chuckling)
- Not tomorrow.
Now.
(Chuckles)
- I can't now.
- When I don't get
what I want,
when I'm supposed
to get it,
I just step in
and I take it.
And I will.
(Sighing)
♪ You love me, baby
♪ You make me hot, baby
♪ I'll teach you, honey
♪ I can't get
enough of you ♪
♪ La la la
♪ La la la la la
♪ La la la la la ♪
(Siren in distance)
- No.
(Sighing)
(Grunting)
(♪ Big beat )
♪  ♪
(Applause)
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Excuse me.
Excuse me.
How many of those
containers did you open?
- What?
- At the warehouse. How many?
- All of them.
(Cheering)
♪  ♪
Where's Spencer?
Have you seen Spencer?
- I haven't seen her.
(Cheering and applause)
- Where is Spencer?
- She was just out there.
I don't know where she is.
You were supposed
to keep an eye on her.
-The much-anticipated
inaugural fashion show
and flagship store opening
from designer Sophie Fyne,
was not so fine
as the events were marred
by the possible abduction
of her teenaged daughter,
who modelled
in tonight's show.
Before the store could be
locked down for investigation,
cashes were already
opened for business
with purchases made
by some very excite--
- Have a seat.
- There still
has been no contact
with any demands
for your daughter.
Why don't we backtrack?
Body in a shipping container,
possible hit and run,
the accident at the store.
I don't think
we can call this
a string of
bad luck anymore.
- Look there has to be
a common thread here
that links these events
to each other and to someone.
- Mr. Fyne, if there's
any pertinent information
we might need to know
to help us find your daughter,
now would be
a very good time to tell us.
- No. There's, uh,
there's nothing I can think of.
- The 3rd partner in
your company, Mr. Ian Jameson.
Any idea how we might
be able to reach him?
- Well, we actually haven't
heard from him in over a week.
- Should we change that
to ex-business partner?
Or how about ex-business
partner with a score to settle?
- He's still our partner.
- Any other rogue partners
we should know about?
I can only imagine
how you must feel like
to have a member of your family
put in this... situation.
(Sighing)
- Look, if she was taken by
someone, it was for a reason.
And that reason is worth more
to them than your daughter.
We'll be back shortly
to set up.
- Great.
(Door closing)
- The truth, Adam.
Please.
- Ian set up a drug deal
with some very powerful
and dangerous people.
- Cassadrian.
- Yeah.
- What kind of drug deal?
- A $20 million one.
The $2 million
in our bank account,
it was an initial payment.
Guess Ian must've
withdrawn it right away.
The drugs were supposed
to arrive in a shipping crate.
The one that you found
in the warehouse.
- There was nothing in that
crate except the goods
for the show and the store.
- I know, but they
don't know that.
And now they think
that I have the drugs.
I don't have 'em.
I swear to you, Sophie.
I don't have the drugs.
- Oh, that's why
they took Spencer.
- Yeah.
(Sighing)
Sophie, what
we're doing here,
it's a very expensive endeavour.
All the travel expenses and
the development work and...
And these places,
they're so corrupt.
Our finances,
they were in ruin.
So Ian, he had an idea
that we could make these
sharp investments
and we could time the market
make the money back.
I trusted him.
It didn't work out.
The losses started
spiralling out of control,
And then our debt was
just mounting and mounting.
And Ian was devastated.
He had the deal with
Cassadrian all worked out
before I knew
anything about it.
I guess he thought that was,
like, his one chance
to replace all
the money he'd lost.
I don't know.
But he got greedy
and he demanded more money.
They were furious...
and they killed him.
- How could you have
let it to this point?
How could you
let it get this far?
- 'Cause Cassadrian said that
if I didn't carry on with the
deal as originally planned,
it wouldn't be me
that he'd hurt next.
- We are partners
in business and in life.
If you'd just come
to me in the beginning,
this would've never gotten
this out of control,
would never
have gotten this far.
And Spencer would never be--
(Cell phone ringing)
That's it?
Where's my daughter?
- Sophie.
- Where is my daughter?
- Sophie!
(Sighing)
(Chuckles)
(Cell phone ringing)
- Hello.
- (Cassadrian):
Abandoned rail yard
at the corner of
Tonnelle Avenue and 91st
in Jersey Hangar 2C.
I'll be waiting.
Come alone or
fashion claims another victim.
We'll be watching.
(Cell phone beeps)
(Talking, indistinct)
- (Marks):
First, set a trap...
- (Adam): OK.
- They wanna meet.
- Where?
- At our warehouse.
- You shouldn't
be doing this.
- We tried to convince her
that we could send an agent.
- She's my child.
I will take care of it.
- Ms. Fyne,
this is for you.
- It's a GPS, in case
there's a problem.
We'll be
right behind you.
(Door opening)
- OK.
You sure
about this?
- No. If she was
your daughter?
- You better be
damn careful.
- You too.
And thank you.
- OK.
- She's leaving
the building.
(Sighing)
- Hello?
Hello!
- Mrs. Fyne.
It is so nice
to finally meet you.
- I came alone,
like you said.
Now where's my daughter?
- Oh, right.
Your daughter. Oh.
Lovely, little girl you have.
- I did what you wanted.
Let me see Spencer.
- No, if you had done
what I wanted,
all this wouldn't
have been necessary.
Please, just let me
see my daughter.
And I will get you
anything you want.
- Really? Well, as soon
as I get my shipment,
you get your little girl.
- What? I don't what you're
talking about. What shipment?
I don't understand.
- She doesn't
know anything.
- Adam, what are you
doing here?
- Uh, I called him.
I thought it was about time
that we cleared the air.
- She shouldn't be here.
It's not about her.
- No, Adam, you're the one
who got her involved,
because you're the one
who backed out of
our little deal, huh?
- What? What is he talking
about? What deal?
- Just let her leave.
We'll work this out.
- No, I'm not going
anywhere without Spencer.
- Sophie, Please!
- I don't know what
Ian has gotten us
into here,
but I'm not just gonna
stand back
and do nothing.
- Well, tell her.
'Cause if you don't, I will.
- It wasn't Ian.
I lost all our money.
And the deal
with Cassadrian...
Well, it wasn't Ian.
It was me.
I'm sorry.
(Scoffs)
It was never suppose to
go this far. I'm sorry.
- How could you?
- I was desperate.
All right?
I heard there was fast money
to be made with Cassadrian
I approached him.
He offered me a deal.
I took it.
It's that simple.
- I can't believe this.
What was the deal, Adam?
- Ah, it doesn't matter now.
- What was it?
(Sighing)
- Heroin,
Mrs. Fyne.
Heroin.
- Adam, why?
- Everything is always
so easy for you, isn't it?
You're so talented.
And Ian, whoa!
Well, Ian, you know,
he's resourceful,
he's innovative.
He's a real
whiz kid, isn't he?
And there's me.
I'm the money guy.
But guess what?
I failed.
I'm a failure.
- OK, this is all
very touching.
Now let's just get to the part
where I get what I want.
- I wanna see Spencer.
- You know, enough.
I am through playing around.
- You don't understand.
I need to see Spencer.
Then I'll show you.
- Bring her in.
(Whimpers)
- Mom!
- Spencer!
- Dad!
(Spencer crying)
- You know what I want.
I'm not gonna ask again.
- (Adam): OK.
OK.
Don't hurt her.
- Daddy, I'm scared.
- It's gonna be OK.
Go see your mother.
Go.
(Whimpering)
(Sighing)
- Are you all right?
Oh my god!
- There it is.
I'll take you to the rest.
Just let them go.
(Chuckling)
- You son of a--
(Cassadrian chuckling)
It's been here
the whole time.
(Crying)
You know, we had
a perfect deal...
arranged between 2 mutually
respectful business men.
But you got a
little greedy, huh?
Causing things
to get a little...
messy.
You know that woman
in the crate?
Well...
Tell her, Adam.
I strangled her.
- And why?
- Because she saw me
shoot Ian.
(Exhales)
He was gonna stop me and...
it was too late.
- That's enough! That's enough.
I'm calling her right now.
- Ian, please.
Please, don't make me do this.
- Let's face it, Adam.
It's over.
- No.
(Inhales)
(Dog barking)
Aw!
(Goat bleating)
(Bucket clattering)
(Dogs clattering)
- Well, and then
we shipped her to you.
That was just to remind you
who you were dealing with.
But you kept putting everyone
around you at risk,
people you supposedly
care about.
Then that
$2 million deposit,
that was just to let you know
that we can give,
then so quickly
taketh away.
Because when you play
double or nothing,
odds are you will
end up with...
(Sighing)
...nothing.
- Are you done?
- Now, let's go to the store.
We've got some
shopping to do.
Oh!
I almost forgot.
(Sighing)
Can't leave any loose
threads now, can we?
- No!
(Women screaming)
- Freeze! Don't move!
Federal agents!
No, no, no.
Stop, stop!
- I got no gun.
- FBI! Drop your weapon now!
- Clear out!
Move out!
(Pipe clattering)
- It's OK.
(Crying)
- Are you both OK?
- It depends
what you mean by OK.
- Ian suspected Adam
and contacted us
a couple days
before he was killed.
We've been following
Adam ever since,
but we needed him
to lead us to the dealers.
(Helicopter overhead)
- Let's go.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah, we're on it.
(Woman on CB, indistinct)
(Car doors closing)
- (Man): Yes, sir.
(Man talking, indistinct)
(Car engine starting)
Closed captions:
Vision Globale