Oh, my God!
Over here, over here!
There's somebody in the water.
Serious head trauma.
Get me the CAT-scan results.
Has her breathing stabilized?
Check her vitals.
Checking pulse.
We may need some more
sutures on that laceration.
Lots of blood loss here.
Get me the CAT-scan results.
Pupils are dilated.
Pupils are reacting, Marilyn,
get me the blood pressure.
Marilyn, get me
the CAT-scan results.
Lots of blood loss here.
Pupils are dilated.
What happened to her?
Serious head trauma.
Marilyn, get me
the blood pressure.
Fishermen pulled her
out of the ocean.
Boating accident?
Any change in her condition?
Umm...
Stabilized, but no change.
Anyone come to ID her yet?
Not yet.
We still don't know who she is.
Yeah, I'm looking for my fiancée.
Her name is Brooke Harris.
I'm Dr. Kaplan, can I help you?
Yes.
He's looking for his fiancée.
Her name was Brooke Harris.
She was on a boat
late last night,
and I think she might
have fallen overboard.
And who are you?
My name is Michael Coleman,
I'm her fiancé.
Now, I've been to
three hospitals already
and your receptionist said that
you had a Jane Doe here.
Is that her?
Yes.
We were beginning to
think nobody would come,
there was no identification,
nothing on the news.
Where is she?
Can I see her?
Of course.
Please, have a seat.
Get me her file.
Yes, Doctor.
Is she okay?
I mean, tell me she's all right.
Mr. Coleman, I know
it's been a long night.
Doctor, please, just tell
me she's all right.
Your fiancée has suffered
from some severe trauma.
We need to run a couple more
tests before you can see her.
Okay.
I promise, as soon
as I run those tests,
I'll take you to her, okay?
I'll be right back.
Fluids are low, increase the drip.
Blood pressure has stabilized.
Lacerations around the scalp.
Her legs seem to look good.
Should heal nicely with
minimal scarring, if any.
Pupils are reactive.
Marilyn, did you get
the CAT-scan results yet?
Yeah.
The swelling has
gone down considerably.
I don't think we're looking
at any permanent damage.
Do you see these?
You can tell by
the purplish colors
that these are more recent,
the ones from last night.
The others, the greenish ones...
What do you see?
These bruises were sustained
before the boating accident?
File a report with the police
just to be on the safe side.
Mr. Coleman.
Doctor, how is she?
Can I see her now?
Oh.
That's everything she had
on her when she was found.
That's funny, I don't
remember seeing that before.
Wouldn't leave
the house without it.
Brooke, baby, can you hear me?
It's me, it's Michael.
I'm here now, baby,
everything's gonna be okay.
I'm gonna take you home.
I need a moment with you.
Your fiancée suffered a
heavy blunt-force trauma
to the head in the accident.
She's in a coma.
What?
She has a severe concussion.
Her brain is swollen,
putting pressure on the spine.
The good news is that the
inflammation is going down,
so I don't perceive...
Umm...
Is there anything
that can be done?
The only thing we can do
right now is wait.
There's no telling
how long it may last.
It could be a day, a week.
There's really no guarantees.
She's in the best care here.
We'll be watching
her round the clock.
But there's something else.
We found bruises on her
that appeared to have
occurred before the accident.
From what?
I was hoping maybe
you could tell me.
Brooke's a pretty athletic girl.
She... she plays
tennis, goes hiking.
I suppose it could be from
any one of those.
You should be aware that
it's hospital policy
to report any
suspicious injuries.
What?
What are you saying?
Not that I'm accusing
anyone of anything.
What, no, you think
that I hit her?
That I abuse her?
No.
I'm not saying that at all.
I'm just saying I have
to fill out the report.
I understand.
Look, I need you to be strong
for her right now, okay?
She's awake!
Somebody, she's awake!
She's in shock, she doesn't
know where she is.
Can you hear me?
Can you understand?
Give me a sign
that you can hear me.
You're at County Hospital.
You were brought here
for treatment.
I'm Dr. Kaplan.
Michael's here.
He's been by your side
the entire time.
I'm right here, sweetheart.
Do you know
what happened to you?
Everything will be fine.
You're safe here.
Okay, shh...
Tell me if you can
understand, okay?
You had a serious accident.
You were in a coma
for almost two days.
You're lucky to be alive.
Do you remember your name?
Brooke.
That's good.
Do you remember the accident?
Anything about how you got here?
Everything's gonna be fine.
You rest now.
We'll continue later.
What's going on?
Why is she like this?
I know this is
very difficult for you.
The concussion has caused
swelling of the lobes,
which puts
pressure on the spine.
The brain is bruised.
The injuries she sustained
caused damage to
the area
responsible for her memory.
Like amnesia?
What, is it permanent?
Most cases, the memory
does come back,
it just takes some time.
How much time?
It varies on the patient.
It depends on
the extent of the damage.
What can be done?
Just be patient with her.
It's gonna take
some getting used to,
but she will get better.
Just be there for her.
If she's struggling, help her.
People, places.
She's gonna rely on you to
help cope with her memory.
Okay, when can I take her home?
A couple of days.
I need to run a few
more tests first.
Okay.
Now she needs her rest.
Okay, it's important she
isn't subjected to
anything too stressful...
physically, emotionally.
She's had enough
excitement for today.
Okay, I understand.
Please don't worry if
you can't remember anything.
Bits and pieces will come back
and then, I promise,
everything will fall into
place eventually.
I was so worried when
I found you here like this.
I mean, if something
happened to you...
...I really
don't know what I'd do.
You don't remember me
at all, do you?
I know how hard this is for you.
I'm sorry.
No.
Don't you be.
The most important thing is
that you're all right.
And I promise you,
I'm gonna help you
and we're gonna get
through this, okay?
They're gonna let us get
out of here in a couple days,
and...
I wanna take you to
our vacation house.
It's... it's quiet
and it's peaceful,
no one to bother us.
You can rest there.
And then when you're
feeling better,
we'll go to our
place in the city.
Okay?
How's that sound?
Sounds nice.
Sedatives.
I want you to rest.
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Thank you for everything,
Doctor.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
It's so beautiful.
How could I forget this view?
You're right about that.
It is beautiful.
And that's a great start.
I'm gonna get a coffee,
you want anything?
I'll be right back.
Honey!
I, um, was just looking for you
because I, uh, missed you.
Well, we're gonna be there soon.
We should probably
get going, okay?
Let's go.
...on the lower deck.
So is it just us?
Yeah.
So no family, I don't have
anybody else?
Uh...
Well, there's Courtney,
your sister.
She lives down in Kent.
Oh, well, maybe we
should call her.
She might be worried.
No, I called her when you
were in the hospital.
What did she say?
You two haven't
spoken in a while.
Really?
Don't worry.
We've got each other.
Listen, before we head home,
we should probably pick a few
things up at the market.
What is it, what's wrong?
I don't know if this is
such a good idea.
Maybe I should
go sit in the car.
If it's about the little girl,
she's just being a kid.
Okay?
Okay.
I... I really, I really don't
feel comfortable in here.
Sweetheart, okay, we'll just
grab a couple things,
we'll be off in a second, okay?
Okay, can you make it fast?
You got it.
Now, I'm just
gonna go grab something.
Are you okay to stand here
while I do that?
I'll be back before you miss me.
Hurry.
Okay.
You're gonna be okay, I promise.
Oh, my God!
There you are!
You have no idea
how worried I've been about you.
I'm sorry, do I...
I don't know.
You don't...
It's me, Melissa.
Mel?
Melissa.
I heard about what
happened to you.
Are... are you okay?
I'm sorry, I don't remember you.
Oh, sweetheart.
Where did you go?
I was looking for you.
Hi, Melissa.
What happened to her?
We're not sure, exactly.
She went out on the boat
and somehow fell overboard.
I always warn
her about the boat.
Thank goodness you're alive.
It's okay, honey,
this is Melissa.
You guys are best friends.
You really don't
remember me, do you?
I'm sorry, I'm sure
it'll come back to me.
Can we go now?
Yeah.
Are you guys gonna be
in town for a while?
Yeah, we're just gonna go
up to the cabin and hang out
until things get back to normal.
Is there anything I can do?
No, we just need some
healing time.
Okay.
Take care of yourself, okay?
Anything familiar?
Mmm, I don't know, sort of.
It's like I've
seen it all before,
but I don't know where or when.
That's a pretty good sign.
Sounds like there's a few things
rattling around in
there trying to get out.
I was thinking it might be
a good idea for you to
spend some time with Melissa,
maybe bring back some memories.
Welcome home.
This is our vacation house?
You decorated it.
How do we afford this place?
Oh, it was practically a steal.
A lot of blood, sweat and tears
went into this place, but...
yeah, I do all right.
Do I work?
Yeah, tech support.
You work from home, helping
your clients by remote.
I hope that memory comes back.
I'm just gonna grab
the groceries and the bag
out of the car.
Yeah, I'd like to roam around
a little bit by myself.
That's a good idea.
Holler if you need
anything, okay?
Hi.
I was thinking,
it's a beautiful day outside.
Might be a good idea
to go for a walk.
How you doing?
I feel great.
I kinda thought this
would make you feel better.
It's beautiful, I wanna
take in every little detail.
Really?
I was kinda hoping we
could pick up the pace
for the last mile.
Yeah, go ahead.
Really?
No problem,
I'll meet you at home.
Okay, well, just...
You follow the path until it
gets you to the base, okay?
You sure?
Yeah, go ahead.
Michael?
Michael!
Hello?
Are you okay?
I heard shouting.
I...
I got lost.
I... didn't know where I was.
Honey!
I told you to follow the trail.
It would have taken you
straight back to the base.
Oh, sweetheart, sweetheart,
I'm so sorry.
I never should have left you.
Can we go home now?
Of course.
Need any help?
Drink and chop.
Could you wash these for me?
Thank you.
That was delicious.
I'm glad to see your
taste buds haven't changed.
You know, I...
made that the very
first time I cooked for you.
That is your favorite.
Well, you certainly
are a good cook.
And you said that the first
time I cooked for you, too.
Really, tell me about it.
Oh, God.
Um...
Well, it was Valentine's Day
and we were supposed to
go out for dinner,
but some jackass
forgot to make reservations.
Ouch!
Yeah, well, I can't be expected
to remember everything.
I had candy and I
had the flowers, so...
What were they?
Orchids.
You love orchids.
And I also got you
a little bear.
Oh, you got me a bear?
So I just went to
the pantry and got out
what I had and...
there it was.
Very nice.
What's wrong?
I just need a little time.
Take all the time you need.
Brooke?
Brooke, you okay?
Look out, look out,
look out, look out!
I'm sorry.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
I was trying to
make you breakfast.
Pancakes?
That's all I could remember.
Sweetheart, it's all right,
it's all right.
Was there somebody at the door?
I didn't get there in time.
I'm so sorry.
Honey, honey, it's okay.
Okay, how about I take you
out for breakfast, okay?
Okay.
Okay, why don't you get dressed
and I'll be right up.
I was looking at
the pictures in the hallway.
Oh.
Yeah, you were rearranging
them before the accident.
I don't know where you
put them, so I just left it.
I'm sorry, I just feel alone.
I understand.
I'm sorry about Courtney.
Why aren't we talking?
I don't really know.
You two just
haven't gotten along
since your parents died.
I was hoping that maybe when
things calmed down a bit,
you could invite
her up to the house.
Do you think she'd come?
I don't know, but we can try.
I think that car
is following us.
What?
The car behind us, they were
following us last night.
Sweetheart, there's
nobody following us.
Who is it?
Maybe if I just
make a turn up here.
I'm Detective Wagner.
This is Detective Hanson.
We're with the PD.
Okay, how can I help you?
Yeah, can we see some
identification?
Sure.
Why didn't you pull over?
Well, that's 'cause I didn't
know you guys
were police officers.
Sure.
Step out of the car.
It's okay.
That way.
Listen, my fiancée
just had an accident.
We're a little on edge here.
I see a strange car
following us,
and I don't know what to think.
Uh-huh.
You mind telling me
what this is all about?
Where were you the night
your fiancée
disappeared, Mr. Coleman?
Home.
And I was waiting
for her to come home.
Did you speak with
anybody during that time?
Anybody that can corroborate
that you were there?
No, I didn't.
Are you implying that I had
something to do with that?
Any phone calls?
No, I didn't speak with anybody.
You have any idea why she would
have been on that boat?
Well, we use it a lot.
She likes to go out on it
sometimes and clear her head.
It's peaceful.
In the middle of the night?
Well, maybe the storm
came up after she left.
I really don't know.
Listen, you're
welcome to speak with her,
but I'm not sure how much
she's gonna be able to tell you...
We heard.
We already spoke with
Dr. Kaplan at County.
Okay, well, then you guys
know as much as everyone.
One more thing,
Mr. Coleman.
Dr. Kaplan mentioned
something about some bruises.
Okay, I will tell you
exactly what I told her.
Tennis.
Brooke is outdoors a lot.
Have you ever hit your
fiancée, Mr. Coleman?
No, I haven't.
And I wouldn't do
anything to hurt her.
Well, please call
us if you have any...
useful information,
anything at all.
I got it.
Number's on the card.
All right, thank you.
What did they want?
They were just following up
on the accident.
Procedure.
It's nothing.
What were we sitting here for?
Hello, Brooke.
I hear we had a little accident.
Do you remember me at all?
You look familiar.
Well, that's a good start.
I'm Dr. Richard Alvarez.
I'm an old friend of Michael's.
The best thing about amnesia
is you're always
meeting new friends.
Well, I'm glad you haven't
lost your sense of humor.
Now, I don't want
you to feel embarrassed
or ashamed of your condition.
We're all here to
get you through this.
Get you back to where
you belong.
Now, Michael tells me you've
been experiencing nightmares.
Want to tell me about those?
There are little
flashes of memories.
They don't make much sense.
Just kind of random, really.
Oh, believe me,
they're anything but.
What I think is going on here
is your brain is trying to
piece together a puzzle
to help you understand
what happened that night.
And that's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna help you take
details out of these flashes,
help you put the pieces together
so you can get back to normal
and you two can get on
with your lives.
Thank you.
So, Brooke, can you tell me
about these flashes?
I'm running.
Scared, I...
Being chased by somebody.
Who?
I don't know.
Somebody... I can't
really see who it is.
There's nobody...
there to help me.
Whenever I get to a safe place,
he's there and he stops me.
It's like he's...
...always there,
waiting for me.
He hits me and...
...there's a girl.
She's running
through the woods and...
she's scared and, uh...
she's...
she's hiding from somebody.
I... I don't know.
I don't know.
I know this is hard for you.
The mind works in strange ways.
Some memories rise to
the surface
while others just dissipate.
These childhood memories, it's...
it's your subconscious trying
to tell you something.
Next time you
have one of these visions,
try not to focus on what it is,
but try to
understand what it's about.
Look for small details.
What's in the background?
What people are wearing,
a hat, a handbag,
things like that.
The place you're in.
It's these small details
that are the key to
you remembering
who you are,
the people around you
and what happened that night.
Any one thing can
bring on a flood of memories.
That make any sense to you?
Thank you, Doctor.
Call me Richard.
Well, thank you, Richard.
Any time.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Maybe he's right.
Maybe I'm looking at things
in the wrong way.
Listen, I'm gonna have to
drop you off at home.
I'm late,
I've gotta meet a client.
Oh.
Someone's gotta
pay the mortgage.
What is it you do again?
Marketing.
And if I can get this bid,
we're gonna be set for a while.
Okay.
You know, maybe I should
go back to work, too.
That's not a bad idea.
If I could remember enough.
I really don't wanna leave you.
That's okay.
I'll... I'll visit Melissa.
I should have her number.
That's not a bad idea.
I won't be long.
I love you.
How's the recovery?
Taking it moment to moment.
So you don't remember anything?
Little things, like...
I see something and I know it's
supposed to mean something
to me, but it just doesn't.
Like my sister.
Michael says we don't get along,
but I have no idea why.
You're...
you're really lucky to
have someone like him.
Yeah, he's really great.
He, um...
But, you know, I don't
even remember how we met.
It's like living with
a complete stranger.
The video store.
What?
That's how you guys met,
the video store.
You guys were fighting
over the last copy of some DVD,
and he suggested that you
guys watch it together.
You're kidding.
No, no.
Love works in mysterious ways.
You okay?
Brooke?
Are you okay?
Come on, let's go.
Where are we going?
Brooke, what are you doing?
I'm sorry, excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Mind your own business.
Brooke!
Who was that guy?
I don't know.
He gives me the creeps.
Then let's just go.
Is that the boat?
Yeah, it is.
I heard they towed it
in this morning.
You're lucky it
didn't hit the banks.
What is it?
It's nothing.
I just hope you
won't go out alone again.
You know you can always call me.
What was I doing
here that night?
Clearing your head?
I don't think I was alone.
What are you talking about?
There was somebody here
with me that night.
Who?
Who else was here?
Who else was there?
I don't know.
Brooke!
Brooke, I can't help you
unless you tell me.
I just need to get
a hold of myself.
I can't work.
tta get a hold of myself.
I've gotta... calm down.
If just...
I gotta just relax.
Where would I have put them?
God, sweetheart!
I'm so sorry, I wasn't...
I wasn't thinking.
Oh, baby, oh,
I'm sorry I scared you.
It's okay.
How was your day with Melissa?
It was good, we had a nice chat.
That's good.
We took a walk in town.
We saw the boat.
Good.
Spark any memories?
Anything come back to you?
Not really.
I tried to do some work,
but I guess I'm not really
ready to go back yet.
Well, we'll work on that.
There was one thing.
While I walked past the store,
something about a bag.
A bag?
What kind of bag?
It was a suitcase.
Hmm, I wonder what that means.
Do you wanna talk to
Richard about it?
Remember what he said
about the small details?
It could be important.
I don't think Richard's
interested in my subconscious
telling me I need to go
on a shopping spree.
No, no, remember what
Dr. Alvarez said.
The answers are in the details.
You focus on an object, even
if it seems insignificant.
You start there and you
work your way backwards.
It's just a suitcase.
No, no, that must be your mind
trying to tell you something.
Come on, just tell
me about the suitcase.
I'd rather not do this now.
Brooke, this could be important.
Come on.
Tell me about the suitcase.
Close your eyes.
What color is it?
It's brown.
It has...
big... buckles.
They're large.
Gold.
What's inside?
Clothes.
It's dark, it's hard to see.
What else is inside?
I don't know.
It's...
I can't see...
Concentrate.
I don't remember anymore.
It's okay.
I thought we were having
a breakthrough there,
I just didn't
want to lose momentum.
Maybe later.
Okay.
I was thinking that maybe later
we could get a bottle of wine
and sit by the fire.
We could talk more about
this if you want to.
I don't really
wanna do that tonight.
It's been a long day.
I'm just gonna go upstairs
and curl up in bed.
I'm sorry, I just need
a little time.
Take all the time you need.
I had another
weird dream last night.
Really?
What was it about?
I don't know, but I'd really
like to talk to
Dr. Alvarez about it.
Um... yeah,
I'm sorry.
I forgot to tell you.
I spoke with Richard yesterday.
He's going out of town
for a few days.
Oh.
More work?
Yeah, I gotta go back into town.
This client is
really busting my hump.
Can I come with you?
I could really use
some fresh air.
Sure.
Well, something tells me
you haven't forgotten
how to use a credit card.
I'll be back to pick you up
in about an hour.
Okay.
Anything she remembers.
She could remember everything.
She remembered the bag.
Look, I'm gonna be out of
town for a few days.
Just be careful.
I'm doing everything I can.
Look, I need to show you
something.
Come out to the car.
No, it's late.
It's gonna take a second.
You hear something?
Hmm?
Come on.
What was it?
Nothing, I guess.
I gotta go anyway,
I got an appointment.
I'll talk to you later.
Detective Wagner.
Hi, it's Brooke Harris.
How can I help you,
Ms. Harris?
I think something's going on.
I was wondering
if I could see you?
Where are you?
I'm outside a store,
it's called Highland Books.
Okay.
Meet me down by the docks
in ten minutes.
Okay, thanks.
How's your head?
Well, the pain is gone,
but my memory is still
a little hazy.
So what's going on?
Why were you following us
yesterday?
Why do you wanna know?
Just tell me.
We're just trying to
solve the case.
Is my fiancé a suspect?
Michael is a person
of interest, but...
But what?
How much do you remember about
your relationship with him?
Not much.
Why?
Do you think he did it?
He doesn't have a solid alibi,
and it wouldn't be
the first time.
And there is something else.
We asked around about
your engagement,
and no one seems
to remember anything.
What the...
Our house, the ring.
Dr. Kaplan said
she didn't see a ring
in all your possessions.
That's crazy, I mean,
what about Dr. Alvarez?
What about... what about him?
Who?
He... Richard Alvarez,
my psychiatrist.
He knows about it.
We'll look into it, okay?
I know how hard it is.
Now, you mentioned
something was going on.
Did you see anything
or hear anything?
What's going on,
Ms. Harris?
It's nothing.
Ms. Harris.
I think that Michael
is keeping some things from me.
Some things?
Missing pictures,
stuff like that.
I need you to think back
before the accident.
Is there anything
you can think of?
Like what?
Abuse.
No, what are you talking about?
Okay, I'm gonna be honest
with you, Ms. Harris.
Unless you say otherwise,
this is probably gonna end up
being filed under "accident."
There are no
witnesses, you're not dead,
and nothing's been stolen,
as far as we know.
So the only person
who knows what happened
on that boat is you.
Michael.
Michael!
You forgot this.
Oh.
Melissa, thank you.
Sorry!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God,
Brooke, are you okay?
Get in the car,
I'll take you home.
You wanna talk about it?
Not really.
Look at you, you're shaking.
Okay, okay, I'I'sorry.
Brooke...
I know you don't remember
everything that happened
and that you're going through
a rough time right now,
but... we're best friends
and we tell each other
everything.
I just wanted to
get back to that.
Is there something you'd
like to tell me?
About what?
What's going on
with you and Michael?
Are you serious?
There's nothing going on
between Michael and I.
I saw you guys this afternoon.
Brooke, I swear!
There's nothing going...
You're my best friend!
Save it.
Brooke!
Brooke, what's going on?
You tell me what's going on.
What happened?
Oh, God.
Sweetheart, where have you been?
I've been worried
sick about you.
Are you having fun with her?
Her who?
What are you talking about?
Don't insult my intelligence!
I saw you and Melissa together.
You and my supposed best friend
that I don't even know.
It isn't like that.
Then what was it like?
Have dinner with me tonight.
Tonight, Le Bistro Provence.
Just have dinner with me tonight
and I will explain everything.
The Bistro Provence,
you love that place.
Just have dinner
with me tonight,
and I'll explain everything.
Oh, God.
Give me one reason to trust you.
I'll give you plenty of
reasons if you just say yes.
Please.
Oh, God, okay.
Brooke, sweetheart, we gotta go.
Coming!
Come on, honey, we're late.
I'm coming!
Thank you.
Tell me what's bothering you.
I talked to Detective Wagner.
Okay, what did she have to say?
She said that nobody
she interviewed
knew about our engagement
and that Dr. Kaplan didn't
find a ring in my possessions.
Do you have anything to
say about that?
Dr. Kaplan was right,
there wasn't a ring
in your possessions.
Okay.
There wasn't a ring there
because you weren't wearing one.
You see, we'd had some problems
and things weren't going all
that well, to be honest.
We had a fight
and you just took off.
A fight about what?
I've learned over the past
couple of days
that none of that matters.
The only important thing
is that you're alive
and that we're together.
Do you remember the last time
you wore that dress?
It was the night I proposed
to you a year and a half ago.
We were spending a weekend
in the city
and we had dinner at this
rooftop restaurant
that was way too expensive.
I love you so much.
When you had your accident,
I thought for the first time
what life might be
like without you.
You can ask Richard, I was...
I was terrified.
It was like I had
taken you for granted
and I was gonna lose you.
Please, will you take a look?
I don't wanna wait anymore.
I can't wait anymore.
And Melissa thought
you'd like it.
A wedding ring.
Oh, my God.
I know we've never
set a date before,
but I don't wanna risk
losing you ever again.
I don't care if
it's just you and me
on a beach somewhere.
I feel like we've been
given a second chance
at a life together...
and I want you to be my wife.
Brooke, will you be my wife?
I just...
I don't know what to say.
All this time I thought
that you and Melissa...
She helped me pick it out.
And believe me,
she spared no expense.
No.
She must think I'm horrible.
You are.
You're a horrible,
horrible person.
That's exactly why I love you.
I spoke to the minister,
and we can do it tomorrow
at our house.
What do you say?
Yes.
I'll make all the arrangements.
Nothing fancy, I promise.
Sweetheart, what's wrong?
I just wish that
my sister would come.
Let's...
let's not worry about the past.
A toast.
To a prosperous
and beautiful future.
Could you excuse me
for a minute?
I couldn't help but overhear.
Congratulations!
Thank you very much.
I always thought
you made a good couple.
Oh, I'm sorry, do I know you?
Oh, that's right,
I forgot about that...
You know?
That's all right.
I work at the coffee shop.
Double-shot hazelnut latte
with room for extra cream.
That's very good.
Ha-ha, like an elephant.
I remember when my husband
and I got engaged,
I was terrified.
We were already engaged.
Oh.
Yeah, we're just making
plans for the date.
You two were engaged?
Wow, I... I had no idea.
I never want either
of us to forget
how much we love each other.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
I'm sure.
Go get 'em.
Hello, I'd like to speak
to someone in your
marketing department.
Where might I find it?
In your Tucson office, huh?
No, it's okay.
I'll call directly, thank you.
Detective.
He told me he was in marketing.
I don't... I don't know.
Am I crazy?
Look, I'll run these for prints
and I'll also check employee
records for the company
and we should be able to
get a positive ID, okay?
What about Dr. Alvarez?
Have you talked to him yet?
No.
His answering service
said he was out of town.
We left a message.
Y'know, we just had
this wonderful dinner
and...
everything is going so well.
I guess I'd be silly
to hope that I'm wrong
about all this.
No.
I would, too.
Sorry to hear about your accident.
Thank you.
Now, to answer your question,
I don't see mention of an
engagement on the account.
Now, unless the account holder
specifically adds a non-spouse
as beneficiary to the account,
they'd have no access.
What about direct deposit?
Is there anything you can
show me with income?
Whose?
Michael.
Like I told you, Michael
would need to be added.
But it's his account.
No, ma'am, it's your account.
Ms. Harris,
this money is yours.
You inherited it from
your parents.
Are there any
other accounts that...
Not with us.
You're sure he said...
Yes, he said Emerald Savings
& Trust, I'm sure.
I'm very, very sure about that.
So what you're saying is
that he can't get
access to this money
without my permission.
Not unless he was married to
you and something happened.
Out of curiosity,
how much money
is in the account?
What's wrong with you?
This isn't your car.
What do you want?
What I want?
It's me, Reynolds.
Your trainer.
I had an accident.
I'm having a difficult
time with faces.
Is that why you've been
running away from me?
You thought...
you thought I was
trying to hurt you?
You came to my house.
We had an appointment.
I'm sorry, you must think
I'm losing my mind.
Hey, don't worry about it.
I'm...
I'm sorry I didn't know.
Hey.
Here.
Call me when you're feeling up
to start working out
again, okay?
Hello?
Courtney?
Who is this?
Brooke.
I know that we haven't
talked in a while,
but I had an
accident on the boat.
Oh, Brooke.
Please, I can't remember...
I can't remember my house,
my fiancé, Michael.
I can't remember why
you and I are fighting...
Wait a second, you didn't
actually get engaged
to that deadbeat, did you?
And I bet you didn't
get a prenup either.
Isn't marriage based on trust?
You cannot get engaged to a guy
that you have only
known a couple of months.
We've been engaged for
longer than that.
Listen, Brooke.
When Mom and Dad
gave us their estate,
they put their trust in us.
I'll call you back.
Who was that on the phone?
Oh, it was just a wrong number.
Oh, check you out.
Hi.
I'm early for my appointment,
so I thought I'd come in
and check in
on the blushing bride.
Thanks for the company.
He is gonna be so happy.
I was feeling the red,
what do you think?
I think go with it.
You know, I was thinking,
since you're gonna be
the only other girl,
you're gonna get the bouquet.
Yeah, yeah, I'd rather cut off
both my arms than catch it.
Oh, wait, y'know what,
I'm sorry, one second.
Maybe that's him.
Hello?
I had the station run those prints
and got a positive ID.
Michael Taylor.
Born 1974.
Permanent residence
listed in Reno, Nevada.
And are you ready for this?
I found three restraining orders
against him from prior
girlfriends.
Really?
And he works for
the Bevlyn Bottling Company,
and according to the people
I spoke to,
you two were never engaged.
I'm sorry, Brooke.
Look, I'm on my way over now.
That's okay.
Didn't you hear
what I just said?
The man could be dangerous.
I will take care
of that, thank you.
Brooke?
Who was that?
Oh, it's just a wedding gift
that I was getting Michael.
What was that?
She hung up.
Does she have any idea
what kind of trouble
she's looking at?
I think I'm gonna go.
Wait.
I wanted to ask you a question.
A year and a half ago,
when Michael asked me
to marry him,
what did I say?
You said it was
the happiest day of your life.
See ya.
Sweetheart, Brooke?
Honey, what's going on?
Oh, wow.
The minister's
gonna be here soon.
What's the hurry, honey?
It's just us.
Sweetheart, the minister's
gonna be here any minute.
He's not coming.
Why?
Come on, let's just do this
privately, you and I.
I like your thinking.
First, you know,
we should make a toast.
Don't you think?
Okay.
To the future
Mr. and Mrs. Coleman.
I'll drink to that.
Mmm.
You remembered
my favorite label.
Yeah, I'm remembering
a lot of things.
What else do you remember?
Well, I went to the bank today
and, you know, they
told me the funniest thing.
Huh?
Yeah.
The money,
it turns out it's all mine.
You mean ours.
No, I mean mine.
But don't worry,
I've transferred it all
to an offshore account.
What?
Just to be safe.
I thought that was
a really good idea.
Why would you do that?
Maybe for the same reason
you doctored every
photo in this house.
What?
For the reason you put
a ring on my finger
and made me believe
that we were engaged.
Sweetheart, I already
explained that.
Did you ever love me?
Let me tell you a little
story about a woman
who inherits
a large sum of money
from her parents.
She's a little lonely, you know,
she doesn't get out very
often, she works from home,
which makes her vulnerable.
And one day, along comes
a nice, handsome man.
But it turns
out he's not so nice.
She thinks that he loves her,
but all he really
wants is her money.
He wants to marry her,
but she refuses.
And when he becomes violent,
she tries to run away.
The next thing you know,
she wakes up in a hospital room,
without any of her
memories at all!
But he, he does everything
he can in his power...
to make her forget
how hard it all really was.
I mean, he goes so far,
he even gets a friend
to pretend to be
her psychiatrist.
I mean, what was his angle?
Was he gonna get
a cut of the money, too?
It's hard to build
a relationship
based on lies, isn't it?
Brooke?
Just in time.
She knows.
What?
She transferred the money.
Where?
Somewhere you can't touch it.
Offshore!
What's wrong with him?
Well, I guess
the sedatives I gave him
didn't mix well with
the champagne.
Where is it?
So you were the one
following me all the time
just waiting for the right
moment to make your move.
Where?
Go ahead and shoot me,
but unless we're married,
he's not gonna get a dime,
which means you're not
gonna get a dime.
I should have killed you
the first time.
Oh, yeah, what were
you gonna do?
Kill me after the wedding
and live happily ever after
on all of my money?
Let me ask you a question.
Did he ever hit you?
Because there are
three women out there
with restraining orders
against him.
Is that the kind of guy
that you wanna be with?
I mean, it takes a real man
to hit a woman,
you know what I'm saying?
You know, I mean,
you really wanna be
with a real man...
You tell me how to
access the account.
You don't have a choice.
You think you're so smart, huh?
You think you got everything
figured out!
Let me kill her.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
She's gonna tell us
where the money is.
You know what your
problem's always been?
You're too stubborn.
No.
She's not gonna tell
you anything.
Oh, yes she is.
She's gonna tell me
everything I wanna know
because she knows there's not
gonna be any second chances.
Brooke!
Brooke, baby!
Just tell me where
the accounts are,
you'll never see me again!
Brooke!
Now, where's my money?
The honeymoon's never quite
how you envisioned it, is it?
Yeah, it's over there.
No weapons?
No, I'm just gonna bag this
and head back down.
Well, that's fine.
Let me get...
You're lucky.
A neighbor heard gunshots
and called it in.
We picked up
his friend, Dr. Alvarez,
trying to get out of town.
Who was he?
Some doctor that thought being
a con artist paid better.
He and Michael did this
to another girl
down in Portland,
but I think he's gonna
cut a deal,
help us put him away.
Hopefully he'll never
hurt anyone again...
thanks to you.
So what are you gonna do now?
Start over.
Rebuild my life.
Well... we're ready
to take your statement
when you're up to it, okay?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Brooke.
Are you okay?
I was so worried
after you called me.
Finding out about
the engagement...
You were right.
He just wanted the money.
And all this time, I just
thought you were jealous.
Maybe I was.
But not because of Michael.
'Cause I thought you had
something I've always wanted.
I should have listened to you.
You were in love.
Sometimes that
makes us do crazy things.
I should have been
more supportive.
I was overly protective
about Mom and Dad's estate.
It almost cost me
my only sister.
Can I come stay with you
for a couple of days?
I love you, sis.
I love you, too.