- You're about to see something
very special: me.
- When was the last time
either of you got blasted?
- Um...
- When was the last time
you got bucked?
- Don't answer that.
- Oh, Ellen, I love you.
- I love you too.
- And you are?
- I'm Amber,
and I love you so much, Ellen.
- Oh, thank you so much.
Well, I hope you win then.
- Ellen, I love you.
- I love you too.
- She's gone.
I don't know where she went.
- Give it up for your host,
Ellen DeGeneres!
- Thank you so much.
Thank you very much.
Have a seat.
Welcome to my "Game of Games."
We have got a big show for you
tonight with lots of big games.
When you watch tonight's show
you're going to feel
excited and nervous
and maybe even confused.
It's the same way I feel when
I listen to a Cardi B song,
and here is the best part
of tonight's show:
Someone in the audience
is going to have a chance
to win $100,000.
- And, by the way, you don't
have to be here to win.
You can play along at home.
While I set up this next game,
here's how you do that.
Open your "Game of Games" app,
and you'll see
a free scratcher ticket.
During tonight's show,
a lucky penny
will appear on the screen.
Us your phone's camera
to capture the penny.
Then, you can scratch away
and see what you've won.
There are thousands of prizes,
so good luck.
All right.
Have a seat everybody.
So this game is like if a cop
gives you a sobriety test
after being drunk
and then on a Tilt-A-Whirl
at the same time.
It's time to play Dizzy Dash.
- All right, tWitch.
Who's going to play?
- All right. Where are Alex
Antenescu and Chidi Azema?
- How you doing, Ellen?.
- Hi. Thank you so much. Hi.
Which one are you?
- Hey.
- You're Alex.
- I'm Alex Antenescu.
I'm from Charlotte, North
Carolina, and I'm in sales.
- In sales?
- Yeah.
- What type of sales?
- I'm outside sales.
I, like, go out in the field
and try to sell things
to people, nicely hopefully.
- Okay.
- I kind of-- Yeah.
- I don't know what you do,
but I don't believe you.
All right. And you are?
- How you doing?
My name is Chidi Azema,
and I'm from New York.
I'm a brand curator.
- All right.
See, there's a clear answer,
a brand curator.
You just sell things, and I
don't even know what you sell.
Like, what kind of things
do you sell?
- I'm in the cannabis industry.
I sell CBD.
- I see.
- So I'm in the CBD market.
- There you go.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- That's why you were like
"outside sales."
Yeah. Now we're talking.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Don't dance around that.
That's fine. So go have a seat
in those chairs, by the way.
They're comfortable. Okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
- And then I'll show
you how to play.
- Let's go.
- After spinning,
two contestants will race
to answer
my questions correctly.
The first person to get
three questions right moves on
to Know or Go.
- All right. Here we go then.
We're going to start.
We're going to play
until someone has three points
or until I'm queasy
from watching you both,
whichever comes first.
All right.
Let's play Dizzy Dash.
- You're about to spin faster
than a bike at SoulCycle.
Speaking of which,
if a bike has two wheels,
a unicycle has one
and a tricycle has three,
what singer famously told Jesus
to "take the wheel"?
Spin them.
- Whoa.
That's some g-force shiz.
- All righty.
What is the answer?
- Is it Carrie Underwood?
- Yes, that is right!
Yes!
- Yeah! Let's go!
- All right.
- Good job.
Good job.
- Okay.
I think the front row
needs to be prepared
to catch him next time
because--
- Bro, that's fast, man.
- That was really--
Yeah. Yeah, it goes fast.
It's called Dizzy Dash.
Here we go.
If Ziggy Stardust
was David Bowie,
Mimi was Mariah Carey,
Slim Shady was Eminem,
whose alter ego
was Hannah Montana?
Spin 'em.
- Oh. Oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
- Oh.
- No.
No!
- Whoo!
- It's getting real out here.
- I almost had it!
- Whoo!
- Miley Cyrus!
- That's right. Miley Cyrus!
- You better get it right
for all that.
- Yeah.
So you each have one point,
which is fantastic.
I think next season
we have to add more padding
because we thought
we had enough, but clearly--
All right, here we go:
Your brain must be
spinning by now so
I'll give you an easy one.
Say the last three letters
of the alphabet backwards.
Spin them.
- Popped the ball.
Z, Y, X.
- That's right.
-Oh, my god.
- I have bad news.
- Good job. Good job. Good job.
- Are you good?
- I'm good!
My head is a little crazy!
- Yeah, I've got
the same thing.
- Yeah!
- You can just set it down.
- This is popped.
- That-- It popped? Okay.
- Yeah.
- All right, you boys--
That's all right.
- Yeah.
- We have plenty of those.
- I was so focused
on running out.
- Bro, yeah.
I did the same thing.
- All right.
Some of the popular hashtags
this year were: LOL, BRB, TBT.
What letters are on the number
two button of a phone keypad?
Spin them.
- Aha!
- Whoa!
- That was very close.
- What is it?
- D, E, F.
- No!
- You have a chance to steal.
Do you know what it is?
- On a number two keypad?
- Yeah.
What are the letters
on the number two keypad?
- The letters on
the number two, uh...
it is D--
- It was A, B, C.
- Aw.
- Yep. I know.
That's a tricky one.
That's what we do.
- Whew.
- Yeah.
- We're tricky.
All right.
If Rihanna rows her raft
down a stream merrily,
merrily, merrily,
what does the itsy bitsy spider
climb up?
Spin them.
- Oh.
- He's got it. Alex has it.
- The itsy bitsy spider walks
up the water spout.
- That is correct. Yes!
- Down came the rain
and washed the spider out!
- You are the winner!
- You are going on to play
Know or Go,
one step closer
to $100,000.
- Yeah!
- We'll be right back!
- Alex dashes his way
to the top of Know or Go
for the chance
at some big money.
Coming up, grab a seat.
- Oh, man!
- It's Blindfolded
Musical Chairs.
- Oh.
- Want to catch your breath?
Too late.
Dance.
- Oh, great.
- And the classic...
- This red button
is in front of me.
I don't know what it does.
- Danger Word.
And fall in love
with the all-new
Runaway Bride.
- You've probably heard
of a messy divorce.
Well, I've invented,
for the first time ever,
a messy wedding.
It's time to play
Runaway Bride.
- Hit the road.
I need three contestants
to vow to love me
no matter what I do to them.
Who is it, tWitch?
- I got you.
Where are Leann Oliver, Felicia
McGuire and Neandre Pesade?
- Hi! How's it going?
- Hi. Good to meet you.
- Who are you?
- Hi, I'm Leann.
I'm from Goodyear, Arizona,
and I'm a photographer. Whoo!
- You are?
- I'm Neandre.
I'm from Dallas, Texas,
and I started a organization
that helps black boys get
access to free business attire.
- Whoo!
- Fantastic. Good for you.
- Yes.
- And you are?
- Hi, I'm Felicia McGuire.
I'm from Birmingham, Alabama,
and I'm a field
applications engineer.
- All right.
- Whoo!
- All of those are good things.
While we turn you
into blushing brides,
here's how you play this game.
Cold feet are going to be
the least
of these brides' worries.
In this game, three brides
will sprint towards the altar
on a treadmill.
I'll launch slices of cake
into the air
and then the brides
will fight to catch them.
But beware. Not everything
I launch will be cake,
and that stuff
is worthless, huh?
The first bride to catch
three pieces of cake
and place them on their hope
chest will win my heart,
and they'll move on
to Know or Go.
- Oh.
You're too cute.
- I love it!
- Beautiful. Beautiful.
All right.
I got you some wedding gifts.
One of them is this
industrial-sized treadmill.
Let's get that
started right now.
Okay.
- Oh, my god.
- That's going pretty fast.
- This is fast!
- The other gifts will appear
being launched from over here.
Brides, pull up your garters
and don't trip
over your trains.
Ready, set, and...
go.
- Whoa.
- Whoo!
- Oh, god.
- Oh, my god.
No.
- Whoo!
- Oh!
Whoo!
- Leann.
- Hi.
- That was a fight.
- Yeah.
- That was a fight over
a piece of cake.
- Whoo! Yes.
- Good for you.
I am going to send you
on a honeymoon
to the top of Know or Go,
one step closer
to the $100,000.
We'll be back.
- That was hilarious.
- Thank you so much!
- You're welcome!
I'll see you later!
- Thank you.
It's more than enough,
and it's almost too much.
The game is more moving than
the episode of "This is Us."
It's time to play
Blindfolded Musical Chairs.
- Yeah!
- All right.
Let's see who is going to play
this crazy game.
Who are you, sir?
- My name is Kelton Hunt.
I'm from St. George, Utah,
and I'm a premed student
at Dixie State University.
- Wonderful.
And you are?
- I'm Petey Yang.
I'm from Hoschton, Georgia,
and I'm a makeup artist.
- Wonderful, Petey. All right.
And you are?
- I am Madison Colbo.
I'm from Hattiesburg,
Mississippi,
and I'm a skin-care consultant
who can also beatbox.
- Oh, wow. And who are you?
- I am Tamara Canara.
I'm from Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania,
and I am a premium processer,
aka I just process payments.
- All right.
- Yes. We love it.
- All right. This game
is so much fun and so easy.
Here's how you play.
- Four contestants
will be blindfolded.
When I stop the music,
they'll race to find a seat.
Whoever can't find one
will be eliminated.
We'll play three rounds,
and the final player
in the game will win
and advance to Know or Go.
Okay, give you your blindfolds,
and the beginning
of our enjoyment.
- Oh, god.
- Everyone has a different way
to do this.
All right, let the music play
and begin dancing.
- Oh, and they really
hit the ground.
Okay.
- Whoo!
- They are in a hurry.
They are in a hurry
to find this.
Okay.
- Whoa!
- Kelton's on!
- Whoo!
- Oh, no!
- Sorry!
- Oh, man.
- All right.
- Whoo.
- Oh, man.
- Oh.
- Whoa.
- No.
So close, and yet, no--
- Ah!
I'm so tired.
- Petey is putting his head up
like a little turtle
out of a pond.
Looking around like that helps.
Oh, on to the spinning
wheel of death.
- Whoo!
- Now he's crawling
like a snake.
- Yeah!
- Madison got it!
Okay.
- Oop!
- No, that was a leg.
- Oh, my god! Oh, my god.
Oh, my god.
- Whoo!
- Oh, my god.
I'm so sorry.
Petey, did-- I don't know.
I didn't mean to hit that one,
and somehow it surprised you,
I'm sure.
It surprised me too.
- It's okay.
- Okay.
All right.
And, Kelton, that was some
excellent ballroom dancing.
Good use of the space.
- Yeah.
- All right.
Ready?
Dance.
- Oh! Ooh!
- Okay. That's--
Have to put an adult warning
on this show because of that.
All right. Oh, wow, Petey,
that quite something.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, it's like
a performance art, almost.
Wonderful.
- I'm going to need to
work on my cardio.
- Okay.
The rolling is good.
It helps.
Okay.
Someone was very close!
No, you passed it up!
- Whoo!
- Kelton got it!
Okay.
Let's see.
There's one stool left!
Oh.
- Oh, Petey.
- Yes!
- Oh, Petey, I'm going to miss
your dancing. That was--
You were so close, and then
you passed it right by.
- Thank you. Oh, well that--
- That's the thing.
Okay, now, one of you is going
to go play Know or Go
because there's two of you left
and one stool.
All right, you want to catch
your breath?
Too late.
Dance.
- Spicy hot.
- Whoa.
Okay.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
- Whoo!
- Whoo.
Yeah!
- Hi, Kelton.
- Hey, how are you?
- That's fantastic.
- Whoo!
- You're going to be up there
playing Know or Go,
one step closer to $100,000.
- Whoo!
- We'll be right back.
- Yes! That was excellent.
- Kelton secures the best seat
in the house on Know or Go
for a chance at $100,000.
Up next...
- I know you want to do it.
- So bad.
- Go ahead.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Contestants push
Ellen's buttons.
- Aww.
- Yep.
- Nothing else matters.
- Welcome back to my
"Game of Games."
It's important to think
before you speak,
especially with this next game
because one wrong word
and you will be
left speechless.
It's time to play
Danger Word.
♪ When you hear the call
- All right. tWitch,
who is going to step
into the danger zone?
- All right. Where are Eddie
and Audrey Later,
and Paige Greighton,
Jenna Massai?
- Oh, my god!
- , Ellen.
- All right, you are?
- I'm Jenna.
- Hi, Jenna.
- And I'm Paige.
- And--
- And what's
the relationship here?
- We're best friends.
- Okay.
- And we're both
dental hygienists,
and this is a dream come true!
Whoo!
- That's wonderful.
And you are?
- I'm Audrey, and this is
my husband of 42 years, Ed.
- I'm Eddie.
- Oh, wow.
- Eddie.
- Whoo.
- 42 years.
They have a connection that is
going to be tough to beat
because when you're together
that long, you know what
you're thinking, right?
- Usually.
- Yeah. Good and bad.
- Good and bad, right.
- All right.
Eddie and Paige,
you're going to sit over there,
and you two are going to
stay here with me, all right?
- Yeah.
- Whoo!
- See what just happened?
They just high-fived.
She just left you.
- I know!
- I'm so excited.
- I know.
Here's how you play this game.
The object of the game
is to get your partner
to guess the winner word
using only one-word clues.
However, if they say
the danger word instead,
I'll blast them.
Take too long, get blasted.
Illegal clue, get blasted.
If the other team guesses
the winning word,
that's right, you get blasted.
Three blasts
and the game is over.
Then the winning team
will send one player on
to Know or Go.
Okeydokey.
All right.
And I'm going to apologize in
advance for whatever happens.
All right, here's my friend
Martha Stewart
to tell the people at home
what the danger word is.
- The winning word is "sofa."
The danger word is "couch."
- All righty.
We're going to start
with you, Jenna.
- Chair.
- Sit.
- Recliner.
- Easy.
- TV.
- La-Z-Boy.
- God, you really--
Your face was like,
"I got this,"
and that is not right.
Okay.
- Wrap-around.
- Couch.
- That is the danger word.
Oh, no.
Unfortunately this red button
is front of me.
I don't know what it does.
I'm just going to
push it to see, okay?
- Oh!
- Oh, thank you so much.
- All right.
- That was beautiful.
- Audrey really feels bad
for you.
- Yeah, it's killing me..
- What does that taste like?
- Ketchup?
- No, you're higher class
than that: It's SpaghettiOs.
- SpaghettiOs!
- Yeah.
- All right, here is
Steph Curry with our next word.
- The winning word
is "dribble."
The danger word is "bounce."
- All right, so we move on
to Audrey and Eddie.
- Bib.
- Napkin?
- Basketball.
- Jersey?
- Baby.
- Food.
- I'll let you push when we--
- Oh, really?
- I'll let you push it.
- It's worth losing.
- All right.
- Spit.
- Rag.
- Neck.
- Dribble.
- Yes!
- Yeah! Yeah! Whoo!
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
- Basketball!
Yeah, of course!
- Again, I have no idea
what's going to come out
because it's always
something different.
Let's just see.
- Oh, no!
- Oh, I think it's chocolate.
- It is, chocolate.
All right.
Melissa McCarthy,
tell us our next word.
- The winning word
is "celebration."
The danger word is "party."
- All right, Jenna.
- Cheers.
- "Cheers." Champagne.
- Festive.
- Party.
- Now, to be fair, Audrey--
- What?
- Anniversaries, celebrations,
you know, festive--
- Oh, you thought
I should have said--
- Yeah.
- Should have said.
- I'm on his side on this one.
I'm so sorry.
- Thank you.
- But I know you want to do it.
- So bad.
- Go ahead.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Nothing else matters.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
- All right.
- Oh, Eddie.
- See, it's a--
- Oh! Oh!
- It's a--
She doesn't even
care she's losing!
- This is the best thing ever!
- Oh, my gosh.
- Eddie, there's $100,000
at stake,
and all she cares about
is hitting that button
and making you--
- Story of my time.
- All right.
Kenan Thompson,
our danger word, please.
- The winning word is "booty,"
of course.
Booty.
The danger word is "butt."
Stay away from them butts.
You hear me kids?
- All right.
We are back to Audrey.
This is tricky.
- Behind.
- Back.
- Okay.
- Sit.
- Butt.
- Whoo!
- I'm sorry.
- Oh.
- Then it's even,
which is exciting because--
Yeah. All right.
There you go.
- Oh, I'm sorry, Paige.
- All right, here's Hoda Kotb
with our next word.
- The winning word is "sea."
The danger word is "ocean."
Back to you, Ellen.
- All right, Jenna.
- Otter.
- Sea.
- Yes!
- Oh, boy,
that is really a shame.
And, you know what, you might
as well do the final one.
Go ahead, please.
All right.
- Oh.
- You were accurate
with that one.
- All right.
You'll go on to play
Know or Go...
- Yes! Whoo!
- For a chance
to win $100,000!
We'll be right back!
- Whoo!
- So Jenna
narrowly makes her way
to the top of Know or Go,
for $100,000.
Up next you either know...
- Oh, god!
- Or...
- Whoa!
- You go!
- Oh.
- It's important to use
your head in this next game
because if you don't, you're
going to land on your keister.
Let's play Know or Go.
- I'm sorry.
I'm still thinking
about that word, "keister."
It's a weird word. Keister.
Anyway, tWitch,
bring out our players!
- Hello, you guys!
Kelton, you couldn't
see yourself ballroom dancing,
and that's probably
a good thing.
Jenna, your best friend got
covered with chocolate sauce
while you made a clean getaway
in Danger Word.
Leann, it was a little fight
to the finish,
but you came out on top
in Runaway Bride,
and, finally, Alex,
you broke our ball
and almost a whole lot more
on Dizzy Dash.
The pressure is on because
only one of you is going to be
standing up there
to go on to play for $100,000.
- The game is simple:
I am going to ask you
a question.
If you know, you stay.
If you don't, you go.
Let's play Know or Go.
- All right.
Kelton, they say good things
come in pairs.
Which pair of twins
played Michelle Tanner
on "Full House."
- Mary-Kate and Ashley!
- That's right!
- All right.
Jenna, I got a feeling that
you're either going to get this
feeling right or wrong.
- Oh, no, Ellen.
- Who sang "I Gotta Feeling"?
- "I Gotta Feeling."
- Yep. Yep.
- Yep. Yep. Yep.
- Black Eyed Peas!
- Yes!
- Leann, ghosting someone means
you end a relationship
by stopping communication.
Who is known as
"the Friendly Ghost"?
- "The Friendly Ghost"
is "Casper the Friendly Ghost"!
- That is correct.
- Alex, Sir Mix-a-lot sang,
"My anaconda don't want none
unless you got buns, hon."
What's the name of the most
popular cinnamon roll chain?
- The name of the most popular
cinnamon roll chain
is called Cinnabon.
- That's right!
- Yes.
- All righty.
Kelton, in 2019,
what former "Suits" actress
gave birth to a royal baby?
- I don't even know
if I have a guess!
- Take a guess.
- Jennifer Lawrence!
- No!
- All right.
Meghan Markle
is married to Prince Harry.
- Oh, no!
Please, please, please!
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Oh.
I want to see my family.
- Oh, they're down here.
Come on down.
- Oh, my god!
- Oh, that's quick!
That's right away!
- Oh!
- That's so sweet of me!
He wanted to see his family
and I brought him down.
Jenna.
- Hi, Ellen.
- Hi.
It might be time for you to go
if you can't tell me
what's the name
of the famous clock in London?
- The famous clock in London
is Big Ben!
- That is correct!
- Leann, they say breakfast
is the most
important meal of the day.
I say it's happy hour.
What cereal's slogan is
"The breakfast of champions"?
- "Breakfast of champions."
I'm going to say...
Frosted Flakes.
- It's Wheaties.
- Okay!
- Yeah, that's the breakfast
of champions.
- Oh, my!
- But Tony the Tiger thought
that that was a great answer.
- Right. Right.
- Okay.
Oh, you're making your bonnet
and you're getting ready?
- It's so pretty,.
- Okay, that's good because
that'll
be cute on the way down.
- Yeah.
- I know.
- All right. Ready?
- Thank you, Ellen!
- Ready?
- No, I'm not ready!
I'm not ready, Ellen!
I'm not ready!
- I'm not ready!
- Okay, now do it.
- Oh, god.
- Whoa!
- Ellen!
, Ellen.
- Hup!
Pshhoo!
Dong!
- I love you, Ellen.
- Oh.
- I do, I love you--
- Whoa.
- Oh!
- It's far!
It's very far,
and it goes beyond that, too.
It goes out, and then down
a sewer line, and it's--
Okay, this is exciting.
This is Sudden Drop.
If you get an answer wrong,
it doesn't mean
that the game is over,
it means that your opponent
has a chance to steal.
If they get it right, you drop.
If not, we go back
to the questions again.
It comes down to this,
and it's so exciting,
especially for my
stage manager, Linda,
because she's so excited
she's crawling around
on her hands and knees.
And-- Oh, I'm sorry,
she lost a contact.
That's what's-- Okay.
Alex, I feel like
we're really in sync.
What former member of NSYNC
is married
to Jessica Biel?
- NSYNC.
Um...
Oh, it's the blond guy.
The frosted tips.
Justin Timberlake!
- Yes, yes.
- Justin Timberlake!
- Yes!
- Yes! Oh.
- Okay.
Justin is going to be so happy
you remember
those frosted tips.
- Sorry, Justin.
- He's going to be watching
that, going,
"I'll never live that down."
It was the '90s, Justin.
- Yeah.
- It's okay. Don't feel bad.
All right, Jenna.
Jenna, there's not question
that this game
is above the law.
What does "FBI" stand for?
Federal Business
Insurance?
Ooh!
- Okay, that is not correct.
Alex, do you know
what it stands for?
- It's Federal Bureau
of Investigation!
- That's right!
- Yeah!
-   Yeah,.
I'm so sorry!
- I am so sorry.
Jenna, that's a shame, though.
They do not provide insurance
to people.
- No they don't! No they don't!
- No, no.
You're going to go down,
and it's going to be so fun.
Look forward to it!
You have no choice!
Be so excited!
- Oh, Ellen, I love you!
- Just say,
"Ellen, I can't wait
to go down there!"
- No, no, no, I'm not excited!
- No--
- No, no, no, no, no!
- No, say it, "I can't wait to
go down there, Ellen!"
- Ellen, I can't wait
to go down there!
- Whoo!
Yeah!
- You're the winner!
You're going
to play Hot Hands!
- Ellen, please.
- Come on down!
- No, no, no!
- Oh, we'll be back.
- All righty.
Well, we're back with Alex,
and I don't want
to freak you out
but we're one step away
from $100,000 possibly.
- Tell me what that money
would mean to you, Alex.
- Well, it'd mean
the world to me.
I'm first generation
in this country, actually.
My family are immigrants
and they won green cards
to get here,
so they kind of scrapped
and did whatever they could to
get to where we are now,
so I'd like to help them
with whatever is going on
in their financial situation.
- Good for you.
- Yeah.
- Who's here cheering you on?
- My mom is right there.
- All right.
Hi, Mama. Hi.
All right, you played
the app before, I hope?
- Yeah, I binged it hard.
- Okay, good.
- It's super addicting.
- Well, yeah.
It is addicting,
but it's so fun.
- Yeah.
- And when you play the app,
the more you play the app, the
better you are in this game.
- Okay, good.
- All right.
The moment we've been
waiting for is here.
Let's play Hot Hands.
- Here's what's going
to happen:
We are going to show you
a series of celebrities.
As soon as you say their name,
hit the button,
lock in your answer.
We'll show you
the next picture.
If you're wrong or take
too long to answer,
the picture will change
automatically.
You only have three seconds.
Move very fast, so think fast.
The more people you name,
the more money you win.
If you can name 10 celebrities
in 30 seconds,
you'll go home with $100,000.
- Whoo! Whoo!
- You get to pick
your category.
So they are Hilarious People,
So Many Logos!,
or World's Greatest
Checkers Players.
- Let's go with
Hilarious People.
- Hilarious People.
Rise him up!
- Whoo!
- All right, Alex.
Get your hot hands ready.
For $100,000, go.
- Ellen DeGeneres.
- Adam Sandler.
- Amy Schumer.
- Kevin Hart.
- Jimmy Kimmel.
- Pass.
Pass.
Zach Galifianakis.
Will Ferrell.
- Eddie Murphy.
- Pass.
Pass.
Oh, no!
- $40,000!
- Whoo!
I've won 40,000!
$40,000's good!
- You got seven right.
That was fantastic.
Come on down here, Mom.
- Mom!
- You are the winner
of my "Game of Games"!
I'll see you next time!
Bye-bye.
- Whoo!