There was a murder in the house
at one time.
There was a murder
in the house?
Like shots of a headache.
Speak to us.
They murdered the man
for his gold.
- "my gold."
- "my gold"?
Do you know what's
happening in the house?
That's a stairwell
going straight up, boys.
The most frightening thing
is being shoved.
Dude, I'm sorry.
- "hold my hand."
- my god.
They are
the spirit hunters.
I feel something
behind me.
They are who people call
when they are tormented
by entities that circle back
night after night --
entities bent on destroying
the lives of the living.
Does this look like the night
that you were murdered?
These spirits
are often trapped,
repeating the same trauma
over and over.
The mission
of the spirit hunters
is to help the living
by breaking the cycle of
the ghost loop.
The spirit hunters
are in clear spring, maryland,
where lee and garry are
being attacked by a ghost loop.
There's at least two spirits
in this house.
They're residents.
They are here.
It's just kind of a feeling of
being pushed down the stairs.
That's scary.
I don't know how
to tell them to go.
I don't think
we're gonna be able
to sell the house
until it's clean.
This, of course,
was one of the prominent states
during the civil war,
so you can definitely feels that
energy just driving around here.
We're talking civil war,
and slavery,
and those were two
very emotional,
traumatic times
in history.
Clear spring is 6 miles from
the border of pennsylvania,
a free state since 1787,
which made clear spring
one of the last stops
on the underground railroad.
As you guys were bringing up
all this stuff,
I just have an overall sense
of desperation.
Built in 1803, lee and garry's
home is steeped in history.
The possibilities for what the
ghost loop might be are vast.
So, lee, can you tell us
a little bit
about the ghost loop
of activity?
What exactly
happens to you?
Every night, between
about 1:00 and 3:00,
I wake up hearing voices
and footsteps downstairs.
When I get up, I go out to the
landing, lean over the railing,
there was a mist.
The mist,
for a few moments,
had the shape of
a lady in a gown.
But without a doubt,
the most frightening thing
is being shoved.
Really terrifying.
That is scary.
You feel this shove
when you're on the stairs?
Yes. Yes.
I could fall down the stairs.
That could...
It could be fatal.
Right. Yes.
It's really, really scary.
Can you guys
go a little bit
deep into the history
of this property?
The house was built in 1803
as a tavern for travelers
going to
the ohio territory.
It was built by slaves,
and then, it was part of
the underground railroad.
Pennsylvania
is right nearby.
6 miles.
6 miles north of here.
I could imagine, during slavery,
that this could have been
one of their last stops
to freedom.
It was.
The tavern was a destination
for the underground railroad,
but not to give slaves
their freedom.
The innkeeper
and his wife...
Their name was kinsell.
...They would capture
runaway slaves,
and then sell them back
for $5 each.
During its days on
the underground railroad,
the house had a tunnel
that ran underneath,
where freedom seekers
were kept.
It was also the place
where the kinsells kept
one for their own --
a little boy.
What happened
with the little boy?
They kept the little boy,
and when they had to hide him,
they would hide him
in the tunnel under the house.
Tunnel?
Is it visible?
You can still see it?
No.
It's been closed off.
So, there was a good chance
that he was in that damp,
cold tunnel, and got sick,
and died.
We really don't know.
So, what are the fatalities that
you know of on this property?
The little boy
and a runaway slave
that was killed
up in the woods.
He was hanged.
Right here?
Right up here,
in the woods.
What about the innkeepers
themselves?
Well, we know that kinsell
was an alcoholic
after the
little boy's death.
He apparently died falling off
a wagon, and breaking his neck.
Lee and garry take kris
and sean into the house
to show them the location
of the ghost loop.
But on the way, lee shows them
where the tunnel once was.
This is the area
under the stairs.
And the tunnel
is under this floor.
Could you walk us through
the exact steps
when you're awoken at night
with the ghost loop of activity?
Absolutely.
I'd be glad to.
This is our bedroom.
And this is where
I'm sleeping
when I wake up hearing
the voices and the footsteps.
And I'll come out here
to the landing.
And I do try to look over,
but as you can see,
you really can't see
the entire hallway there.
Coming down here,
I can still hear the voices
and this footsteps.
And this is where this thing
wants to shove you,
right here at this point?
Right here. Right here.
This is where I feel
the...The push.
This is the most dangerous part
of the stairs,
that you would
harm yourself the worst.
It is very scary.
With the interview over,
sean and kris fill in
the rest of the team.
- What's up guys?
How we doing?
- What's going on?
This place used to
be a tavern.
Lots of walks of life
have come through this property.
There's a couple
of culprits.
The innkeepers that owned the
tavern and the little boy slave
that was here fleeing
for his safety.
And then, lastly,
we have this man
that was hung
on the property
'cause he was trying to
escape for his freedom.
So, here's the plan --
the three of you,
why don't you guys
go inside the house,
see what you guys
can get.
Because this man may have been
hung right up the hill,
kris and I are going to go
up there, and check it out,
and see if we can get any
evidence of that, as well.
And we'll link up
past that.
Sweet.
- Alright, guys.
- Let's go.
While matt, eric, and califf
investigate the location
of the ghost loop
in the house,
sean and kris
investigate outside,
where a runaway slave
was murdered.
Emf reader -- see if you
get any spikes.
What do you want
to use first?
I'm gonna use
the portable gateway.
It's just another interpretation
of the spirit box,
but it has an echo.
It eliminates some of
the white noise,
gives the spirits
opportunity to speak.
Okay.
Was someone killed
over here?
Are we standing close
to where you hung, sir?
Were you running
for your life?
Do you have anything to do with
the activity in this house?
Do you know who does?
I can't believe that's
going off right now.
That's crazy.
That sounded like
a little kid.
Is a little boy
with us right now?
We want to know
if he's with us.
Man.
"look down there, ma."
I heard that.
Look down where?
The tunnel?
"yes."
it really does sound like we're
communicating with a little boy.
Can you tell us who is
scaring garry and lee?
Are the innkeepers' spirits
lingering here
on the property
or in the house?
Touch the device.
My god,
look how crazy it went.
Do you want our help
while we're here to investigate?
Touch the device.
So, that's confirmation,
right there.
Can you tell us your name,
little boy?
I wonder if he's,
like, scared?
You don't have to
hide anymore.
It got really quiet.
I think the little boy
is just nervous --
too nervous and scared
to come through,
and communicate with us.
Yeah.
While sean and kris continue
to search for evidence,
inside, matt, eric,
and califf investigate
where the ghost loop
lures lee out of her bed,
and pushes her
down the stairs.
It's right
around here.
She starts feeling
this violent push.
Here. 0.3.
0.3.
Alright, eric.
Talk to them, baby.
- Where are you?
Come to me
with what you got.
Push me.
You know, it may be
that it's too early.
This thing comes out
in the middle of the night,
and wakes her up.
That's a good point.
I've got my back turned
towards these steps.
Where are you?
So you can try to hide all you
want, but we will find you.
I feeling like something's
behind me right now.
2.4.
You don't want to pick
on a dude, do you?
You want to pick on
this scared woman.
I'm gonna lay down.
I definitely had this
incredibly worrying feeling
that they were going to be
pushed down the stairs.
Where's this entity
that violently pushes lee
on the steps?
"it's on the stairs."
The spirit hunters
are in clear spring, maryland,
where lee is being pushed down
her stairs by a ghost loop.
I could be hurt.
It could be fatal.
At the edge
of the property,
sean and kris contact
a little boy who died long ago
when the house
was a tavern.
That sounded like
a little kid.
Is a little boy with us
right now?
Man.
Meanwhile,
eric, califf, and matt
investigate the location
of the ghost loop.
Where is this entity
that violently pushes lee
on the steps?
"it's on the stairs."
the back of my head is, like,
it's a headache right now.
- Are you good?
- It's like shots of a headache.
Speak to us.
You want to push me
down the staircase?
I was just
standing there.
That's a coward's move.
You want to push somebody down
the stairs, call us out by name.
"matt."
that said "matt."
That sounded like
it said "matt."
do you like me laying
on this side of the bed?
Hold this.
Alright. This is where
lee hears you.
Who are you?
Where's the kid?
Kid?
Yeah. Where's the kid?
That sounded
like a kid.
"open the door."
- "open the door."
what door?
I'm gonna go back
this way, guys.
What door are
you talking about?
Nothing back here.
Yeah. Just the living room.
No doors in here.
Alright.
So, we're looking for a door.
It was remodeled, so --
top to bottom.
We get told by a spirit
to find a door,
which, always odd
to be directed by things
from the afterlife.
Before the renovation,
this,
where we're standing,
was a porch.
And I believe that this area,
right here, was the door.
Check over there.
There's a lot of cavities.
There's a secret
passage or something.
Yeah, dude. That's kind of
what I'm looking for.
You guys looked up here?
I mean, it's a big fireplace.
There's no door, right?
I'm not seeing anything.
Yeah. I don't think
there's anything here.
I think it's a bust, guys.
Yeah.
I mean, maybe just one
more walk through, and...
I mean, I guess.
- Hey.
- What? What?
Get this
out of the way.
Dude. Hold on.
I mean,
it kind of blends in.
Hold on. Here we go.
Holy ****.
Are you kidding me?
Holy ****
dude.
That's a stairwell
going straight up, boys.
My god.
Let's go.
Here. Let's go.
This has got to be it.
we find a door
that leads up to the attic.
It was incredibly
unsettling,
and not something
I'm very fond of at this point.
What the hell?
you alright?
Yeah.
Something went like that.
You say you just got pinched?
Swear to god.
Lift it up. Lift it up.
Lift it up.
There's no marks, right?
Where? Show me.
No.
It was right here.
Right here?
Yep.
It just looks like a pinch.
That seems like a really kid
thing to do.
Yeah. That's what
I was thinking.
Is this the little boy?
Is this the room
you wanted us to go to?
That sounded like
a little kid.
Hey, little one.
You can talk to us.
You don't have to be afraid.
We're here to help you.
Do you need
to be set free?
"release."
do you need
to be released?
Do you want
Which one of us do you feel most
comfortable communicating with?
Me?
What about matt?
My god.
It literally just said,
"here you go, matt."
hey, little boy,
are you here?
Are you good?
Little kid just said, "no."
dude, they are talking now.
I think he was afraid
because we were all standing up.
Tell us your name,
little guy.
What did that say?
I heard
"albert" very clear.
Is that your name?
Albert?
"albert."
knowing that there's a child
that's lost here,
it makes me sad.
We're gonna have to find out
more tomorrow night.
Yeah.
We've got a giant,
giant pile of questions,
and very few answers,
right now.
With the preliminary
investigation over,
califf explains how
lee and garry's house
may have been used
on the underground railroad.
He meets with
lanesha debardelaben.
The underground railroad.
What was it?
The underground railroad
was literally
a network of support
for freedom seekers
during the period
of american slavery.
It was a collection of people
and places, homes,
churches for african americans
who were escaping slavery.
Some estimates state
over 100,000 freedom seekers
escaped to the free states
and canada by 1850.
Then, the government introduced
the fugitive slave act.
Once the
fugitive slave act passed,
it became profitable
for americans
to capture freedom seekers,
and to return them to slavery.
And so, there was often
financial gain
for sometimes
tricking freedom seekers
into thinking that
they were safe,
and being helped,
when in actuality,
they were being betrayed.
When lee and garry's home
was a tavern in the 1860s,
it was rumored to be a stop
on the railroad.
But the tavern owners
at the time,
sarah and joseph kinsell,
sold the freedom seekers
back into slavery.
Califf speaks to local historian
david wiles.
Hi. I'm david.
How are you?
Pleasure to meet you, david.
Let's go inside.
Do you know any of the history
about that particular location?
A little bit.
The house was build
by joseph kinsell.
He had 16 slaves that he used
to build the house,
and then, afterwards, he sold
all the slaves, but kept one.
Is there anything special
about that one particular slave
that he kept?
I don't know, other than
his name was albert.
And nothing more
about it,
except that he was kept
in the family.
I can't believe this.
I'm blown away.
Albert is the name
of the little boy spirit
we heard in the attic.
Tell us your name,
little guy.
"albert."
albert, a few years later,
did die,
and he was buried in one
of the caves behind the house.
There's a lot of caves
in the area,
because of all
the limestone.
Is there anything else
that you think I should know
about this town,
as far as that property,
the stretch of road?
It is well known in the area
for being haunted.
How far back does that go?
Do you know?
Well, I heard it
from my grandparents.
So, they were born
in the 1890's.
I mean, it was always
passed down that,
"that house is haunted."
so, this house
has a history?
The house just saw endless
activity of stagecoaches
and covered wagons.
But you also had the mixture
of good and bad travelers,
and card games, and whiskey.
There was a story that there
was a card fight, or something,
and there was a murder
in the house at one time.
There was a murder
in the house?
In the house.
In clear spring, maryland,
the spirit hunters have been
following a lead
their ghost loop
might be connected
to a little boy
from the
underground railroad.
Tell us your name,
little guy.
I heard "albert."
But after speaking with
local historian david wiles,
lee and garry's home that was
originally a tavern
built in 1803 might have
more secrets to divulge.
There was a murder
in the house at one time.
in the house?
Odd, but they say
that the dead man
is still buried
under the front door.
The person
that was murdered
is buried under the front door
of that property.
That's the story that that
was always passed down, yes.
There's just no details.
It's just a story that's
been in the area forever.
Sean and kris asked lee and
garry about the rumored murder.
There was a traveler.
He stayed here
when this was an inn.
And the tavern keeper
and his wife got him drunk,
and killed him, and buried him
under the kitchen floor,
under a stone
that's under the kitchen floor.
According to local folklore,
the innkeepers had murdered
the traveler
for the gold he brought back
from the territory.
But they never found it.
So, there is a body possibly
buried under the home,
and gold that was buried on the
property that nobody's found.
Right.
That's the legend.
That's the story.
With this new lead
pointing to the innkeepers,
kris, sean, and eric returned
to the site of the ghost loop.
Alright, guys,
I have an idea.
Want to set it up
on the stairs.
Yep.
Are we communicating
with the man
that was murdered
by the innkeepers?
Are we communicating
with the innkeepers?
This is incredible.
Direct line of communication.
You'd think it would be
the murdered man that was here,
but it's the innkeepers.
Maybe they're still
looking for the gold.
Is that why you bring lee
to the stairs here?
Because you want to bring her to
that moment that you murdered,
when it was a tavern,
for your gold?
Is that why you bring the lee
to the stairs here?
- "my gold."
my god.
- My god.
Holy ****.
Said "my gold."
this area, right here,
is where the tavern was.
They got him drunk.
They murdered him for his gold,
and then buried his body
somewhere on this property,
under this house.
That's incredible.
It's all coming together now.
Do you want us
to find your gold?
Touch the device.
Interesting.
Maybe he doesn't want
anyone to find it.
Do you not want anyone to find
your gold, because it's yours?
My gosh.
Do you know of the little boy,
the african american boy?
Is he here in the house
with you?
Touch the device.
Is he with matt
and califf outside?
- Wow.
Little boy, did you communicate
with us in the house?
Are you out here
with us right now?
You can use my energy,
as well, little boy.
Only the little boy.
How are you feeling?
You alright?
You need a minute?
Talk to me.
I'm just --
dude, I'm sorry. ****
what's going on?
I just asked him to use
my energy, man.
I just, it's sad, dude.
It's a hopeless feeling.
Let's go down.
God.
That was emotional, man.
My god.
It was wrong.
It was gross.
It was a feeling -- like I said,
it's a feeling I don't ever,
ever want to feel again.
It was bad, dude.
It was bad.
What?
I don't think the little boy's
out here right now.
I do not.
Are you the innkeepers?
Make that go off
if you are.
Back away.
Do you want to harm
lee and garry?
Are you the ones pushing
them down the stairs?
back away.
Back away.
Is your name joseph?
Or is this sarah?
dude. My god.
This is the most intelligent
rem pod action
that we've gotten
in a while.
Ask if joseph's here
again, dude.
Joseph's got to be here.
Sarah, is joseph with you?
Look.
fire up the spirit box.
Dude.
Okay.
Joseph, sarah ann,
are you guys with us?
You talked to us
on the rem pod.
Bro!
It said "sarah."
it said "sarah"
in a female voice.
Do you know what's
happening in the house?
"murder"?
Murder.
The spirit hunters
discover a murder was committed
at lee and garry's house
by tavern keepers
sarah and joseph kinsell,
in the early 1800s.
There was a traveler,
and the tavern keeper
and his wife killed him,
and buried him
under the kitchen floor.
Later, joseph died
falling drunk off a wagon,
while sarah died of natural
causes 30 years later.
Now, sarah and joseph
are trapped in a ghost loop.
They whisper
to lure lee out,
so they can push her
down the stairs,
obsessed with protecting
the missing stolen gold.
Is that why you bring lee
to the stairs here?
- "my gold."
they murdered him
for his gold
and then, buried his body
somewhere on this property.
It's all coming
together, now.
Outside, matt and califf
keep up contact with sarah.
Sarah, did you do
the killing?
my god.
She was more evil
than him, bro.
That's what
I'm sensing.
Do you still want
to kill?
Suddenly,
the spirit goes silent.
Let's get the hell
out of here, dude.
Back at the house,
sean, eric, and kris,
investigate
where the spirits
whispering begins
the ghost loop.
How did you murder
this man?
Was he shot?
Was he pushed
down the stairs?
My god.
Do you regret
murdering that man?
Touch the device.
Did you mean to kill him
'cause you wanted his gold?
Wow.
That's insane.
Are you still looking
for this man's gold?
Touch the device
on the table.
what was that?
What was that?
It just knocked
on the table.
****
okay.
Is that sarah?
"yeah."
wow.
It said "yep,"
and then, that went off.
Sarah, do you
want our help?
She also needs
our help, guys.
Dude, it's going crazy.
Now that all the evidence
is in,
the team discusses
how to move forward.
The elements of gold
in our story, here, guys,
it's so prevalent.
It's so profound.
I know that we caught
"my gold."
we all heard it.
- "my gold."
they murdered the man
for his gold,
and they really didn't have
any remorse about it.
Did you mean to kill him
because you wanted his gold?
Wow.
I mean, I kind of feel like
sarah's the culprit, here.
Okay.
I'm going with that, too.
We were up there
on the hill,
and we were talking
to the rem pod,
and we literally asked,
"did you do this?"
sarah, did you
do the killing?
we were in
the dining room.
We were asking,
"are you responsible
sarah, for the push
on the stairs?"
sarah, are you the one trying
to push lee down the stairs?
126.4.
Stop it.
Holy.
What if they think lee
is after their gold,
and that is why she's feeling
that push down the stairs.
Like, now they're
after her, as well.
Are you still looking
for this man's gold?
Touch the device
on the table.
what was that?
It just knocked
on the table.
And it's interesting.
We actually asked
if she wanted our help,
and the thing went crazy.
Sarah, do you want
our help?
40.9.
She also needs
our help, guys.
How does she
want our help?
Does she want our help
to be released
or she want to help
finding this gold.
- Right.
- Exactly.
History backs that.
In fact, sarah ann and joseph
kept a slave --
a young boy named albert.
He sold all the slaves,
but kept one.
He was kept in the family.
His name was albert and...
When we got to the attic,
it said, "albert",
through the spirit box.
Tell us your name,
little guy.
So, they kept this boy,
they treated him
as one of his own,
but for the time,
if people came over or came by,
you couldn't have him present,
so they'd hide him
in the tunnel.
And something we also got
during that night,
right, when I was standing
over the area of the tunnel.
It's crazy.
And I'm like,
"did you hide down here?"
is this where you went
to go hide all the time?
"I did."
albert died in the tunnel
under the house.
I mean, there was
a possibility
that albert was treated
awfully by these people.
I mean, we saw how they treated
the other 16 slaves
that were on their property --
sold them back to their owners.
I feel like the little boy
is ready.
He knows
our intentions.
He knows that we're here
to help him.
It's been a really long time.
I think he's ready.
Well, think about it, he's been
kind of a guiding light
for us all, right?
He's been the one
showing us to places,
helping us out, trying
to figure out more answers.
So, I think that he wants us
to put this puzzle together,
so that way,
he can go.
There's no doubt that albert is
attached to the innkeepers,
who clearly don't want
to leave this place.
If we get rid
of the innkeepers,
then, we'll be able
to release albert.
It all makes sense now.
It really does.
Leading us tonight
to our trigger
and environment room.
And eric.
What stands out
the most for me,
these innkeepers are here
for the gold.
So, I have a box
with a bag of gold in it.
Considering what we have
for a trigger environment,
why don't we bury the gold
somewhere on the property,
and see how they interact
with us while we do it.
'cause obviously,
that's a huge piece,
and core element
to what's going on here.
Alright, it's our trigger
environment evening, guys.
Let's end the ghost
loop of activity
that garry and lee
are experiencing,
so they can
live peacefully.
the main purpose of this night
is to lure all the spirits in.
For this trigger environment,
I'm transforming the dining room
into a tavern
from the 1800s.
there's various different
ash trays and bottles.
There's the cash register
in there.
Most importantly
for this case,
I'm bringing in
two bags of gold.
I guarantee these items
will lure
sarah and joseph
into the open.
Albert, can you
touch my hand again?
Hold my hand.
my god. He's literally
grabbing your hand.
The spirit hunters
have identified
the ghost loop as
sarah and joseph kinsell --
murderous innkeepers who are
still searching for the gold
they killed for.
Refusing to move on,
the kinsells are also holding
back a little boy spirit,
albert,
that they kept in real life.
Albert has been aiding
the spirit hunters,
so he can move on.
So, eric has built
a trigger environment
to emulate the tavern
from the 1850's,
to lure the spirits in,
so the team can
cross them all over.
Amazing job with this
trigger environment.
It literally
looks like a tavern.
It's what these spirits think,
that it really is a tavern.
So, let's see
if they interact with us
as if we were one of the patrons
of the tavern tonight.
Hell, yeah.
Guys, I'm ready to help
lee and garry.
Let's break this ghost loop.
sarah and joseph,
we're looking for you
to communicate
with you tonight.
Can you please
come forward?
Sarah,
are you here with us?
We know what you did the night
that you met the traveler.
You murdered him
for his gold.
"they're inside."
we have some gold sitting
over there in that chair.
How do you like
the look of that?
I have your gold.
It's right here.
I'm taking all of it.
Right. So, we're going to put
your gold back on the table.
This is for you.
as soon as we put
the gold down on the table.
Sarah, joseph, are you still
looking for this gold
that you took
from this man?
Can you make
that device light up.
my god.
I mean, it's clear
why they're still here.
Sarah's presence
is so strong.
Sarah, are you responsible
for this man's murder?
she has no problem
admitting that at all.
She is a bigger part
than what we even know.
If there are other people that
you've killed, touch the device.
That was
probably joseph.
He's here with us.
"she's mad at me?"
what is she
so mad at?
These spirits are reacting to
not only us,
but to each other,
on the other side.
Sarah feels guilty.
She probably does.
Maybe joseph didn't fall off
that carriage when he died.
Maybe he got
a little...
Push.
My, god, dude.
Are you serious?
My god, dude.
Okay. Okay.
I had an epiphany,
we're in here talking.
So, I started thinking, what if
sarah was an awful person,
and maybe, when he was drinking
on that carriage,
he didn't fall off.
Maybe he got a little...
Push.
that's going off.
We're talking about it.
She hears us.
Alright.
Let's get back in there.
Go, go, go.
My god.
Sarah. Thank you.
Please back away.
We have a question
for you.
my god.
Maybe she is upset because she
accidentally killed her husband.
Sarah, did you accidentally
kill your husband?
It wasn't an accident.
She did it on purpose.
Sarah, did you mean
to kill your husband?
Are you serious, dude?
My god.
I was starting to feel
something.
Sarah, how did you
kill your husband?
What did you do?
"pushed him."
"pushed him.'
With the entire team
in the room,
the spirit energy escalates.
What happened to albert?
My god.
It just felt like
somebody pushed into me.
Albert, did you just
push into kris?
- Kris.
- It just said "kris."
albert, if you're here,
can you touch the device?
my god, dude.
Albert, is that you?
Albert.
Right by you, kris.
Don't move.
The spirit hunters have drawn
out the conspiring murderers,
sarah and joseph kinsell
to the trigger environment.
But they've also
brought out albert,
the little boy who has been
guiding the team along the way,
and desperately wants
to cross over.
Right behind you, kris.
Don't move.
My gosh.
My god.
It's a little kid.
It's right there.
It's right there behind you.
- Albert.
- My gosh.
Right where your hand is.
Albert, can you touch
my hand again?
Hold my hand.
my god. He's literally
grabbing your hand.
My --
my god.
It's gone.
My god, guys.
I just find it just to be
a very touching situation,
just knowing that
I'm able to help him.
He's ready, he's willing,
and he wants to go now.
Alright guys,
we've got to figure out
how to break this loop.
Be careful.
Well, keep in mind joseph
isn't gonna go easily.
Right? No. I think him and sarah
both are unwilling.
They're both still here,
having no closure,
because they can't
find this.
So, what you want to do
about that, matt?
I want to bury this.
All of the gold
we brought for them.
Absolutely.
Of course.
Alright. We're gonna go outside,
bury this gold.
I want the little boy,
albert, joseph, and sarah
you want to go to the light.
You're ready. All of you.
We know what you did,
but we're not here to judge you.
You have to trust us.
You have to come forward.
It's time to let go of
the human life that you lived.
Up here, matt.
Yes, sir.
Right where we communicated
with them last night.
Do you want
to cross over?
"yes."
follow our voice.
Joseph and sarah ann,
this is now your gold.
We're going to bury it
right here.
Califf and matt hope that,
by using the gold as bait,
it will appease sarah and joseph
enough to cross them over.
This is the last call
at the bar.
Your gold is found, so come get
it, and leave this property.
Albert, you can take my hand,
and I can help you.
It's working.
Is everyone here,
and ready to go?
- "let's go."
our father,
who art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done,
on earth as in heaven.
For each one
of the lives you took,
and for every bad thing
that you did...
...I still hope
you find peace.
Give us, this day,
our daily bread,
and forgive us
our trespasses,
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us all from evil.
Holy mary,
mother of god,
pray for us sinners, now until
the hour of our death, amen.
- "amen."
- "amen!"
at the same time!
My god.
"thank you."
I mean,
I'm speechless.
Feels lighter in here.
Like, I really --
I think this is over.
I truly feel that.
good work, my brother.
It's quite the mystery
that you to moved into, here.
We want to know how
things went, naturally.
What we truly believe,
why you've been lured out
to those stairs
so many evenings,
is because you've been
hearing these whispers.
And what those
whispers are,
are conspiring voices
of that night
they plotted to kill
this man for his gold.
And that's what ultimately led
us to our trigger environment.
Eric actually built this
phenomenal trigger environment.
We went back in time,
into the 1800s,
and we built
this tavern.
So, did they cross over?
Yes. We absolutely believe
that happened.
- Fantastic.
-100%.
Fantastic.
The most amazing experience,
when we were in the
trigger environment,
while these spirits
were being crossed over,
they actually ended the prayer
with us in sync.
They said "amen"
with us.
My gosh.
'cause we've been asked
if it's haunted.
And so, we would --
we would like
to truthfully say "no."
right. And now,
you can finally do that.
Thank you so much for helping
these spirits move on.
Thank you for giving us
peace of mind.
I'm going to miss
the little boy a little bit,
but I'm happy to know
that he's also moved on.
I can't tell you
what a relief it is.
We are so appreciative.
Thank you.
Lee is the most precious thing
in my life, and I --
and I'm grateful
that your team
was able to send
these spirits packing.