Eddie!
Eddie! Stop! Stop right there.
Eddie, no! No!
Hey no, no! Eddie! Eddie!
Ed Eddie! Eddie!
Eddie.
I got you. I got you, buddy.
I'm right here. I'm right here.
What the hell
got into you, buddy?
I have a question.
Why would a guy
come to a bar
and order a club soda?
I don't know.
Uh, it's 10:00 a.m.?
That doesn't stop people
at airports.
Oh, so you've been watching me?
No.
You are sitting
underneath the TV,
and I've been
watching that.Ah.
But it did
have me wonder,
because there are
a lot of places a guy could go
to get a glass
of carbonated water...Mm.
...but you came to a bar,
and so you want to be drinking,
but instead you're staring
at a cup of club soda.
Are you, are you
the beverage police?
Yes, I am.
And I'm writing you up.
You, uh...
I-I do, I do, uh, drink alcohol,
too, sometimes.
Would you like to sit?
Yeah. Okay.Yeah?
Please.If you insist.
Are we gonna drink alcohol?
I mean, it's not the airport,
but I'll give it a shot
if you want, yeah.All right.
Hi.
What can I get for you?
Hi. He's gonna
have an Irish Mule,
and I...Wha
Hold on. Uh,
what's a...
what's an Irish Mule?Oh, no.
You'll like it. It's good.
Maybe I want a Scotch.
Maybe this isn't about
what you want and maybe
this is about what you need.
I'd listen to the lady.
Sounds like she knows
what she's talking about.
Yeah, she does, but, um,
I-I don't even know
what is in an Irish Mule.
He's always like this.
I'm sure he's always
like this.
The ginger
in the ginger beer
is gonna help improve
your brain function.
Which will maybe bring you back
to the land of the living.
And the whiskey, well,
that is nothing less
than a time-honored tradition
to elevate one's mood.
Aha.
Mm-hmm.
Two Irish Mules, then.Actually, that's
too sweet for me.
I'm gonna have a Scotch.
Neat.
You got it.
You're very funny.
Mm-hmm. What's your name?
Oh, God, that's so cliché.
Really, you're gonna meet
someone at a bar,
and that's your opening line?
I just, I feel like
you're the type of guy
who comes up with something
more original.
I-I generally would be
that type of guy.
Maybe I get a drink in me first
and that'll help.
Hmm. I'll allow it.
You will. Nice.Yes.
Nice. This will be
a two-way street.
I will not ask you your name,
I will not ask you what you do.
And...
we will think
of only interesting
and original things
to talk about.Okay.
We will do that, um...
Right after you take that.
It's-it's a work thing. I-I
promise I'll be right back.
Mm.If you touch my Irish Mule,
I'll, um, I'll do
something terrible. Okay?
Give me one second.
Hey. Um, I'm
just, quick question
um, how am I supposed to have
a couple personal days
if you keep calling me
all the time?
Relax.
It's not a work thing.
I'm just checking in with you.
I'm-I'm doing fine.
But, hey, I-I did,
I called Adam again, a-and it
went straight to voice mail.
All right, so I'm thinking,Mm-hmm.
usually it rings a couple times,
then it goes to voice mail.
So, when-when in life
do you turn your phone off?
I don't know. Uh, when I'm on
a plane, I guess.
That's right. Right,
so maybe he's on his way back
from wherever he was.
Yeah, it's possible.
Hang on. You're
okay, you're okay.
It's all right.
How's Eddie doing?
Uh, he seemed
a little off when I left.
No, he's worse than "off."
He took off from the house, ran
into traffic on Kalanianaole.
I just pulled him out.
You need a hand?No, no, no, I'm good.
I got the vet
coming by pretty soon.
Is that the vet,
the nice vet lady
that you took out on a date
and it went really great
and you didn't ask her out again
because you're insane
or something?
Yes, her. Listen, uh...
after I'm done here,
I'm gonna go
grab a bite to eat.
You want to join me?
Uh, no, I don't want
to have a bite with you.
In fact, I am sitting
at a bar right now
with a very pretty lady.
What are you doing talking
to me? Are you crazy?
Listen to me, Danny, don't blow
this very rare opportunity
that a w a female wants
to converse with you.
Get this
she actually came up to me.
Oh, wait, is she a bartender?
'Cause you know that
she has to talk to you.
If that's the case,
that's her job.
Tell Eddie I love him.
Okay? Goodbye.
Very sorry. Sorry, sorry.
It's fine.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's good.
Okay.
Ah. Ahoy.
All right. Down the hatch.All right.
Cheers.
Yep.
Mmm.
That's a lot.
It's, uh, it's good.
So, how-how are you liking
the island so far?
So far?
Mm-hmm.
What makes you think
I'm new here?
Oh, well, the outfit, for one.
Which I like very much.
It's very classy.
You look fantastic.
But it's very
East Coast.
And you look like, uh, you know,
you'd be gainfully employed,
but, uh, we're at a bar,
not an office.
Thank you.So here-here's
what I'm thinking.
I'm thinking either you, um,
you got a new gig,
flew out here for it,
it hasn't started yet,
or you-you know,
you're doing, like, half-days
while you, while y-you get
yourself settled.
How am I doing?
Warm? Hot? Cold?
Yeah, I think
you're pretty warm.
Thanks.
So are you, like...
you're, like,
a detective or something?
Something like that.
Can I tell you things?
Can I be honest?
Please.I'm not,
I'm not too sure
about this place.
Not
The, um, the island.
Ah. I understand.
And, uh, I felt the same way
when I first got here,
but it grows on you.
Right. I'll believe that.
Mm-hmm.
That was, uh...
Yeah, it was.
For the record not that, uh,
you're keeping a
record or anything...
...but, uh, I've
never done
this before.
Yeah. Me, neither.
Oh, that's good.
Um...
I don't know, if you're up
for it sometime, maybe
I'd like to take you out to
dinner or something like that?
Take me out to dinner?Yeah, something
like that.
Yes, I would, um,
I would like that very much.
Good.
Just, um...
What-what are
you doing?
I'm calling a Lyft.
Oh, why you calling a Lyft?
I think, I think I could
give you a ride home.
Oh, you could give me a ride?Mm-hmm.
You don't, you don't
have to do that.
I know, I'd like to do that.
Uh, and I had one sip
of that drink.
Yes. I know,
you did not like that.
It was okay.
I guess I'm gonna get
in a strange man's car.
You are gonna get in a strange
man's midsize rental.
Wow.Yeah.
A midsize rental.Yeah. But it came
with a beautiful, uh,
tropical air freshener.
Wow. Uh, you know,
on second thought,
I'll probably just take the bus.
Shut up.
Whoa, hey.
What?You trying
to get busted?
Let me just make sure
the coast is clear.
Frickin' amateur hour over here.
Sorry, sorry.
Hey, I don't, I don't want
to, uh, I don't want to pry,
but, uh, why Haleiwa?
Oh.
I don't know.
Uh, my friend lives there...
Oh....with her husband
and these rotten kids.
I'm just staying there
until I can find a room
of my own in Honolulu.
Uh, how's that going for you,
the search?
Oh, it's terrible.
It's the worst. Um...
This place I saw the other week,
it was pretty cool
'cause it's about
a half a block away
from where Benny Agbayani went
to high school.
Okay, stop everything right now.
Did you just name-drop
late-90s Mets outfielder
Benny Agbayani?
Wow.
You got that reference.
Yeah Me? I'm-I'm
the Hawaiian Punch?
I was at the game.
No, you were not. You were not.Yes, I was.
Don't No. No.I'm telling you,
it was the craziest thing
I've ever seen live.
I'm telling you,
it was, it was, it was nuts.
That's crazy.
Thought it was the third out.
Yeah.Ah, I knew
you were from the East Coast.
You're from the East Coast.
Okay, I think that
you are from... Jersey.
Yes, I am. Yes, I am.
I love Jersey.
That makes two of us.
Well, I'm from Massapequa.
All right. Strong Island.
But I love Passaic.
My-my favorite aunt lived there.
Okay.Yeah, it was the best.
I'd go see her
and we'd watch R-rated movies
and we'd order sausage pizza
from Romeo's.
Romeo's. Well, your aunt
has very good taste.
He sees us, right?
Hey...
Hold on.
Oh, my God!
Doc, hey. Thanks so much.
Uh, come in, come in.
Um, I know you don't
usually do house calls.
Yeah, no, I don't,
but it sounded urgent.
Where is he?He's in the kitchen.
Small confined space, right?
Like you said.
Yeah, good. Oh,
well, uh whoa.
Probably, it's...
probably best if I conduct
my initial exam without you.
It's just that dogs, they pick
up on our anxiety and...
Yeah, I got a little bit
of that today.Yeah.
Um, just so you know,
uh, what's been going on lately,
has been, uh, bizarre.
I mean, he's not himself.How so?
What do you mean?Well, he's kind of s
he's skittish and jumpy,
he's, like,
on high alert all the time.
And you know Eddie.
He's a relaxed guy.
Right? I mean,
at the moment, I can't,
I can't close a drawer
in the, in the bedroom
without him
totally freaking out.
And this morning, the door
was cracked a little bit.
He bolted.
He's never done that before.
He ended up in the middle
of Kalanianaole.
Almost got us both killed
pulling him out of that traffic.
Well, uh, how about I
go take a look at him?
Yeah, yeah; yeah, yeah. Okay.
Hey, there, Eddie.
Remember me?
Stitched you up
a little while back?
All right... it's maybe not
the most pleasant of memories.
Right? I thought we had a
little bit of a bond, hmm?
Now let's see what's going on
with you, bud.
Come on. Let's see, bud...
Good boy...
All right. Let's just check
those pearly whites...
All right.
Good boy.
Uh, hey...
Look at me.
You okay?
Yeah...
Look at me.
Uh, it hurts...
All right.
It hurts.
Okay.
I'm gonna get my
phone, all right?
Hey.
Mm-hmm?Where's your phone?
Uh, it's in my, um,
it's in my bag.
Oh, God,
my legs...
God, it hurts.
Okay.
All right.
We got no service.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna go up
to the road,
try to get a signal, okay?Mm-hmm...
All right?
Okay.
We're gonna be fine,
all right? I promise.
Sorry.
Huh?Mm...
Seven-two-four.
Huh?
The, um...
the last three digits...
...of the plate
were seven, two, four.
Don't worry about
that right now, okay?You have to tell...
you have
to tell the police,
so that he doesn't
hurt anyone.
He already hurt somebody.
Just...
just breathe.
It's gonna be okay,
I promise, all right?
Be right back.
Seven-two-four, right?
Got it.Seven-two-four.
The door's jammed.
Hey.Hey.
He's showing signs of
post-traumatic stress.
PTS?
Okay, h I know
military working dogs
can get PTS, but he's never
shown a hint of that.
Maybe so. But what he's
exhibiting right now,
hyper-vigilance,
an elevated heart
rate, dilated pupils;
those are
telltale signs.Doc, this doesn't
make any sense.
Uh, look, after the Marines,
he was with the DEA for years.
Why now?
Look, Steve, you and I both know
PTS is varied; it's complex.
We understand very little
of how it affects humans,
much less dogs.
I don't know;
in my opinion,
I think that Eddie must have
some long-buried trauma
that for some reason
has just resurfaced.
But I don't know. I'm not
an expert in this, so...
sorry I... can't
be more helpful.
No, no, you've been
plenty helpful, thank you.
I'm, I'm just, you know...
Thank you.
I mean...
I-I got a place
to start now, right?Yeah.
Um, Emma,
before you leave?
I feel like I should probably
bring up the, uh...
How how you never
called me back?
Yes. That.
And, uh...
first of all, I'm really sorry.
I just want to let you know
that, uh,
it wasn't because
I didn't like you,
'cause I did, I do.
I mean...
I have always had a problem
balancing the job with my life,
and historically,
uh, my personal life always
gets the short end of the stick,
and I guess I just wanted
to let you know that, um...
it wasn't a you issue.
Uh... I'm the problem.
Typically, when men say
something like that to me,
I think about
which shin I should
kick.
But...
I don't know, for some reason,
when you say it, I believe you.
Well, you should,
'cause it's the truth.
Yeah. Hey, look,
there's no hard feelings.
'Cause I'm seeing someone.
That's great.Yeah, it turns out
there are some good guys
on those godforsaken apps, so...
I'm legitimately happy for you.
You deserve it.
Thanks.
Anyway, I don't want
to hold you hostage.
Thank you.
Bye, Steve.
Oh, and keep me
posted on Eddie.
I will, I promise.
Thanks again, Emma.Yeah.
Big man on campus.
How's Parents Weekend? Expensive.
Renee's got me
running all over the place
running errands
while she's helping Will
decorate his
new off-campus apartment.
Uh-huh.Boy, these kids now.
Did you know, when I went away
to school,
you know what my parents
gave me?
A ratty old blanket and a roll
of quarters for the pay phone
and the laundromat.
Now, Father of the Year,
aka yours truly,
is going out to buy Will
a flat screen TV and a portable
air conditioning unit.
Come on, you love spoiling
that kid, you know it.
Yeah, I know, but let that be
our little secret.
Listen, the reason
I'm calling you
is because I got a text
from Tani, and she said
that Eddie's in a bad way.
He's not doing too good.
The vet just left.
She said she thinks it's PTS,
but she's no expert.
Well, fret not, pal of mine,
because I happen to know one.
Will played high school baseball
with the son
of a resident Army veterinarian.
And his primary expertise
is in military working dogs.
Are you kidding me right now?
About Eddie?
Bite your tongue, man.
I love that dog,
so I reached out to him.
And he thinks he can help.
His name is Dr. Art Currin.
You'll find him at the
Veterinary Treatment Facility
at Fort Shafter.
And he's expecting you, too.
How about that?
Thank you so much, Lou.
I really appreciate this.
No problem, man.
Anything for that pup.
All right, I got to go.
I'm late for an argument.
Shh... you're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
Shh-shh-shh-shh-shh.
You were right
to bring him in.
Eddie is definitely
exhibiting signs of canine PTS.
He recently
suffer any trauma
in the field?
No. I mean, that's the thing.
He's been, he's been
with me for, uh,
couple years now, and
he's been exposed to, to
gunshots, to explosions,
uh, he's-he's never
had a bad reaction.
Before he came to me,
he was a DEA dog.
And then preceding that,
he was with a Marine unit
in Afghanistan.
I'm trying to
think what I
could have exposed him to.
I've had a lot going on
in my personal life.
I-I guess, uh...
It's killing me, Doc,
to think that maybe
I-I've exposed
him to something
that's, that's, that's
had this reaction.
I can tell you're hurting.
You shouldn't
beat yourself up.
It's not uncommon
for canine PTS
to stay dormant for weeks,
months, sometimes years;
lying dormant till something
sets it off.
That something can be a sound,
sight, smell.
Literally anything
can bring an old trauma
back to the surface.
My guess, this didn't happen
because of something
you exposed him to.
You would have noticed the signs
immediately if you had.
More likely, Eddie was alone
when the triggering
event happened;
in your home,
perhaps outside.
It's not your fault, Commander.
Now let's
talk treatment.Mm.
First, I'll administer
an anxiolytic
to help with
the underlying anxiety.
Honestly, the meds
are just a band-aid.
You're gonna have to figure out
exactly what triggered Eddie
and remove it
from his environment,
or, frankly, his condition's
only gonna get worse.
That said,
you can't know what you need
to remove until you determine
the root cause of this trauma.
Right.
Lou tells me you're
a seasoned investigator.
Something like that, yeah.
It's time to investigate this.Understood.
Eddie's first handler...
he was killed in action
in Afghanistan.
You know any details about how?
No.
Well, then I'd start there.
Steve. You got
me and Quinn.
How's the little man?
He's all right.
He's a little quiet.
I think it's the meds.
So the Army vet was helpful?
He was. He was very helpful.
But, uh, Eddie's not
out of the woods yet.
We still need to figure out
what triggered it.
So where do we start, boss?
We start by turning back
the clock.
Eddie's first handler
was killed in action
in Afghanistan.
I want to know everything
that happened that day.
Okay?
The doctor seems to think
that his trauma is rooted there,
so let's dig around
and see if we can find
anything actionable.
If we can't,
look into his DEA history.
But my gut says
that the doctor's right, and his
trauma is linked to the death
of his old handler.
That was a one-of-a-kind bond,
and it got broken.
In the meantime,
I don't want to leave him alone,
so if you guys
could do me a favor,
I want you to go talk
to Colonel O'Donnell at MCBH.
He should be able
to put us in contact
with Eddie's old unit. On it.
We'll send you an update ASAP
as long as you give Eddie
a belly rub from us.
Will do.
Hang in
there, buddy.
Okay. All right,
just relax, okay?
Here's what we're gonna do.
I just need to get you stable.
I'm gonna go
up the road
and I'm gonna flag down a car,
all right?
We're gonna take a look.
Okay?
Okay.
Let me see.
Okay, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
No, no, no, no, no.
I can't feel my l I can't
feel my leg, can't feel my leg.Sorry.
It hurts everywhere. There's
something wrong with my back.
Okay, all right, so look,
just breathe, focus on me.
Look at me. Everything's
gonna be okay, all right?
I'm just gonna
check you out
and see where else
you're hurt, okay?
Yeah, you do that.
You need to do that.All right.
Lean forward a little bit,
just a little bit.
Little bit,
little bit.
Okay, I see it.
Okay.
All right.
All right,
stay like that.
What is that? What is that?It's just a little cut.
What was that?
What is it? Is it bad?
It's bad.No. It's just a little cut.
Just, look it, look it,
I got to get it cleaned up,
and then we'll
be okay, all right?
Just tell me.
Just don't lie to me, please.
Don't lie to me now.
It's not good.
Okay?
It's a little bad,
but I'm gonna fix it, all right?
I'm gonna get you stable,
and everything's
gonna be okay.
You are gonna make it
through this. You understand?
Yeah.
You're looking for
personnel information
on the dog's old unit?Yes, sir.
Eddie, is it?
Correct.
Um, specifically,
we would be grateful to speak
with any of the Marines
that were on duty the day
that Eddie's handler was killed.
I understand.
Uh, Corporal Bollinger
was killed
in Farah Province
on July 9, 2013.
Of the unit on patrol,
two men died that day.
Another two are on
active missions
in classified locations,
thus unreachable.
But it looks as though
two Marines
might be available
to make contact.
That's great.
One has left the service.
He's now a firefighter
in Portland.
Uh, Maine, not Oregon.
And the other,
he was the unit's
radio operator.
He's currently stationed
at Marine Wing Liaison Kadena
at Kadena Air Base in Okinawa.
Great. Thank you
so much, Colonel.
Happy to help.Thank you.
I hope the warrior's
better soon.
Thank you, sir.
Absolutely.
Anything?
I'm looking.
I thought you said
this place grows on you.
It does. Do me a favor
and don't talk.
You got to save
your energy, okay?
There's so much blood.I know.
I'll take care of that
right now, okay?
Okay.Lean forward
for me. Breathe.Mm-hmm.
All right.
Lean back,
and good pressure on that, okay?
All right, we're gonna
take care of this now.
This is probably
gonna hurt,
but I got to stop this
bleeding, all right?
Okay, I got it.
Come on, come on, you're tough.
You're tough.
Look at me.
Stay with me, okay?
I'm scared.
I know you're scared,
but you don't have to be.
You're gonna be okay.
I'm right here, all right?I don't pray.
You don't have to pray.I should pray.
No, you don't have to pray
'cause I'm right here, okay?
All you got to do is hang tough.
All right? Look at me,
we're gonna get out of this
thing. I'm gonna go up there,
I'm gonna flag down a car,
we're gonna go home.
Okay? Promise.
I promise.
Don't get upset,
okay?
You know, since we're being
honest with each other, I, um,
something I didn't tell you
that I think I should.
You know, you said your aunt
used to take you to,
uh, to Romeo's.
I know Romeo's very well.
I actually got into
a-a fight in front of Romeo's
when I was in,
when I was in school
when I was a kid.
You serious right now?
Yeah. Seventh grade.
Seventh grade,
there was these two big
high school jerks
that were messing with my
friend, calling him fat 'cause
I don't know,
calling him butterball.
Well, was he fat?
Yeah, he was very fat.
You know, he was,
he was a big kid.
He used to pop zeppolis
like they were Tic Tacs.
Anyway, it doesn't justify
the ridicule, you know?
I agree with that.
What happened?
Why, I, uh, I, uh...
They were in high school.
They were big high school
basketball players.
They beat me up pretty good.
I got my ass kicked, you know.
You're a good guy.Thanks.
Just got a text from
the radio op, he should be ready
to Skype McGarrett
in a few minutes.
Cool.
Eddie okay?He's restless.
He's restless. McGarrett's
trying to settle him for a nap.
He did lap up some of the water
from the bowl
that I brought, though, so...
Oh, that's weird. Did you tell
him the water was for Eddie?
You want to talk about it?
I don't know.
I Okay, fine. Yeah. Um...
So I go upstairs, and
I'm-I'm thinking about Eddie,
and I'm-I'm worried about him.
I'm thinking about
all the terrible things
that have happened to him.
I'm thinking about
the trauma that
almost got him killed today.
And then I-I walked by
Junior's room...
Junior's not invincible either.
And now he's off on
his secret SEAL mission,
and I haven't
heard from him since
the morning that he left.
But, like, I'm-I'm-I'm trying
not to think about it.
Um... Just...
being in this house is...
doesn't make it easier.
You're right.
Junior's not invincible,
but he is tough as hell.
And I know that
he will do everything
that he can to get
back home safe,
back to the people
that he loves.
Hey. You okay?
Hi. Yeah.
I think he, uh, he's
finally sleeping, so...
Okay, this is him.
Okay, his name is
Sergeant Victor Michaels.
I brought him
up to speed.
Copy that.
Sergeant Michaels,
can you hear me?
Loud and clear, Commander.
Thank you very much for your
time today. I appreciate it.
Hey, I always got time
for Eddie.
Sorry to hear
what he's going through.
Yeah,
appreciate that.
We spoke with his doctor,
and the doctor said if we can
figure out what the-the
trigger is for him,
then maybe we can prevent this
from happening in the future.
We're pretty sure it's connected
to the death of his handler,
so and I'm very sorry
to ask this
'cause I know how hard it is
but anything you could
tell us about
that day, uh,
it'd be really helpful.
Of course.
That's not the kind of day
you forget.
As soon as we got out
of the Humvees,
I had that...
that eerie feeling.
You know the one,
like there was death
in the air.
The area was littered
with IEDs.
It felt like the whole place
could blow at any second.
Eddie, he had about
the best nose in the Corps.
That area was a straight-up
death trap.
All it took is
for one boot to take
one step out
of formation, and...
Suddenly I was on my back.
I remember
the first thing I saw
were purple flowers,
covered in blood that
I thought was mine.
And that's when
I spotted Eddie.
He looked injured,
but then he got up.
He had to find his handler.
Those two had a special bond.
Bollinger
was a good man.
I'm sure he was. I'm sorry.
Thank you, Commander.
I'm not sure
if any of that helps.I know, I...
I think it really does. Listen,
those purple flowers
you mentioned, you remember
what they were called?
Oh, yeah, they grew all over
the place in, uh, Farah.
It's that restharrow stuff.
Restharrow.
Well, thank you again, Sergeant.
Of course. And look,
you take care of that dog, sir.
Lord knows he took care of us.
I will.
See what I'm seeing?
If you're talking about
the look of a man
who's about to crack the code,
then that's an affirmative.
All right,
all right.
Hey. I need you to lean forward.
I'm gonna change
these dressings, okay?
Can I ask you something?Of course.
Why were you in that bar?
That's really what you want
to talk about right now?
If I can't be rescued,
I shall be entertained.
You are going
to be rescued, okay?
I was in that bar
because I was in a mood
because of my ex-wife.
Yeah, yeah, that'll do it.
How long you been
split up?
If I, uh, if I try to tell you
that whole story,
we'll both be dead
before I finish.
We were sort of trying to
work it out the last year or so.
Didn't take?
No, no.
We're better off as friends.Yeah.
I've been there.
Yeah? You got
some stories of your own?
Mm-hmm.
Really?
A lady never tells.
Ah.
It's a car.
No, no, no, no. You can't
leave me, you can't leave me.Hey, look at me,
look at me, look at me.
You're fine.You can't leave me,
you can't go.I'll stop the car,
we get an ambulance,
and then we go home, okay?
That's all, that's all.Please don't go.
Hey!
Stop!
Hey, hey!
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, wake up.
Wake up, wake up.
There you go.
Hey, I missed the car. Okay?
Okay.
It's not your fault.
Oh, thank you.
Mm-hmm. Are you
always this unlucky?
I was in that bar, wasn't I?
Come on.
Mm.
Let me check you out here.
Let me see.
All right, this is good.
Let me see your back.
Hey, you gotta stay awake
for me. Okay?
Stay awake.
You're out of towels.
It's all right.
It's gonna be okay.
Not of we don't
stop the bleeding.
I got this. Gonna...
All right, lean back.
Lean back.
Pressure.
You gotta keep pressure
on your back
and you're gonna be fine.
We're getting out of here. Okay?
All right?
Just breathe easy. Easy, okay?
Excuse me.
Hi.
Hello.
Can I help you?
We sure hope so.
I'm Tani Rey.
This is Quinn Liu.
We work with your neighbor,
Steve McGarrett.
I hope we're
not intruding.No, not at all.
Steve mentioned you're
a botany professor.
I am.
We came from central
Connecticut,
so this is paradise.
The biodiversity of flora here
is incredible.
90% of plant life
found in Hawaii
can't be found anywhere else
in the world.
Sorry. Uh, you obviously
didn't come by
to hear me geek out
about plants.Actually...
Oahu's climate can support the
growth of just about anything,
so I've planted rare species
from all over the world.
For my students to study
and enjoy.
Someday for my son, too.
This is the one
you were asking about.
Spiny restharrow.
Known to Latin speakers
as ononis spinosa.
It's quite lovely,
isn't it? It is, yeah.
So Eddie must have
gotten through the hedges
connecting the yards,
or through the gate.
Either way,
he was nosing around,
smelled them
and got triggered.
I don't understand.
Are you talking about
Eddie, Steve's dog?
Is he all right?
It wouldn't be a problem
if he ingested it.
It's not poisonous.
It-It's not that. Um,
I'm not sure if Steve told you,
but Eddie was a military
working dog.
He served with the Marines
in Afghanistan.
These plants are
abundant there.
And he suffered a combat trauma
in a field full of them.
A couple days ago, Eddie's
canine PTS was triggered.
And my plants were the trigger.
Oh, I feel awful.
Oh, please.
How could you know?
None of us did.
Regardless, I will
remove these right away.
I can call a few
of my students and have them
help me transfer them
to the greenhouse on campus.Thank you.
We appreciate your
understanding.
Steve will, too.
Yeah.
Oh, come on.
Come on, wake up.Uh, wha
Wake up. You're okay.
All right? Just breathe.
Just breathe.
There you go.
That's good.
All right, look,
you're stable right now
and you're strong.I don't feel strong.
All right? You're strong.
All we gotta do is
catch a break. Okay?
That's it. That all
we gotta do, all right?
You cold?
I'm tired.
All right. You're all right.I'm tired.
So cold.
I know, I know.
I know.
Hey, I know. Come on.
Come on, won't you come on?
Okay.Okay, good.
Can't stay awake.Okay.
Can't stay awake.
No...
All right.
Come on. Come on.
Come o
Come on!
Somebody!
Wake up!
Come on!
Hey.
You hear that?Don't miss this one.
Hey, I'm a cop.
I need to use your radio
to call an ambulance.
Of course.
Channel nine.
Is it good?
Yeah.
All right, this is
Detective Danny Williams
with the Five-O Task Force.
I need an ambulance,
uh, Waianae Valley Road,
about a mile past Haleahi.
Um, got life-threatening
injuries sustained by a female.
She's lost a lot of blood.
I need an ambulance immediately.
Copy, Detective.
Sending paramedic units
to your location right away.
Right now, right now, please.
Thanks.
Aw, look at you two.
Love is real.
Yeah, you know, uh, I think
romcoms want us to believe
that a race to the airport
tops the list
of romantic gestures,
but I believe that
dodging traffic has that beat.
Not to mention I always thought
chasing somebody to the airport
was a little psycho.
You know, it's strange,
out there this morning
in the traffic,
where Eddie made
eye contact with me,
and I could see his panic
and his fear,
not knowing
which way to turn.
And I swear to God,
I could relate.
And after everything
that's happened this year...
that's exactly
where I would be
if I didn't have this dog
to lean on every day.
If I didn't have all of you.
Not going anywhere, Steve.
Yeah, ditto.
And I don't think
young Edward here
is gonna be moving
for the next 18 hours.
So I hope you're comfortable.
By the way, um,
how's Danny doing?
I heard he was taking
a few days.
I spoke to him this morning.
He's good.
Oh, maybe that's him now.
Not unless he forgot his key.
Adam.
Hey.
It's been a minute.
Yeah, I, uh...
I'm sorry I was gone so long.
I just, um...
I just had to get away.
Clear my head.
I get it.
Welcome home, bro.
Hey, hey...
Hey. Hey. Good news.
Ambulance is on the way.
Huh?
Okay? So you gotta
stay awake.
All right?
Okay. Okay, there you go.
What's so funny?What's so funny?
I got, I got the luck,
like you said.
I meet the girl of my dreams,
and I get into a car accident.
Ah, you're okay.
Things are gonna
work out for you.
Yeah. Yeah.
Stay awake.
Hey, you never
told me your name.
My name? My name is Danny.
My name's Danny. You gonna
tell me your name now?
Huh?
No, no.
Hey, hey.
Wake up. Wake
Wake up.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
and TOYOTA.