- My name is Meg Murphy.
This is my street.
And this is my house.
[Alarm clock ringing]
That's me.
Hi.
[Sighs]
Okay, not the
best first impression.
Let's skip ahead.
Much better.
So as I was saying,
I'm Meg Murphy,
and today begins what I know
will be the
greatest summer ever.
Being me can be exhausting.
My life is a little...
Strange.
But it's not just me.
My whole family is different.
Hi, mom.
- Good morning.
- Morning, trouble.
Morning, dad.
- Good morning, beautiful.
No, not you, Harold.
Yes, you do
have beautiful eyes.
- We may look normal,
but we're not like
other families exactly.
- So how did you sleep?
- Great.
I was only woken up once
when a bat flew into my room
and got stuck
in my pillowcase.
- Oh, that's good.
That's so much better than the
angry badgers from last week.
- Yeah.
- Well, it looks
like somebody's summer
is getting off
to a good start.
I know you don't like bacon.
There's cereal up there.
- Easy enough.
Just go get that cereal up there
on the shelf, right?
Just use the ladder
or a stool.
- And the second one...
[Murmuring indistinctly]
[Cereal clattering]
- [Gasps]
[Whispering]
Nobody move.
- Hi, baby.
[Baby cooing]
Yeah, give mommy
the orange.
Give mommy the orange,
baby.
Give mommy the orange.
Okay, give it to mommy.
That's a good girl.
Give mommy the orange--
no!
[Ice clattering]
- Oh-ho-ho!
- Oh!
Ugh!
- Ooh!
Oh, not the bacon.
[Electrical zapping]
- [Gasps]
[All sigh]
[Explosion]
[All screaming]
[Wood creaking]
- Okay, troops,
time to evacuate.
- Charlie, time to go.
- Be right there,
dad!
- Whoo-hoo!
[Laughing]
Whoa!
- Oh, I know.
It's such a bummer.
- Oh, that was so awesome.
I got it on video.
- Walk briskly to the exit,
everyone.
- Okay, kids, grab
your emergency suitcases.
[Crashing]
- Okay, boys and girls,
time to go.
- Now I know.
- Out the door, Charlie.
- Move, move, move.
- Let's go!
Let's go!
[Crashing]
- It's a good thing we have
insurance on speed dial, huh?
- Yeah.
Come on, Charlie.
[Crashing]
[Dog barking]
- Let me get my camera.
- Whoa, whoa,
wait, wait.
Charlie, I'll get it.
Heh.
Hey.
It still works.
[Rumbling]
[Crashing]
- Not again.
[Mischievous
instrumental music]
¶ ¶
[bees buzzing]
Clank!
[Birds chirping]
[Water hissing]
[Crashing]
Splorch!
[Horn honking]
[Bird squawking]
[Bird honking]
Boof!
[Baby powder shaking]
[Baby cooing]
[Bees buzzing]
[Glass shatters]
[People screaming]
- I wish I were normal.
I wish I could tell you
that our house falling down
was a once-in-a-lifetime thing.
But this was the fourth time
it had happened.
This year.
The local hotels have
all politely told us
we're never,
ever allowed back.
So this time we're staying with
our grandpa in harvest hills.
Boing!
- Oh!
Honey. Oh.
Honey.
- Okay.
- Yeah, I'm stuck.
No, it's even worse.
- Okay, stop, just--
- yeah, okay, go ahead.
- Let me.
- Yeah, just--
okay, got it?
[Gasps]
That's the sweet spot...
- Here's the deal:
My family is jinxed.
100 years ago,
a witch put a magical curse
on my great great grandfather
Tommy Murphy,
and now every Murphy
since then
has been stuck with bad luck.
This isn't just any bad luck.
I mean, reputation-tanking,
life-frazzling bad luck.
We call it Murphy's law.
If anything can go wrong,
it will.
But we figured out how
to deal with it.
When you're a Murphy,
you have to see things
a little bit differently
than everyone else.
- [Makes buzzer noise]
- What?
- Gangy!
- Mom and dad taught us being
a Murphy makes us special,
but that's a little harder
to believe
now that I'm in high school.
As you can imagine,
being a walking disaster
does not equal popularity.
People tend to run away
from me,
hurricane Meg.
[Water hissing]
You might think I'm exaggerating
the whole curse,
that I'm just accident-prone.
Nope.
The curse is real.
[Water hissing]
[Bucket clattering]
It's magic,
and it's out to get me.
I want to do something important
with my life,
like become a famous scientist
and discover
the cure for pimples.
[Substance gurgling]
[Explosion]
[Kids gasping]
But it turns out
science is no match
for an evil spell.
I guess I should settle for just
trying not to kill anybody.
- Next up,
Meg Murphy.
- I've tried to be normal,
but I don't even need
to finish this sentence
because I'm sure
you've already figured out
how that worked out
for me.
Ready?
Okay.
- Oh!
- But in the whole history
of Murphys,
no one's figured out how
to break the curse.
Whenever I ask my parents
about it,
they change the subject.
Twang!
[Suitcases clattering]
[Tires squealing]
- Hi.
Sorry about this.
[Horn honking]
Let me grab it.
Honk!
My house is--
hold on a sec.
- Come on!
- Ha-ha!
Oh, this is awkward.
Go ahead.
I'll go.
[Horn honking]
- If this curse had
a magical cause,
it must have a magical solution.
I've got
to find it this summer
so I can leave
all this baggage behind me
and start high school,
normal.
- [Sighs]
Home sweet home
for the time being.
This'll be fun,
right, gang?
Hanging with grandpa.
24/7.
- Oh, I totally forgot
about the second floor balcony.
It's perfect
for a skating trick.
Oh, I can fly up the ramp
to the railing,
and then I could jump
to the roof
and then skate
the roof Ridge,
and then Ollie back
to the windowsill
and grind it,
and then fall from my board
and crash onto the side
of the house.
Oh, dad, you
could totally film it.
It would be epic.
- That's my annoying
little brother, Charlie.
You might recognize him
as Internet sensation
skater fail boy.
He's famous for his videos of
him doing crazy skating tricks.
And failing.
It's, like,
his thing.
Clunk!
[Kids cheering]
- [Laughing]
Yeah!
- Uh-uh-uh-uh!
Just stay epic down here
on the ground, buddy.
- The Murphy's have a strict
policy against heights.
I mean, even people
who aren't cursed
get hurt falling
from high places.
Charlie's the only one
who ignores the family motto.
All: Climb over three feet,
you're dead meat.
- Um...
What's that?
- Yeah, why does the front door
look like it's about to fart.
Thoonk!
- [Grunting]
Whoa.
- Grandpa has had the curse
a lot longer than any of us,
and has found interesting ways
to deal with it.
- Hi, dad.
- [Laughing]
Oh, hi.
- Hey, grandpa.
A giant bubble, huh?
That's new.
- Yeah, great find,
right?
I never go outside
without it now.
Never.
[Geese honking]
Look.
It's a flock
of migrating geese.
[Splatting]
- [Squeals]
- Majestic creatures.
[Door closes]
[Grunting]
Oh, I'm so happy
you're all here.
[Chuckling]
I can't believe how much
you've grown.
Now, kids, you remember
where your rooms are, right?
Get!
- Wow. I love what you've done
with the place, dad.
All the memories and--
no, don't even think
about it.
- Be careful.
I haven't had time
to baby-proof the house yet.
See, all this
is just Murphy-proofed.
- Since my baby sister Georgia
can't walk yet,
the curse doesn't affect her
too much for now.
But it sure does make
mom's life harder.
- My little Georgia want
some peaches?
Here it comes.
[Makes airplane sounds]
[Baby coos]
[Flashbulbs popping]
Okay.
So that's a no
on the peaches.
- Oh, uh, this...
Was dropped off
for you earlier, son.
I...
- [Gasps]
Oh-ho-ho-ho.
Test case number 456
for Murphy's machinations.
- [Chuckles]
- Murphy's machinations
is my dad's company.
It's hard to keep a job when
you're cursed by Murphy's law.
- Thanks.
Have a good day.
Bye-bye.
Oh.
Uh...
Smack!
Hi.
[Whistling]
Whoa! Whoa!
[Garbling]
- But dad found a way
to turn the curse
into a business opportunity.
He tests out new products
for defects.
This glue is guaranteed
to create a lifetime hold.
Not much of a guarantee
if you ask me.
If there's a flaw,
I'll find it
and help you fix it.
If something can go wrong,
it will
with mark Murphy.
- We're still rolling.
[Dial tone]
- Wow.
Wow.
Looks expensive.
Can't wait to break it.
They call it
the insta cookie 3000.
It's made
by matayama industries.
If I could figure out
what could go wrong
with this by Monday,
they said I could test
all their products,
which could mean
big time...
[Clicks teeth]
For the whole family.
- Wait.
What's this mean?
- Money.
- Oh.
Hey, dad,
can I have some of this?
- [Laughs]
No.
- Ah, the Murphy wall of fame,
huh?
Oh.
[Laughs]
This one's daddy.
[Clears throat]
Okay, I know it's not
your best scenario
for your summer.
- Best?
Try even worse
than my worst nightmare.
- Okay.
Well, I know it's not home,
but harvest hills
is a nice little town.
I think you could have
a lot of fun here.
Oh, oh, look.
A science camp
for teenagers
at the university.
You just fill out
the application.
- Seriously, mom?
Do you know what would happen
if a Murphy was let loose
in a science lab?
[Monster roaring]
[People screaming]
I'm sorry!
I didn't think you could
actually release the kraken.
- [Sighs]
- What?
We're cursed.
It could happen.
- Meg, everyone has problems.
It is not just us,
okay?
How you handle it
is what matters.
- You know the best way
to handle our problems?
Get rid of the curse.
- [Laughing]
Okay, sweetie.
Could you just let let go,
maybe,
and enjoy your vacation?
- But there's got to be a way.
I mean, I can't go through
three more years of high school
as hurricane Meg.
- [Sighs]
You know what?
I know.
I know what will
make you feel better.
Here.
Yes, I am paying you off
to be a happy daughter.
Seriously, you should just go
and buy yourself
a whole new summer wardrobe.
You deserve it.
- My suitcase got left behind?
- Yeah.
- ¶ It's a cruel ¶
¶ cruel summer ¶
¶ leaving me here
on my own ¶
¶ it's a cruel ¶
¶ cruel summer ¶
¶ now you're gone ¶
¶ you're not the only one ¶
[kids screaming distantly]
¶ The city is crowded ¶
¶ my friends are away ¶
- oh.
- Oh.
You.
- Ivy Murray.
Aka the meanest girl
in the history of mean girls,
aka the bane
of my existence,
aka--
oh, no.
- What are you doing here?
- Well, my grandpa lives here,
so--
- here?
In harvest hills?
But this is my town.
I come here every summer,
and you're not invited.
- Trust me. I am just as unhappy
about this as you are.
- My summer's ruined.
My life is ruined.
Give me that.
This town is supposed
to be a hurricane Meg-free zone.
- Of all the towns we could
have come to this summer,
it had to be here?
Harvest hills is horrible.
This is going to be
the worst summer ever.
- Hold on.
I found these
monkey socks first.
And finders keepers.
These must be yours.
- Yeah.
- I would definitely rock
those socks, though.
- Thanks.
I'm embarrassed.
- Well, hi, embarrassed.
I'm Brett.
- It's Meg, actually.
- Well, nice to meet you, Meg.
Are you from harvest hills?
I haven't seen you before.
- No, I'm just here
visiting my bees.
I mean, my grandpa.
Well, not visiting.
I guess I'm kind of living here
this summer.
My house, it, uh,
kind of fell down.
So many bees.
- Well, welcome.
You're actually just in time
for the harvest festival.
- I can see.
- There's tons of fun stuff
to do.
It lasts all week.
And every year
they pick one person
to lower the flag
at the closing ceremony.
Guess who they picked
this year.
- Who?
I have no idea.
Wait.
Is it you?
- Yes.
Jeez.
Took you long enough.
I'll have you know
it's a very big honor.
Get to shake hands
with the mayor.
Get a really snazzy t-shirt.
- You know, we can never
have too many t-shirts.
- [Chortles]
- Smooth, Meg.
- Well, anyway,
um, you should come.
There's gonna be a picnic
and a fair.
And a dance.
You've got to come
to the dance.
- I do?
- Sure.
It's a town tradition.
You don't want to hurt
the town's feelings, do you?
- I guess not.
- Um...
Let me help you
with the rest of these.
- Thanks.
OMG, he doesn't know
I'm hurricane Meg.
Mom was right.
Harvest hills is awesome.
This is gonna be
the best summer ever.
If only this bee
would leave me alone.
Smack!
- Ow!
- Oh, I am so sorry.
I really didn't mean to.
- Wow. You got a strong
right hook there, Meg.
- Oh, my god.
- Oh!
- I'm so sorry.
No, no,
it was an accident.
Here you go.
It was very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Sorry.
- It's okay.
don't worry about it.
- Okay, curse,
this means war.
- Butt balloon activate!
- Sorry, grandpa.
Cool invention.
- Oh, it's handy
for napping anywhere.
- This stupid curse
is ruining my life.
I mean, look at the things
this family has gone through.
"Hiccupping man causes
circus stampede."
Okay, "man throws coin
in fountain,
floods town."
- That was a lot of water.
- "Local youth
invents homework."
The Murphys invented homework?
Really?
[Both murmuring]
- It's been 100 years.
Why has no one ever tried
to break it?
- Oh, we've tried.
- Dad.
- Oh.
- What? Grandpa, is there
a way to break the curse?
- There are certain things
a Murphy must never do--
needlepoint,
whale watching.
But messing with the curse
is at the top of the list.
- So you admit you've tried it.
What do you do?
Do you got to a fortune-teller
or do a seance
or find a spell in a book?
- [Gasps]
- Ha! There's a book.
- Enough, Meg.
We've told you before
that the curse can't be broken.
So don't make yourself miserable
by trying.
- Okay, so I guess I should just
stay miserable not trying.
- That is not what I meant.
- Trust us, Meg.
There are fates worse
than Murphy's law.
- She's getting too curious.
She doesn't know the chaos
that she can cause.
She'll--
- she won't find
the diary, son.
- But if she did--
- won't.
- I'm just saying---
- shush.
- I'm playing devil's--
- nope.
- Every time I--
- no.
- I looked everywhere
for this--this book,
but things are easily hidden
in grandpa's big old house.
And I probably should have
remembered Murphy rule 51.
[Sighs]
[Sniffs]
Never use matches.
[Explosion]
Whoa!
[Grunts]
[Coughing]
Grandpa was right.
I didn't find the diary.
The diary found me.
[Chortles]
- Hey, hey
to all my fans.
I just made a new invention
that's gonna make my videos
even more awesome than before.
The dizzy cam.
World, you are so not ready
for this.
- Dude, this is gonna be
so rad.
- Dude, I know,
right?
- Let's go.
- All right.
- Go, go, go!
- You got this!
Whoa!
- Charlie's never landed
a trick
thanks to Murphy's curse.
But he doesn't care.
He doesn't even try
to be a good skater.
His fans just want
to see a cyclone on wheels.
- Yeah!
- [Gasps]
- Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
- Whoa.
- [Chuckles]
[People cheering]
- [Laughing]
Yeah!
- June 22, 1914.
- Hi, honey.
I'm gonna run to the store
because Georgia has graduated
to the industrial strength
diapers.
So, uh, I could drop you off
in town.
You could go do things.
Kids your age,
they have places they like
to go, hang out, right?
You could get down.
- No, thanks, mom.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- "Tonight is the harvest dance,
and I, Tommy Murphy..."
- Am the luckiest man
around.
[Fountain splashing]
[Indistinct chatter]
A man once said to me,
"Tommy Murphy, you're
the luckiest guy around."
And you know what?
Today I feel like I am.
[People cheering]
[Frogs croaking]
[Cheering]
Yes!
Yeah!
[Laughing]
[Upbeat fiddle music]
¶ ¶
and tonight I bet
I'm gonna end up
with the prettiest girl
in town.
- Hi, Tommy.
- No, not Violet.
Caitlin O'Leary.
Now, some townsfolk think
she's a witch,
but I think that's just silly.
Everyone knows there's
no such thing as magic.
Although she's certainly
put a spell on me.
[Chortles]
- Will you dance with me,
Tommy?
- I don't know.
I'm not a very good dancer.
But I'll tell you what.
I will let
my lucky coin decide.
Heads, yes.
Tails...
[Both laugh]
[Stirring string music]
¶ ¶
[grunts]
- Tommy.
- Mm, mm--
no!
Caitlin.
No, it's--
it's not what it looks like.
Caitlin, wait!
Caitlin, stop!
[Dress ripping]
- [Gasps]
- Caitlin!
Caitlin.
Caitlin, come on.
Come back to the dance.
- I never want to talk
to you again, Tommy Murphy.
- Violet means nothing
to me.
So you're wearing
grandma's underwear.
I don't care.
- [Sniffs]
You still want to dance with me?
I'll flip you for it.
Heads, the answer is yes.
Tails...
[Magical shimmering]
I curse you and every other
no-good Murphy forever.
[Wind whistling]
- What's a stupid coin
know anyway?
Caitlin, wait!
Splorch!
- Unbelievable.
We've suffered generations
because people
saw her underwear?
"I don't want to complain,
but..."
- Ever since that day,
things haven't been going
so well for me here
in harvest hills.
[Horn honking]
A man came up to me today,
and he said,
"Tommy Murphy, you are
the unluckiest guy around."
And he was right.
Things that were easy
for me
weren't easy anymore.
I tried to find Caitlin.
I wanted to talk to her.
- You may kiss the bride.
- But I was too late.
[People laughing
and cheering]
- Congratulations.
[Cheers and applause]
[Horse whinnies]
- [Grunting]
But I wasn't giving up.
I was gonna find a way
to break the curse.
- Very interesting.
- Even if it killed me.
- [Gasps]
- Ah!
Which, the way things
were going,
it might.
[Coughing]
- I finally found the answer.
Yes, this is it!
"All I have to do to lift
the curse is..."
[Water splashing]
[Electrical zapping]
Yes!
Ow!
Ha-ha.
You stupid curse.
You hit me two seconds
too late.
I already know everything
about how to stop you.
Caitlin O'Leary,
your reign of terror
has gone on long enough.
[Wind whistling]
[Beeping]
[Machine whirring]
[Machine beeps]
[Beeping]
[Alarm beeping]
[Explosion]
- Off to an excellent start.
Yeah.
[Sighs]
- There you are.
Sweet.
- Hello, sweetheart.
How are you?
Good.
Good talk.
[Coughs]
- Every step I take
gets me closer
to my goal of being normal,
of being just like
everyone else,
of not being hurricane Meg.
I'm gonna find that coin and...
[Groans]
What now?
- Meg.
Oh, Meg.
I've been all over town
looking for you.
- What for?
- Can't it just be
because I love my sister?
All right,
I need 50 bucks.
Meg, wait.
There's a skating competition
this summer,
and I'm gonna rock it,
build up my fan base.
Get cur-a-zy.
Only I can't afford
the entrance fee.
- Okay, then why don't you ask
mom and dad?
- They said I had
to pay for it myself.
- Okay, then why
are you asking me?
- Because I consider you
a patron of the arts.
- [Scoffs]
- Come on, Meg.
Help me give the people
what they want.
Loan the money?
- No.
But you can earn it
helping me break
the Murphy curse.
- Whoa!
Wait, wait, wait.
- [Screams]
- Oh, my gosh.
Ivy, I'm so sorry.
Are you okay?
It was...
An accident.
- You being born
was an accident.
- If it makes you
feel any better,
that was a pretty sweet wipeout.
- Who is this person
speaking to me?
- My brother.
- There are more of you?
Ugh!
Let's go.
- Jeez, what's her problem?
- So much for making friends
in harvest hills.
- Sorry, Meg.
Okay, so let me get
this straight.
You want to break the curse,
but you were warned not to,
which makes me want
to help,
but how do I get my money?
- "If the curse
you want lifted,
"find the object
that was flipp-ed.
"Give it to the next O'Leary,
but be sure they
take it cheery."
- Yeah, I don't get it.
- It's the key
to breaking the curse.
Great great grandpa Tommy
was cursed with a magic coin.
That's what was flipped.
If we give it back
to someone who's related
to that witch woman
Caitlin O'Leary
before the end
of the harvest dance,
we can end the curse forever.
We just have to find
that coin.
- But, Meg,
how are we supposed
to find some coin
from 100 years ago?
It's not like he put an ad
in the paper
saying where he spent it.
- Actually,
he kind of did.
- "Man throws coin
in fountain,
floods town"?
- Tommy threw the coin
in the fountain
to try and wish
the curse away.
It didn't work,
and the coin caused a crack
in the fountain
that flooded downtown.
Typical Murphy.
- So where's this fountain?
[Water splashing]
Hey, Meg.
I found it.
There it is.
I solved the mystery.
- Go.
- Which one is it?
- It's a 100-year-old coin.
I'm sure it's got
to stand out.
- Hey, Meg!
- Brett.
- Quarters, pennies...
- Um, sorry.
- Whoa!
[Splashing]
What the?
- Hey.
- It's my favorite boxer.
How does my nose look?
Is it crooked?
- Your nose is perfect.
I mean,
perfectly straight.
I'm sorry.
After what I did,
I thought you'd want
to stay away from me.
I'm a mess.
- Are you kidding?
Of course not.
You seem like
a really cool mess.
Harvest hills can be
a pretty boring place.
But I feel like hanging out
with you,
I wouldn't be bored at all.
Bleeding and terrified,
maybe,
but not boring.
[Fountains hissing]
- [Spluttering]
Hey!
Hey, come on!
I could use some help here.
A lot of coins,
and I only have two hands!
- Is that kid trying to take
money out of the fountain?
- Probably just
some crazy person.
You were saying something
about hanging out with me?
[Fountains hissing]
- [Grunts]
- As long as you promise
to warn me
if you're gonna punch me again.
- I can't make any promises.
These babies have
a mind of their own.
- [Laughs]
So I see your reading up
on the town history.
- Oh, this.
Yeah, um,
just a big fan of history.
- Oh, me too.
Yeah, I actually used
to volunteer
at the town historical society.
They have a whole display
on the fountain flood
that destroyed harvest hills.
- And the stupid little coin
that started it.
- Wow.
You really do know
the history.
- [Grunting]
- It's kind of crazy
how a small thing like that
could cause such a mess.
They have the actual coin
on display there.
- They do?
I mean, oh.
That's cool.
[Bells ringing]
- [Grunting]
Uh-oh.
- [Clears throat]
So...
I was wondering...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
If maybe you would, um...
- Oh, my gosh.
Is he going to ask me out?
No, don't be ridiculous, Meg.
Why would--
- do you want to go to the
harvest festival dance with me?
- Sure.
[Chuckles]
Why not?
- Awesome.
- [Screaming]
- Anyway, um...
I should go.
And I will see you later.
- All right.
Bye.
While you were playing
in the water,
I just solved the mystery
of the coin.
We just have to figure out
how to get it.
- [Spits]
[Heavy mechanized breathing]
- Okay, let's spread out.
Hi, baby.
Hi, Georgie.
It's peaches.
- Excuse me, everyone.
I have an announcement
to make.
I have a date
to the harvest dance.
- [Gasps]
[Laughter and cheering]
- Yeah, Meg!
[Wood crashing]
[Cheering]
[Knocking on door]
- Hey.
I have a surprise for you.
Close your eyes.
Ta-da.
It's for the dance.
- [Chortles]
- It's fireproof,
stain proof, wrinkle proof,
and short enough
you won't trip on it.
- I love it.
Thank you so much.
- [Chuckles]
Let's see.
[Gasps]
Oh, honey.
Oh.
[Sniffs]
[Chortles]
You know,
the harvest dance
is where your father took me
on our first date.
It was the most romantic night
of my whole life.
Even after
your father got sprayed
by not one,
but two different skunks.
[Sighs]
- I'm so happy.
- Yeah.
Mm, you see?
It's like I always told you.
The curse doesn't matter
as long as you have
the right attitude, right?
- Wrong.
I was happy because I
was a day away
from breaking the curse.
Right.
- Hmm.
- Well,
I think we can agree,
it's time for this
a-cha-ching-cha-ching.
- And what does that mean?
- Money?
I mean, you got to pay up.
I helped you look
for the coin.
- Yeah, right.
You don't get paid
until we break the curse.
And we still don't have the coin
or know who
Caitlin's descendants are.
You have earned zero dollars.
- Aw, jeez.
You know, you're going
through a lot of trouble
just for some boy.
- I'm not doing this
for some boy.
I'm doing this for us,
for our family,
so our lives can finally
be normal.
- Meg...
I don't know if I want
my life to be normal.
- What are you talking about?
- It's just,
what about my skating?
If we break the curse,
then...
I won't be a master
of destruction anymore.
- [Scoffs]
don't worry, buddy.
Even without the curse,
you're probably still
a terrible skater.
- Thanks, Meg.
- The dance is tomorrow,
so we're breaking into that
historical building tonight.
And we need to get a coin
and find out who's related
to Caitlin O'Leary.
- All right.
Heist time!
- Shh.
[Whispering]
Heist time.
[Owl hooting]
- [Sighs]
- What?
It's the only black clothes
I own.
- Okay, but why bring
the wand?
- [Sighs]
[Dog barking distantly]
All of harvest hills'
historical treasure
is guarded
by impenetrable security,
but I have a plan.
We'll get in from above
through the skylight.
You will repel
to the roof,
then through the skylight
with glass cutters.
I'll create a distraction here
to mask the noise.
Here's where it gets
a little tricky.
You've seen spider-man,
right?
Take these suction cups and...
- Hey, sweet.
It's unlocked.
- Can do it that way.
Come on.
- [Groans]
- [Whispering]
don't make any sound,
and don't touch anything.
- Like there's anything
in here I'd want to touch.
Hey, check it out.
She's picking my nose.
- Stop messing around.
- [Sighs]
I've no idea
what you're saying.
- I'm gonna go look
over there.
- Fine. You go look
for the coin.
I'm gonna try and find
the town records.
- Uh!
Whoa.
Ha-ha.
Meg, I got it.
I found the coin.
- Nice.
- Aw, yeah.
I saw the target,
and I acquired it.
I slipped in and out
of the shadows silent
and undetected.
Yep.
I'm pretty much a ninja.
[Clattering]
- Shh.
[Keys jingling]
Quick.
Hide.
[Keys jingling]
[Jingling footsteps]
- [Grunting]
[Clattering]
- Hm.
[Door closes]
Man, that was so close.
- Okay.
I figured it out.
If Caitlin O'Leary
had a baby,
and that baby had a baby,
and on and on
for five generations,
then this book shows everyone
who's related to them.
It goes all the way down
to present day.
So according to this,
the most recent descendent
of Caitlin O'Leary
and the person we have
to give the coin to is...
Oh.
- Well, who is it?
- Ivy.
I should have guessed.
The girl who dubbed me
hurricane Meg
is the descendent
of the woman
who caused the hurricane
in the first place.
- Target acquired.
- I'm gonna get
into position.
- ¶ All the lights,
turn them off ¶
¶ it's too loud
in here to talk ¶
¶ I don't understand
a word you're saying ¶
¶ I'm trying to sleep,
but instead ¶
¶ karaoke on the bed ¶
- as I watched Ivy,
I couldn't help thinking,
what if this curse
somehow sensed
I was about to break it?
It would do anything it could
to stop me.
I would have to be more careful
than ever
if I wanted
to survive long enough to--
- hey, Meg.
Hey, Meg,
does this thing work?
- Stop interrupting
my inner monologue.
Yes, it works, Charlie.
You don't have to scream.
Where are you?
- Tonight my name
is nighthawk,
and I'm up in the lights.
I'm a go.
- I'm not calling you
nighthawk.
- Please?
Please, please, please?
- Oh, my god,
okay, fine.
- What's fine?
- Uh, you.
You're looking...
Fine.
- [Makes retching noise]
- Ha, shut up.
I mean, wow.
I should shut up.
I mean,
hi.
- Uh, hi to you too.
You look really pretty
tonight.
Do you want
to go get some punch?
- No,
me and punch are a bad idea,
with the spilling
and whatnot.
- Get your raffle tickets.
What about you,
young lady?
- Oh, no, thank you.
- You could win
an all-expense-paid trip
to the grand canyon.
- Trust me.
I won't win.
Not in 100 years.
0% chance.
- Here you go.
- What's the name
for the ticket?
- Meg Murphy.
Thanks.
So I present to you as a
"thank you" for being my date
a 0% chance
of winning a vacation.
Or maybe tonight
your luck will change.
- Thank you.
And I hope so.
- Oh, and it's also
your lucky day
because you get to embarrass
yourself on the dance floor
with me right now.
But I have to warn you.
I got moves.
It's the lawnmower.
What?
It's the running man.
I'm a sprinkler.
- Stop, stop,
I can't take it.
You're too good.
- [Laughs]
Shall we?
- Yes.
- Remember the mission.
Target's
in the refreshment area.
- I mean, no.
I mean,
I have to go get something.
I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Nighthawk, cover me.
I'm going in.
- Hey, Meg, I was thinking
about the rhyme of the curse.
You know, "give it
to the next O'Leary,
make sure they take it cheery."
You know, I was thinking
you could tell her a joke,
like, "knock-knock."
"Who's there?"
"Give me the coin."
"Give me the coin who?"
And then give her the coin.
- Yeah, no.
I think I'll just wing it.
Ah!
[Gasps]
[Fabric ripping]
- My skirt.
Meg Murphy!
- I am so sorry.
- This night was supposed
to be special.
You will never stop
tormenting me.
- Tormenting you?
You're mean to me for fun.
- Are you insane?
You're the mean one,
Meg Murphy.
You've been ruining my life
every single day
for the past eight years!
My last name is Murray.
Murray,
Murphy--
it's alphabetical.
Splorch!
Every year,
every class,
I have been one seat over
from you.
Everything that happened
to you
happened to me.
Oh!
You've made every day
of my life
a living nightmare.
Ah!
And the saddest part
is that you've always been
so full of yourself
and your whole,
"I'm cursed, so pity me" saga,
that you've never even noticed
anyone around you.
- Could what she
was saying be true?
Do I just ignore
the people around me?
- Are you even listening
to me?
- Hey, Ivy,
cut it out!
You're the one feeling sorry
for yourself.
- What?
- Yeah, you've been moping
around this town all summer.
- It's not Meg's fault
she's a little accident-prone.
- Accident-prone my foot.
She's cursed.
- Oh, come on.
- It's true.
I am cursed.
All the bad stuff
that happens to me,
it's...
It's never gonna go away,
so...
That's that.
- Come on, who cares what
my cousin thinks?
I like you.
- [Groans]
Come on.
- Seriously?
[Indistinct chatter]
- Wait. You and Ivy
are related?
- That's what cousins means.
- So Caitlin O'Leary was...
- My great great grandmother?
Kind of weird that you know
that, by the way.
- Hey, Meg, that means
you can still break the curse.
You just have to give Brett
the coin.
- This is it, guys.
End of the dance.
So let's finish up the evening
with the traditional
harvest hills square dance.
[Cheers and applause]
- May I?
- Oh, just give him the coin.
It's the last dance.
- Okay.
- Come on, let's dance.
[Coin clattering]
- Uh-oh.
Big problem.
- I'm nighthawk.
[Upbeat fiddle music]
¶ ¶
[coin clattering]
All: Whoo!
Whoo!
- I need to talk
to you in private.
- What is it?
- Uh...
Knock-knock.
- Excuse me?
- Coming through.
- Knock-knock.
- Who's there?
- Give me that coin.
- Give me that coin who?
- Thank you.
[Magical shimmering]
- Okay.
Well, thanks.
I'll keep it as a memento.
- What a fantastic last dance,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
- Nighthawk here.
Did you break the curse?
- Was it broken?
I didn't know.
How could I tell?
- And now what you've all
been waiting for.
I'd like to congratulate
the lucky winner
of our raffle,
Meg Murphy!
[Cheers and applause]
- Meg.
Meg, you won.
- No, I never win anything.
- Meg Murphy, please come up
here and claim your prize.
- I won.
- You won.
- I told you.
Ms. 0% chance.
- Hey, kid if you play
your cards right,
maybe your girlfriend here
will bring you
on her vacation.
- Yeah.
Maybe my girlfriend will.
- Girlfriend?
[Cheers and applause]
The curse is broken.
My life is finally
gonna be normal.
I can do anything I want.
I even, amazingly,
unbelievably,
stupendously
have a boyfriend.
Life is perfect.
- "By harvest night
complete this verse,
and the o'learys
will receive the curse"?
What is this?
[Birds chirping]
- ¶ It's a brand new day ¶
¶ and everything is okay ¶
¶ I don't have the curse ¶
¶ something that rhymes
with curse ¶
all right,
this isn't a musical,
and I can't sing,
but the point is,
I'm curse-free.
Look out, world.
There's so much
I can do now.
No more hurricane Meg.
[Machine beeping]
- Okay, Mr. cookie,
give me your worst.
[Machine beeping]
[Gasps]
Ding!
What the heck?
Both: Something's wrong.
- The insta cookie's
working perfectly.
- I fed the baby,
and look at me.
I'm clean.
- If I didn't know any better,
I...
- Oh, no.
Oh, she couldn't.
- No.
She wouldn't.
- [Laughing]
No.
Meg!
Meg?
- I have some amazing news,
everyone.
- Meg, did you break
the curse?
- Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
- [Sighs]
- Why is no one jumping up
and down?
- Meg, honey,
what were you thinking?
- I was thinking I'd get rid
of that horrible curse
that's been in our family.
You know,
the one that makes us trip,
throws tree branches at us,
and makes houses fall down
and stuff.
Aren't you happy?
- Honey, um,
who did you give the coin to?
- Brett,
and it ended the curse.
- No, Meg.
You didn't end the curse.
You transferred it
to--to Brett and his family.
- And now he's doomed.
It all makes sense now.
- What are you talking about?
- It's the last verse
of the rhyme
from Tommy's diary.
"By harvest night,
complete this verse..."
All: "And the o'learys
shall receive the curse."
- This line has been
temporarily disconnected.
- Never a good sign.
This has to be some sort
of horrible mistake.
Seriously,
Brett was fine.
I think.
I mean, I could never--
I would never transfer
the curse to him.
I was just trying
to get rid of it.
[All murmuring]
Hey, is there any way I can
transfer the curse back to us?
- I'm afraid not.
The curse can only be broken
during the harvest dance.
- I don't believe this.
I'm gonna kill my boyfriend
before I get my first kiss.
- I got this, honey.
- Uh,
yeah, I'll go.
- I was hoping you
were gonna say that.
- Now that I'm normal,
I'm supposed to be happy.
But instead I'm more miserable
than ever.
- Honey, I--I don't know
why you thought
you needed to be normal
to be happy in the first place.
- Because how can anyone be
happy when they're jinxed?
- You know, I wasn't born
a Murphy.
For 20 years, I lived
a perfectly normal life.
And I will tell you
a secret.
Since I married your father
and I took this curse on,
I have never been happier.
Oh, sweetie.
I told you before,
this curse does not determine
whether or not your life
is good or bad or happy
or lonely.
You do.
- But it's too late.
I've already given
the curse to Brett.
It's over.
- No, it's not over.
- What?
How?
- I took a second look
at the diary.
The curse must be broken
by the end of the festival,
not the dance.
The festival--
back then,
the dance
was the very last event.
- But it isn't anymore.
The festival doesn't end
until the closing ceremonies.
- So that means I can still take
the curse back from Brett.
- Yeah.
- I'm going to his house.
- Quick,
you only have an hour.
Run!
- Run!
Okay, we've got
an hour without the curse.
[Gasps]
I haven't used a curling iron
since I became a Murphy.
[Gasps]
- One hour with no curse.
- Dad...
[Panting]
[Chainsaw buzzing]
Is it cool if I use this
to chop down one
of your trees?
- Sure, son.
- Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
No curse!
- I can run!
Without tripping or--
or hitting tree branches.
So this
is what normal feels like.
No worries, no fear
of everyday things
like waking up in the morning
with a bat in your hair
or--or walking or...
Wait.
If I take the curse back,
good-bye running,
good-bye science camp,
good-bye normal.
Taking the curse back
means giving up everything
I've been hoping for.
[Water hissing]
[Lawnmower rattling]
Whoosh!
[Crashing]
[Animal sounds]
Um...
[Knocking on door]
Hello?
- You.
- What are you doing here?
- Not that it's any
of your business,
but my house fell down today.
Then I come
to my cousin's house,
and there's an angry monkey
tearing the place apart.
Now you show up,
and this is officially
the worst day ever.
- I know.
And I'm sorry,
but I need to find Brett.
- He's at the closing ceremony.
Now bye!
- Ivy,
here's the thing.
There's a chance that I maybe
might have possibly,
accidentally cursed you
and your entire family.
- You think?
- Right, sorry.
But I need your help to...
How did you get all that gum
in your hair?
- The angry monkey.
I don't want to talk about it.
- Right.
I have to find Brett
to take the curse back
before the festival ends,
or you and your family
will be stuck with it.
We need to go.
Ivy didn't want to go
at first,
even though after one day
with the curse,
she lost her house,
she has gum in her hair,
and her cousin's house
is a wreck.
It was the thought
of being alone with the monkey
that convinced her to help.
[Monkey screeching]
- Next contestant
in the harvest hills skate jam,
Charlie Murphy.
- Yo, I bet he breaks
every bone in his body.
How awesome is this gonna be?
- Hey, skater fail boy.
How do you plan out
those gnarly crunches?
- Eh, it's a gift.
I don't even have to try.
[All chanting "fail boy"]
- Charlie.
What's the matter?
- I'm not cursed,
so I'm not gonna fail,
and then everyone's
gonna hate me.
- [Chuckles]
They're not gonna hate you.
Just do your best.
- Dad, I'm skater fail boy.
- No.
You're Charlie Murphy.
And cursed or not,
you can do anything.
If you try.
- Thanks, dad.
- Go get 'em, son.
[All chanting "fail boy"]
- [Breathes deeply]
[People cheering]
[People gasping]
- Whoa!
[People cheering]
Yeah.
[Chortles]
I did it.
- Whoo-hoo!
Way to go, Charlie!
Yeah!
- Yeah, I did it!
- Whoo!
That's my son.
Whoo!
[Audience slowly clapping]
[Cheers and applause]
- Yeah, I did it!
I did it!
Yeah, I did it!
[Cheering]
- Where is this kid?
- Whoa!
- I'm sorry I'm late,
sir.
It's been kind of
a crazy day.
I had to outrun
a bitey raccoon.
But I think I lost him.
- Um, okay.
Let's all give a big hand
to Brett Taylor
for being chosen as this year's
closing ceremony ambassador.
[Cheers and applause]
Thanks to his tireless community
service for our great town.
Now, once he climbs up there
and lowers the festival flag,
another festival of fun
will officially end.
Okay, son.
Climb that tower.
[Cheers and applause]
[Wood creaking]
- Wait.
I need a break.
Ah!
- Ivy.
- [Whimpers]
- Are you okay?
- [Grunts]
[Panting]
This whole time I thought
you were doing
these awful things
to me on purpose.
I thought you were out
to get me.
You weren't,
were you?
[Sighs]
I've been unfair to you.
You really were cursed.
- It's okay.
I should have been nicer
as well.
I mean,
I never really realized
how much my hurricane can get
other people caught in it.
If it makes you feel any better,
I've fallen
in enough mud puddles
to know it does wonders
for your skin.
- [Chortles]
- Now, come on.
Let's go find Brett.
[Bee buzzing]
- Really?
Go.
Whoa!
[Grunts]
[Panting]
- I don't see him.
- [Grunting]
- There he is!
- All right,
go get him, Meg.
All: Climb over three feet,
you're dead meat.
- Listen to us, dummy!
- Meg?
Do you want me
to climb up there instead?
- No, just stay right there
and don't look up until I take
the curse back from Brett,
or a meteor might fall
from the sky
or something
if you do.
Okay.
Not this time, ladder.
Not this time.
I won't let my fear of--
- are you gonna go already?
- Right.
Okay.
- [Grunting]
- This was it.
My last chance to back out
and have my life be normal.
But then I realized something.
I don't want to be normal.
I want to be me,
hurricane Meg, a Murphy.
And cursed or not,
if I can climb a ladder,
I can do anything.
[Whimpering]
Stop!
don't lower the flag!
- Meg?
- You're the first good thing
I've seen all day.
It's been kind of crazy.
- I know,
and it's all my fault.
I gave you a curse.
- What?
- You see, my family was cursed
with bad luck by a witch,
and then I sort of gave it
to you.
I'm sorry.
- What--so this happens
to you every day?
- On a good day,
yeah.
That coin I gave you last night,
do you still have it?
- Uh, yeah,
I kept it,
I thought for good luck.
- Great.
I can take the curse back.
All you have to do
is give it to me.
- No.
- No?
What do you mean, no?
- Well, I don't want you
to suffer from bad luck either.
- No, no, no,
it's not like that.
I don't mind the curse.
I mean, not anymore.
I haven't really minded it
since I met you, actually.
You make things...
Well, you make them okay.
Better than okay--
happy.
And we all have stuff
to deal with.
It's all about how
you approach it.
So?
Give me the coin.
- Give her the coin,
idiot!
- Okay.
[Lightning crashes]
[Electrical zapping]
- [Moaning]
- Whoa.
- Ah!
[People gasping]
Help me.
Please grab my hand.
Grab my hand.
Please pull me up.
[Woman screams]
[Gasps]
[Cheers and applause]
Thanks.
- No problem.
- Now that everything
was back to normal,
dad discovered the cookies
from insta cookie
turned your teeth blue.
- Holy smokes,
my teeth are blue.
I got you,
insta cookie.
[Laughs]
We're gonna be rich.
- So he turned his report in
after all.
To celebrate, we decided
to take the trip
that I won at the raffle.
The Murphys,
the grand canyon?
What could go wrong there?
Charlie's big win
at the skating competition
made him realize he doesn't need
the curse to be awesome.
[Glass shattering]
Best of all,
I realized that my mom
was right.
It didn't matter
if I was cursed.
I could be anything
I wanted.
That's right.
I went to science camp.
I will now add
hydrogen chloride.
- No, no!
No, no, no, wait!
That's not hydrogen...
[Coughing]
[Students gasping]
What?
- Then I realized
my bad luck
could sometimes do good things.
You're welcome,
bald people everywhere,
and I found out
my great great grandpa
learned the same thing.
- If I'd never had the curse,
then I'd never have been
at the hospital,
and I'd never have met
my edna.
She makes me happier
than anything.
And I don't need
this coin anymore.
'Cause I'm the luckiest guy
in town.
Splash!
[Water rushing]
[Water splashing]
- Meg, time to go!
- Grandpa.
- Oh, hi, honey.
- I'd give you a hug,
but...
- Oh, I know.
It's like hugging
a pregnant orange.
I still got some kinks
to work out.
- And I know you will.
Even though this isn't
the summer that I imagined,
in some ways it was better.
- Bye.
don't get me wrong.
I'm happy we're
leaving harvest hills
to go to the grand canyon,
but I'm going to miss
my new best friend.
- Meg.
- You heard me right.
I have a best friend.
She truly gets me,
curse and all.
What are you guys doing here?
- We had to come
and say good-bye
and remind you about rule 34.
Careful on road trips.
- And you be careful
of angry monkeys.
I'll see you in school.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
[Trunk slams]
- Standing right here.
Okay.
- [Chortles]
See you when you get back,
okay?
Call me when you get there,
all right?
- Okay.
See you guys later.
You know, I think we all feel
like we're cursed at times.
- What?
- Move over,
little brother.
The question is,
are you gonna let it define
who you are.
- Hey, dad, we're going
to the grand canyon, right?
- Yep.
- But isn't
Murphy rule number 82
to stay away from canyons?
- I think it's time
we bent the rules just a little.
[Bungee cord snaps]
[Electrical zapping]
Both: Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh.
Zap!
- Whoo!
[Crashing]
- ¶ The reason why ¶
- ¶ I thought I was too young
for love ¶
¶ to think that there
could be just one ¶
¶ girl for me ¶
¶ I was never too good
at romance ¶
¶ or maybe just never had
a chance ¶
¶ to love the right girl ¶
¶ and little did I know ¶
¶ that this would be
a crime scene ¶
¶ and I would be the one
to fall ¶
¶ slingshot ¶
¶ love so deadly
that I dropped ¶
¶ the day I met you ¶
¶ just one look
knocked me down ¶
¶ smile so sweet,
I hit the ground ¶
¶ k.O.,
count to ten ¶
¶ 'cause this young heart
won't get up again ¶
¶ it's you and me ¶
¶ and that's the story ¶
¶ of my pretty
little slingshot ¶
¶ slingshot ¶
¶ love so deadly
that I dropped ¶
¶ the day I met you ¶
¶ just one look
knocked me down ¶
¶ smile so sweet,
I hit the ground ¶
¶ k.O.,
count to ten ¶
¶ 'cause this young heart
won't get up again ¶
¶ it's you and me ¶
¶ and that's the story ¶
¶ of my pretty
little slingshot ¶
¶ pretty little slingshot ¶
¶ pretty, pretty,
pretty little slingshot ¶
¶ my pretty little slingshot ¶