Hey, appa.
- Hi, Janet. You come early.
- Yeah.
Doesn't mean
you can leave early.
Thanks.
Did you ask?
- What?
- If you can wear her shirt.
You wearing umma's shirt.
- This is my shirt.
- Okay.
I bought it at Kensington
market, like, a month ago.
And my style is anything
but ajumma style.
- What's ajumma style?
- You know...
"oh!
I don't wanna get
too dark sun tanning.
But in secret I am...
Darth Vader."
Hi, Janet.
What you doing?
Oh, I just came in from outside.
Oh, good. Smart to cover up.
- Don't want to get too dark
from sun tanning. - Hmm.
Huh! What you think
of Janet's shirt?
It's okay. Not really her style.
It's a great shirt.
And not yours.
Yeah. First mine,
then value village, now yours.
You're making that up.
Next time if you like my shirt,
Tell to me before I donate.
And just between us,
it look better on me.
Bye!
Ooh. Now you wearing
appa's style, huh?
Oh, I don't mind.
What happened to floor?
Time takes toll on everything.
And someone scraped it
with a dolly.
Time takes toll.
I have to see Mrs. Lee.
If you go to wholesale,
maybe you pick up some flower.
- Why?
- -because flower is pretty and nice.
Make house bright
and remind us of good thing.
Hint-hint...
The flowers?
- For your anniversary?
- Oh...
- You have to do something.
- I do something.
I stay married for 28 year.
- Appa...
- Janet,
When you get older, you learn
anniversary is just way
For card company to make money,
with flower company
and swan boat ride company.
- Big conspiracy.
- Whatever.
Eh, you think it's so important,
you do something.
Actually, I was thinking
Of hosting a surprise dinner
for you guys. At my place.
You know how surprise work?
But I thought I should
talk to you first
Because I was gonna invite
the whole family.
You, me, umma...
And Jung.
Yeah.
Because I know umma would
really like that.
Probably.
So would you be up for something
like that?
Maybe.
But I don't think Jung would
come if he knows I'm coming.
Jung has moved on.
You're the one who...
- Who what?
- Nothing.
I'm not the one
with the problem.
Jung is usually
the one with the problem.
Well, he has no problem
with this.
Fine. Tell me when is dinner.
- Thursday works for Jung.
- Oh, yeah,
I guess we just work around
Jung's schedule.
Appa...
- Okay.
- Great.
- And bring flowers.
- Why?
Hey, so you told me to pick up
pastries for tomorrow's meeting.
- What are we thinking?
- Uh, pastries.
Got it. But, um, various,
shapes and sizes...
- Just have fun with it?
- Yeah,
This is so stressful.
- Hey, Terence. Just arriving.
- Can't talk.
There she is.
Looking good, for a boss.
Or something more...
Thanks.
But maybe don't lean
on my desk like that.
- Too sexy?
- That, and it kinda blows
the covert entrance
we're going for.
We nailed that
so hard.
Sure, just one small thing...
Oh, I grabbed your coffee
when I got out of the car.
Right.
And when you come in,
might be better
to just be like,
"hi, good morning,"
So it's like the first time
we're seeing each other.
Gotcha.
And just so I know,
How long are we planning on keeping
up the whole spy movie entrance thing?
Uh, for as long as
we both work here?
But I could, like, tell
close friends, right?
Just to be safe,
let's not tell anyone.
I just don't want anything
to change, you know?
I just think that
if we approached this right
And we come up with a game plan to
tell everyone, people might be into it.
Right. Yeah, but it's tricky
'cause I'm a woman in power,
Which means everyone is
just waiting to catch me out
So they can say I'm unfit
or emotionally unstable.
- Yeah, makes sense.
- Which part?
- Um...
- Look, it won't always be like this.
Well, unless we work
here forever.
Exactly.
So, umma,
Any big plans this week?
Yeah, going to superstore
with Mrs. Lee
And getting big box
of rice cracker I like so much.
- And that's it?
- That's a lot.
Superstore, rice cracker.
Sometimes I think
you have add, Janet.
It's just there's
something Thursday
That I thought we could do
together that'd be fun.
Oh, Janet. What?
It's a photography exhibit
that I'm in.
Oh.
But I was thinking you can
come to my place beforehand,
We could have drinks,
then go together.
Yeah, but I just go to
your photography show.
Help you get award.
Best to go out on high note.
This is different.
It's my best work.
Very personal
and all about family.
Maybe your appa want to go
this time. Or Jung. Or appa.
It's just they can't make it,
like, at all.
So you'd be the only one
from the family
That could come to this
really important exhibit
That's all about family.
- Okay.
- Great.
It's gonna be really special.
I have to think so.
Otherwise we get depress.
Jung Kim!
Where you been hiding?
Sorry. Big date.
For two days?
- It's busy season.
- Nice.
And you know I'm all about
my boy livin' his best life,
But a "hey, bud,
don't wait up," wouldn't kill you.
- My bad.
- "my bad" accepted.
Now dish. Have you met
the Hermione to your Ron yet?
A gentleman never tells.
Well, whoever these ladies are,
I'm impressed.
And frankly, a little relieved
you dodged the Shannon bullet.
Uh, yeah.
Swing-and-a-miss, bullet.
Don't get me wrong,
I loves the shannonigans...
For sure.
I was just worried you'd get with
her as soon as Alejandro bounced.
Well, he didn't bounce,
she dumped him.
Probably for a reason.
But... yeah,
Shannon's so not my jam.
Plenty of fish, right?
Aritzia girl.
Or keg waitress.
Totally.
Oh, my god,
are you dating keg waitress?
Definitely not. And by the way,
she's a manager now.
Oh. Good for keg waitress.
Mr. Kim. At the risk
of being formal, how are you?
Okay.
Have you ever heard
of a soft opening?
- Like, new sex something?
- No.
When a high-end restaurant
opens its doors to reviewers
And influencers, before
the rabble ruins the place.
- Free appetizer?
- And more.
Open bar, cigar lounge.
Gorgeous servers,
and in this particular case, us.
Oh! You serious?
Thursday. Seven o'clock.
The party begins.
- Thursday?
- Save the date.
Save date for what?
An unforgettable evening
of gratuity.
Shall I arrange an Uber Black?
Yeah. It's just, uh...
I have to work
at store Thursday.
What?
I can watch the store.
Me and Janet can do
photography show other time.
- Mrs. Kim with the glove save!
- Yeah.
- No.
- Why? What's problem?
I have to... Wax store floor.
You know, because of a scratch
and time take a toll...
Wax another day.
Moscow mules await.
No. Have to wax the floor.
And you have to go
to Janet photography show.
Well, you're a better man
than I,
And a better father
than a friend, that's for sure.
- Good morning, Shannon.
- Maybe don't sit next to me.
Right.
Wasn't going to.
Well, guess I'll just have
a seat next to the boss.
Thanks a lot, guys.
Oh, good morning, Shannon.
So, I'll keep this short.
The head office is rolling out
a new initiative called,
"go the extra mile."
Will there be an exam? I don't want this
coming out of nowhere, like the pastries.
You had a week, Terence.
Anyway, it's a new program
designed to make
our customers feel heard...
Oh, you got
a little something there.
And you, Kimchee, have something
on the sides of your head.
Your earlobes.
Let me just dust
those off for you.
And you, sir,
with that big old neck.
Like the Eiffel tower.
Or la tour on.
And Mr. Fuzzy sideburns here.
Wolf man. Love it.
- And, Stacie, these shoulders...
- No.
Right.
Where was I?
Uh, the point Shannon's
trying to make
Is we're all about
better customer service.
- Exactly.
- So, just to be clear,
Is it no to touching customers
or yes to touching customers?
Hey. Nice cover at the meeting.
Are you kidding? I touched
everyone's face like a pervert.
You're being paranoid.
Stacie just said hi to me.
Hi from Stacie?
And Kimchee knows for sure.
Nah, trust me. He told me
I dodged a bullet
Not getting involved with you.
Really? A bullet?
Like, dating me would kill you?
Yeah! So he's the last guy
That's gonna suspect
we're together.
But what did he mean
by dodge a bullet?
Nothing. That's positive.
You dodge a bullet, and you're alive.
It's a good thing.
Not if you're the bullet
that people need to dodge.
He meant more like it would
ruin our work dynamic.
You know, how you were saying that
how women bosses are crazy and stuff?
- What?
- Who cares what he thinks.
You're a bullet
I'm happy to take.
And the point is,
your secret is safe.
- Our secret.
- Hi, guys.
Stacie, hey.
That was a totally normal,
"hi, guys," right?
It was until you said that.
What is this?
Wax buff machine.
Mr. Addy is a janitor,
he get for us for free.
Oh, that's a nice shirt.
Yeah, want to look good
for customer.
Might get dirty.
Not my favorite shirt, so maybe okay.
Oi, what you doing?
Help.
But you have to go
to photography show with Janet.
Most important.
There's lots of time for that.
The sooner we start,
The sooner you can finish.
Yeah, but once I start,
I can't stop until finish.
Yeah.
- Hi, Anjali.
- Young-mi!
Great news!
Sanjiv hurt his back!
Oh, yay, that's good news.
Thanks for calling.
Best to Sanjiv.
Keep going.
He gave me his tickets
To a swanky restaurant
opening tonight.
Oh.
Cocktails,
champagne, the works!
You'll be my plus one.
Yeah, yeah, I might have time
for quick drink.
I'm leaving now.
I'll text you the details.
Okay.
Okay...
Have to go. See you.
- Going now?
- Yeah.
Bye.
Hello!
Hi.
- Where's your umma?
- She's late.
Like you.
Ah.
I bring gift for you and Jung.
You used to love as a kid, huh?
Uh, mostly Jung.
Was his favorite.
See, I not the problem.
"Thank you, appa.
So kind, so thoughtful."
- Where are the flowers?
- What flower?
Oh, my god, I reminded
you, like, three times.
But I bring cookie, and you don't
even remind me one time, huh?
- Where's Jung?
- He's not here yet.
Ha! See?
It's umma! Hide!
Why?
- Surprise!
- Hey. When does this start again?
Twenty minutes ago.
- Where's the wine?
- Oh.
I'll be right back.
- Seriously?
- Sorry, I got a lot going on.
It's okay, Jung, we forgive you
for being late and forgetting wine.
No, we don't. And you both
came late and empty-handed.
Not empty hand.
And Jung little more late than me.
But not bother me.
- Hey, appa.
- I was waxing.
A little manscaping.
I hear ya.
Oh, I bring this
for you and Janet.
Oh. Uh, thanks.
Hmm. Not a problem.
- Hey, Kim-cheese.
- What's-a-happenin'?
Just ordering the new
"going the extra mile" signage.
What's-a-happenin' with you?
Oh, the uje. Working.
Then on the personal side,
I'm just living that single life.
Livin' it large.
Hells yeah.
You got anything
exciting on tonight?
Nah.
Honestly, I'm still processing
the big break-up with Alejandro.
Feels like I really dodged
a bullet with that one. Right?
I don't know
if you dodged a bullet.
You dated him for two years.
Sure, but what went wrong?
Was it me?
Am I a someone who's bad
to date for some reason?
No. You're amazing.
Any guy'd be lucky
to be with you.
So if I was, say,
fired from a gun,
You don't think there's anyone
who should get out of the way?
Uh... Maybe everyone.
Why did you tell Jung that he
dodged a bullet by not dating me?
Oh. Yeah... That's not about
you being a bad person.
It doesn't feel like
a compliment.
I like you,
I like Jung.
But you're a serial monogamist,
And Jung is a serial...
The opposite of that.
I just think there's potential
for you both getting hurt.
Aww, that's sweet.
Then I'd always have to be choosing
between my boss and my boy,
And it'd be stressful for me
here and at home,
And it'd just...
Kinda suck for me.
Maybe sweet's the wrong word.
Wait, why did Jung
tell you that?
Oh!
You guys are dating?
Yo! That's so great.
Congratulations!
Thanks. But we're trying
to keep it on the d-l.
Right, 'cause if it blows up,
It won't be a big,
embarrassing thing for you guys.
- No, that...
- That's not it at all.
Okay. Then why are you
keeping it a secret?
Hey, guys.
Was that kinda weird?
Yes. You hear it, too.
Thank you.
Oh.
So fancy.
And a real towel.
Those actually stay here.
Oh. Yeah.
Janet? Oh, no,
I lose track of time.
Sorry, I missed
your photography show.
No, you didn't miss it.
There's still time.
Just come to my place now,
and we'll go together.
Oh, but Mrs. Mehta
is still dancing.
Where is she?
Maybe we go meet.
No, I prepared all this.
You got a quiche from Sobeys.
- Janet?
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh, I love this song.
Umma, are you coming?
Yeah, yeah, I leave now.
Right after I finish
this sex on the beach.
Ooh.
Yeah, I'm actually
gonna take off.
You can't.
This is important to umma.
Obviously not.
Where do you have to be anyway?
Let him go. You plan not work.
We do this other time.
There is no other time.
If you want to go, go.
It's just a wedding
anniversary, nothing special.
What's that supposed to mean?
- Okay, let's not get all... - I don't
think you understand what I talking.
I think I understand exactly
what you talking.
Maybe we should have
the cookies now.
- What's your problem? - I don't have
a problem. You brought it up first.
Please, let's not get into it.
What I bring up?
Tell to me what I bring up!
Stop it!
This isn't about you.
Or you!
It's my anniversary.
Dad, you and umma
never celebrate.
That's what
he was talking about.
He didn't think you didn't think
it was special.
He and umma don't think
it's special.
But I do.
And I thought maybe it was worth
celebrating, with all of us.
But if you wanna leave, leave!
And we can forget about this
stupid party that no one wants!
Knock, knock. Hello?
Janet! I'm here.
Oh, thanks to so dangerous taxi.
Jung? Appa?
Why you both are here?
Something wrong?
No, we're here because of you.
For a surprise party.
So... Surprise.
Yeah, surprise.
Surprise from me too.
For your anniversary.
All of you organize this?
Yeah.
- I organized it!
- I bought wine.
I mean I forgot it, but...
And I bring flower. Next time.
So you do all this?
Well, I got the food,
made some snacks,
Did the decorations,
Bought the baguette you like
from the french bakery...
Okay, okay,
we all say thank you, Janet.
- Did you?
- Oh, don't pick fight, Janet.
We all here.
That's most important thing.
What?
Well... Shall we sit?
- Mmm.
- Yeah, okay.
- Something burning?
- Oh, my god!
Dunzo. Nothing like
an end of day trunk lunk.
You've a smudge of something
on your face.
Let me go
the extra mile for you.
Did you guys notice how long Shannon
kept her hand on me at the meeting?
But clearly the biggest connection
was between her and Jung.
There's a little
somethin'-somethin' goin' on.
Okay. I would like
to say somethin'
About that little
somethin'-somethin'.
Yeah. Uh, Shannon would never do
something as unprofessional
As date someone on staff.
That was a totally normal,
professional face wipe.
I thought the sideburn rub
was pretty professional.
And I didn't mean to react
harshly to your shoulder touch,
I'm just shy.
Trying to be friendlier,
say hi more.
Right.
And really,
when you think about it,
Is it so wrong
to date someone at work?
I'm so glad you said that.
How do you feel
about dancing horses?
Because I have two tickets
to see Cavalia.
No, Omar, I...
Thank you, but no.
What I'm saying is Jung and
I are in a relationship.
- Oh. - And it's an amazing
relationship. Very strong.
I have a great feeling
about how long it's gonna last.
- You're overdoing it.
- Maybe I'm just more confident.
Well, anyway, now you know.
I know we only have
a few minutes left,
But let's make then count.
Stacie, do you like
horse-dance theater?
Can I have both tickets?
Hope it wasn't too overcooked.
No. Just enough overcook.
I know it's not easy for
everybody to come. Or to cook.
But this is first time
we all eat together in 15 year.
Sorry, just so touched.
And tipsy.
- Doesn't make less special.
- Mmm.
Well, you and appa deserve it.
Because of you two getting
together, we're all here.
We go.
Look like Jung is leaving.
Actually, I was
just grabbing these.
We haven't had dessert yet.
Oh, yeah.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Mmm.
Yeah.
Ah.
Hmm.
What's the expiry date on these?
Janet,
don't be the problem.
Got him.
Hey, how was dinner?
Uh, good. A little burnt,
and calories per portion were high, but...
I meant having dinner
with the family.
Oh. Uh, not sure.
Not great, but... Not terrible.
- Did you order another pizza?
- No.
- Hey.
- Hey, Kimch,
It's our boss Shannon from work.
Come in, come in.
- You remember Kimch.
- Everyone knows, buddy.
- Yeah...
- Really? That's great.
- That's great, right?
- Yes.
I really wanted to tell you.
It's okay, Shannon filled me in.
I thought maybe
we could grab a drink.
Yeah, I got some beers here.
Yeah, yeah.
We could drink in this apartment.
Grand.
Guys, Gwen's coming over,
So I was hoping
to have the place to myself.
Oh, right. We could go out,
grab a drink.
Thank you.
Or better yet, we could grab
some beers and hit the park.
I can only do so much.