- Who you talk to?
- Shh! I don't know.
How you not know?
You is on the phone.
Ah, I think it's pastor Nina.
She phone me, butt-dial style.
What pastor Nina butt saying?
I can't hear because someone
keep talking too much!
Oh. Oh, yes.
Oh! I think I hear a man.
Maybe it's just a movie?
Ah, but they both laughing.
Frisky or normal?
Now it's quiet.
Frisky.
- Now I hear talk.
- About me?
What they going to say
about you?
I don't know!
That's why I listen!
Hello? Hello?
- Hello?
- Hello? Who is?
Mr. Kim? It's pastor Nina.
I must have dialed you
by mistake.
Yeah. And we must have
answer by mistake.
Is everything okay?
I thought I heard yelling.
Yeah. Everything fine
and, uh,
Not good to listen
to people conversation.
You're right.
But I didn't know it was...
Apology accept.
Enjoy you guest.
- How did you...
- Okay. See you. Bye.
You think she know
we eavesdrop?
I'm still here.
Stop nervous moving.
I'm not.
It's just all the big donors
are here,
And they have
a lot of influence
Over who wins
the Clark medal.
They do?
And isn't one of your photos
upside-down?
Oh, come on.
I thought you hung it?
I did.
Yeah, you is the same way
When you was little
before piano recital.
But don't worry, Janet.
Your photos much better
than your piano.
I'm sorry. Do you mind
If I steal Janet away
to meet some alumni?
Yeah, yeah! Go schmooje.
I'll be right back.
Hmm.
Excuse me.
Is there any meat
in those spring rolls?
Oh, no, no.
It's vegetarian, very good.
- Mmm. I'll have two please.
- Hmm?
Oh.
And a chicken skewer, too,
if possible.
Here you go.
Thank you. And can you take this, please?
Thank you.
So, then,
Gerald doesn't notice
The huge wine stain
on his collar
But keeps asking if there's
anything in his teeth!
It's funny because Gerald
is dumb, huh?
You know what's funny?
Nice lady at event,
um, Mrs. Taylor,
Mistake me for waitress
and make me serve her food.
What?
There was food?
She assumed you were a waitress
because you were Asian?
No, no, no.
I was standing beside food.
Lots of waitress
is Asian people.
Innocent mistake.
It was racist.
Ah! Innocent racist mistake.
Ignorant racist mistake.
You missing joke.
I was wearing same clothes as waitress.
No! It's typical
white, unconscious bias.
Hmm, happen to me all time.
- Really?
- Yeah.
People mistake me for working
in the store every day.
But you do work here.
But how they know that?
See? Racist.
I can't believe you're not
more upset about this.
- Just the way life is, Janet.
- Not you.
Let it go. Enjoy your night.
Okay. We try.
This is the last of your stuff
from my place.
Mostly hair products
and colognes.
- My mango body butter in here?
- No.
I'm keeping the mango
body butter.
Friends said
this might get messy.
Tell your mom I say bye.
Okay.
Take care of yourself, babe.
Probably shouldn't
call me babe any more.
Baby steps, babe.
Looks like splitsville's
got two new residents.
You think?
The box of stuff?
The awkward hug?
Tale as old as time.
Well, Shannon is kind of
an awkward hugger in general.
Well, we'll know for sure
in a minute.
Yup. No look back.
Roll credits on that one.
I mean,
she's probably okay, right?
She will be,
once I make my move.
Time to fly low
and buzz the tower.
What?
Hello?
Owner take such a long time
in the bathroom, huh?
Hello! You have customers here.
So inconvenient.
Aren't you the owner?
You think all Korean
is a store owner?
No. I mean,
you're wearing slippers
And you're always here, so...
Fine. Get out of my store.
So it is your store.
Why you throw out customer?
Because he only see me
as a shopkeeper.
You are shopkeeper.
In Korea, I was a teacher.
Why people not mistake me
for teacher?
I wanted to be nurse.
No one mistake me for nurse.
Wanting to be nurse and being
nurse not the same thing.
Ah, you hardly was teacher...
Just starting.
Once a teacher,
always a teacher.
See? I just
teach you something.
Maybe it was
her comfortable shoes?
I mean, servers love those.
It doesn't matter,
and making excuses for it is even worse.
- You're right.
- I have to say something.
Just letting it go
isn't going to change
- anything.
- I completely understand.
I mean, I could never
completely understand.
Although, I was once
offered change
While waiting for Chelsea
outside the bay.
Not the same thing.
Absolutely.
Oh, sorry.
I don't want to interrupt.
It's just I want to talk
to you about something
That may or may not
be anything. I mean, it's...
I get a 15-minute lunch.
Last night, at the showcase,
A woman thought
my mother was a caterer
And wanted her
to serve her food.
What did your mother do?
Served her the food.
But she was upset?
No, she was happy.
So, does she
need a reference?
No. 'cause she's not a caterer.
And people shouldn't assume
she is just because she's...
Serving food?
Asian.
Oh! Now I see.
I think an apology
of some kind is in order.
It's not 2016 anymore.
This stuff has to stop.
Of course. Did you see
who the woman was?
It was Mrs. Taylor.
It's about principles, you know.
You're right.
And we have a zero-tolerance
policy here at the university.
But just so you know,
it's the Taylor family
That adjudicates
the Clark medal,
So that is something
to consider.
Oh. Right.
Well, I just think people should
know when they do something wrong.
And I will absolutely
say something.
But you can do a bad thing
and not be a bad person.
- Yes.
- And should one mistake
Dictate who you are, forever?
So I shouldn't
say something?
Sometimes not saying anything
Says a lot more than
saying the wrong something.
So I'm saying...
Something. Yes.
I think we have to.
Yes. Final answer.
Yeah, these are
the three we ordered.
Pretty awesome, huh?
Ah, they're so adorable,
it's sick.
The shipment
looks so much smaller.
Yeah, since you made a switch
from big-swipes
To turbo-towels,
you're ordering way less.
Because they're quilted?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Get a room.
- Or a lab.
For all that chemistry.
Turn down the heat on the
Bunsen burners, you two!
- What?
- Sorry. Ah, no.
- Someone else.
- Oh.
But it's great to see, you know?
'Cause they work together,
so when they started
Seeing each other
outside of work,
It was pretty effortless.
Good for them.
Yeah. Good for them,
good for... Others.
Sure.
I mean, what's really
important is that
Gwen was free
of all past relationships,
As far as I know.
Ah, true. Yes, Gwen is...
Was suddenly available.
Right.
Clean slate, ready to date.
Great.
'Sup, Shannon. Got a sec?
Omar! you kidding?
Nothing I like more
than some secs with you.
Some seconds.
Seconds with you.
- Got it.
- And...
Not sloppy seconds... some...
Some good old-fashioned
"time" seconds.
Oh, hello, Ms. Murray.
Mrs. Kim,
you remember Mrs. Taylor?
Oh, yes.
Nice to see you again.
I insisted on coming the
moment I heard what I'd done.
I feel absolutely sick
about it.
No, no, no, no!
It's easy mistake.
I standing right next to
catering table.
You are too gracious,
but it's not who I am.
My daughter-in-law
is Sri Lankan.
I'm just happy Janet is
doing good at school
And she is finalist
for big prize.
I think she might even win,
don't you?
Oh, we really can't say.
Yes. Stiff competition
this year.
But it's true.
She gonna win.
Well, we certainly
wish you well.
You and your husband
have a lovely store.
Why you think I run store?
Don't you?
Do I?
You were stocking cans.
Yeah, I do.
And a dollar from every roll
goes to "truth or bear",
An organization that
rehabilitates wounded grizzlies.
- That's funny.
- Is it?
Sorry, Kimchee.
I just love how you can't
stop talking about her.
- Who?
- Gwen.
You two really have
that spark, huh?
It's, like... boom! Fireworks.
Yeah, our spark is pretty lit.
But a lot of sparks
never spark into anything.
- Gotta put the work in.
- Ugh, boring.
As soon as I feel it,
I go for it. No take backs.
Gary in grade 8, rugby rick,
mason the mason,
Guy I dated before Alejandro
whose name I can't remember.
And how'd those guys
all work out?
Oh, you know. Good.
I mean, the bloom
goes off the rose eventually
And sometimes very quickly.
I just know
Gwen and I would never
Have made it this far
if we rushed it.
- Huh.
- So, about these paper towels...
Marcus! That's what
his name was.
Wow! That was gonna bug me.
What's wrong?
It's my socks.
I'm wearing two lefties.
How can you tell?
How can you not tell?
Oh, Janet. A word?
Sure.
Just letting you know
the apology's been delivered.
Wow. That's great.
Thank you so much.
Was my mom okay with it?
Oh, she handled
the situation very well.
So, congratulations.
Sorry?
Well, it's not public yet,
But it looks like
you're getting the Clark medal.
I won?
Ah.
So, just be sure to let her
know that it's a done deal?
- Sure.
- Great.
Found someone
wearing two righties.
What are the odds?
Oh.
You probably trying to see
what's on the shelf.
- Not really.
- Hmm.
It's a teaching degree.
No, thank you.
Just these today.
- I was a teacher back in Korea.
- Hmm.
But here, people think
I am just a shopkeeper.
I know. People just see me
as a cleaning lady.
Yeah! You's also good cook,
good mommy...
And an excellent
ultrasound technician.
Yeah! Yeah? Yeah!
What subjects did you teach?
So many, hmm?
Geography, history, psychology.
- My son, Javid, is struggling with math.
- Mmm.
Do you think you might be
able to help him?
Yeah! I can help him
with, ah,
Geography, history,
psychology.
And math.
Wonderful.
Thank you so much.
No problem for teacher.
Okay, so, uh,
Four can of noodle...
Adding tax is, uh,
5.89.
Like it says on the machine.
Yeah. Okay.
Hey.
So, I was thinking,
if you're free tonight...
Yes. I mean no. Uh.
I don't know. Why?
What are you thinking?
Uh, well, if you're into it,
maybe we could see a flick?
And then grab a bevy?
Or some chow.
Or a bevy and chow.
Is sounding casual
always this hard?
No. I mean, I can't.
It...
It all sounds great,
But I-i need to take things
slow right now.
Okay.
- Yeah. I thought that we...
- We did. I just...
I'm a rusher.
It's kind of my thing.
Has been for a while.
I end one thing and then
I rush into another thing
And sometimes I don't even
know the new thing's name.
- It's Jung.
- Oh, I know.
And that's what
makes this different,
So I want to keep it
that way
By breaking
my rushy rebound habit
And just taking it slow.
Well, how slow
are you thinking?
Think of it as a yellow light.
Doesn't yellow turn red
before green?
- It does.
- Gotcha.
But it's about the journey,
not the destination.
- Mmm.
- Road trip.
Vroom, vroom! Honk, honk!
Fun, right?
Just wondering when
the owner is coming back?
Just give to me you money.
Thank you.
Guess who won
the Clark medal?
- Me.
- Oh!
Congratulation, Janet.
You see, Janet?
Work and focus.
Even you can be successful.
Thanks, umma.
Is it also possible
that you might have used
The Mrs. Taylor situation
to influence her decision?
What decision?
She judges
who wins the Clark medal.
Ah, no, no. You win,
fair and square.
- Yobo.
- What?
Sometime you sneak attacking
so good,
You not even know
you sneak attacking.
What did she do?
I tell Mrs. Taylor fact.
What's problem?
- Oh, god.
- Simple math.
Innocent racist mistake,
Plus Asian lady suggest
a daughter should win,
Multiply by years
of white guilt
Equal Janet win award.
You welcome.
Hey, if you find a ring
in the car, let me know.
- You lost one?
- No. I want one.
Hey, Jung, do you mind bringing
the blue escape around?
Jung?
I'll get you an escape.
Or die trying.
Did Jung hear you?
Are you going to fire him?
Can I watch?
It's fine.
It's a... Inside joke.
You got me, Jung. Ha-ha.
You can't walk past me
like that.
Oh, I just wouldn't want
anyone getting confused
About the pace of
our relationship, you know?
Wouldn't want anyone
thinking that I would just...
I dunno... drop everything
and move a car around for you.
So you did hear me.
Or it's just
a random example.
Moving cars is your job.
Yeah. And I'm taking it slow,
like you said.
Or I could go slower.
Fine. Slower the better.
Super. You know,
maybe we could go so slow,
We don't even go at all.
Best thing you've ever said.
- So it's decided.
- Oh, it's decided.
- Great.
- Good.
I'm sorry I said all that slow
stuff. I didn't mean it.
- Please stop talking.
- Sorry.
But if you think about it,
we really are going quite slow.
Okay, want me to speed up?
Should I speed up? I'll speed up.
No, no, no! Just mean we've
known each other for years.
So that makes this
way different
Than all those randos I've
rushed it with before, like...
Oh, my god.
I forgot his name.
Okay, now you need to
stop talking.
Yeah, I'm gonna sweep
Shannon right off her feet.
"Sweep". Just as I grab
a broom. That's a sign.
Marcus.
Okay.
Take power
of y times x square.
Transfer zero,
plus math style,
- And you get, ah...
- Wrong.
What? How you know?
'Cause it's what
you did before,
And I heard Siri tell you
it was wrong
When you asked her
in the bathroom.
Okay.
Truth is I only teach math
one time
To cover for friend
who have nosebleed.
My main subject is history.
Yeah. Me, too.
'cause history's easy.
- No!
- Face it, Mr. Kim.
We're not math guys.
We've been at this
for like a million hours
And haven't solved
a single problem.
- Maybe you attitude is a problem.
- I don't think so.
Yobo. Oh, hi, Javid.
How it's going?
Yeah! Good, good, uh?
Lots of number, letter,
adding, subtracting.
Oh, yeah.
But, uh,
sometime is good to have
A second opinion, uh?
For variety.
If, ah, you is teaching,
what you do?
Oh.
Just use more number.
Looking good. Nice work, yobo.
Did I only win
because of my mom?
Janet, so nice to
see you again.
- I need to know.
- You were already a finalist.
I can't accept the medal.
It's art, Janet.
It's completely subjective.
A dart throw at best.
Is an apple
better than an orange?
Is a triangle
better than a square?
I don't know.
And I'm supposed to be
an expert,
And Mrs. Taylor thinks that
Barnett Newman
is the pinnacle of art.
He does stripes, Janet.
The emperor has no clothes.
Hello?
I've seen west side story.
I know how to fight.
Terence. Hi.
Just looking for
a customer's lost locket.
But, uh, no such luck-et.
- Want me to look?
- Not now.
You're off the clock,
so don't go making me look bad.
I forgot the light.
Ah, I can see
your head, Jung.
Better not find that locket
before I do.
Get outta here.
- Here's Janet with medal.
- -mmm-hmm.
And here is medal on table
with no Janet.
And here is a medal
from side view. And the...
Hello, Janet.
Your mother's been telling me
all about the award.
Quite the accomplishment.
Thanks, Mrs. Ada.
- And here the medal from behind.
- Ah.
But I couldn't have done it
without my mom.
That's very sweet of you
to say.
No, really.
She made them give it to me.
Your family
has so many talents.
Mr. Kim.
Just the Kim I wanted to see.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
I already tell Javid he need
to find better teacher.
No. Javid has
never done better.
He pass?
62%.
So... You proud of that?
Ah. Very clever of you
to pretend
Not to know the answers
so javid would teach himself.
Yeah.
It's a old teaching trick.
Thank you so much.
Okay. Bye.
So, maybe we take
this down, huh?
Yeah. Don't have to brag
about everything I do.
Yo. Anybody home?
Uh, where you going?
Oh, sorry. It's your store?
No.
What they don't know
can't hurt them, right?
Hmm. Hard to say.
I could steal
this golf magazine.
Then I'm happy because
I have a free magazine.
But I'm also sad
because I'm stealing
And I hurt owner of store.
Yeah.
- See ya.
- Oh.
She pay for that?
What do I know?
I'm just a customer.
Okay, then. Time to pay.
- What?
- You is a customer.
$10. For magazine and chips.
Still worth it.
Where you going?
Get my chip.