Coffins and bodies were
floating down this river.
Lot of shadowy figures
coming up here,
it's not something
I like to do by myself.
He was just up there
looking down on you.
He knows.
Do you have any regrets
on what happened?
I'm the boss, do what I say.
- Okay.
- Do what I say.
We have a gentleman that comes
down the steps,
he's not a man,
you can see through him.
My god.
That's going off. Everything is
literally going crazy in here.
What the ****
is happening right here?
The dead want a voice.
We just
want to help this family.
The living need our help.
Have you always been here?
He was watching already.
we'd been to derby,
connecticut before.
We have.
And this time
we are investigating
the twisted vine restaurant,
which is the former
birmingham national bank.
It was the bank
for a number of years
and then in the '70s it was
converted to a restaurant.
they have a lot of activity
and they have been having it
for a decade.
I know that the activity
that they're having here
is all the time, things are
being thrown, they heard voices,
they see apparitions,
and it affects people that work
and it affects people that
kind of eat there, too, right?
Yeah, and that's just it.
I think mike, the owner,
he wants to know
what's going on.
He's had staff members
run out after closing
because something happens.
And the activity, like,
it's increasing in frequency.
wasn't there a flood here?
Yes, there was a massive flood
in derby in 1955,
there were
a number of casualties.
Probably one of the more grim
things that happened
was the floodwaters
overtook some cemeteries
that were further up river,
and coffins and bodies
were floating down this river.
If all of that debris
and rubble and death
was coming down this river
and just sort of settled here,
what did that leave behind?
I don't know.
- hey, hi, how are you? Welcome.
- Hi.
This is quite the building.
Actually this building
was a birmingham national bank
that was built in 1892.
So was it directly from a bank
or did it have any other
incarnations?
Went directly from a bank
to a restaurant
in the late '70s early '80s.
Okay, and so then
it looks like a lot
of these furnishings
are original to the bank.
When it was originally a bank,
it had a huge cathedral ceiling,
which is still up
in the attic.
- Wow.
- Okay.
And the windows
are original to the bank,
the vault's original
to the bank is as well.
Now as far as, like, original
artifacts from the bank,
do you have anything
from the bank?
Yeah, we have actually
a bank check,
if you'd like to see it
I can get it.
Yeah, for sure.
Sorry.
This is an original bank
check from 1873.
Wow.
Wow, that's cool.
That's really neat.
Obviously we're here for,
yes, the history,
but we're also here
for the activity,
the paranormal activity
that's happening here.
Have you ever had
any experiences?
We've had things moved around.
We've had voices and nobody
was in the place yet.
Wow, okay.
We've had customers say
they've seen images
while they were here.
Have you ever had people
who are dining here
that kind of up and leave
because of the activity?
Quite often.
Wow. So, I mean, imagine
if it picks up and gets worse.
Like, what would it --
I mean, you don't want
that reputation, obviously,
because then nobody would come.
Absolutely.
We definitely wouldn't, like,
want that reputation, for sure.
- Sure.
Okay, so as far as
the paranormal experiences go,
is there anyone else
we should talk to?
Stacy would be
a great candidate.
Yeah.
All right, so where
can we find stacy?
She's right downstairs.
- Okay.
- After you.
amy and adam, thanks so much.
And here's stacy.
- Hi.
- Nice to meet you.
So what kind of activity
is happening in this space
that has made you want us
to come and figure it out.
Well, we have a gentleman
that comes down the steps
that you guys came down,
lands on the landing down there,
and then you realize
he's not a man,
he's -- you could
see through them.
You could tell
he's not from now.
- Okay.
- He's from the past.
- So what --
- what is he wearing?
- Yeah.
- A long jacket, a top hat,
definitely older style
clothing.
Does he ever acknowledge
anyone else
or look at anyone
or say anything?
Just comes straight down,
kind of lands,
and then he's gone.
We always say the music
must have tracked him down --
right.
...Because that seems to be
when we see him.
I have not seen him.
I hear things and doors opening
and closing and walking around,
but never actually
physically see anybody
except when there's music.
- Sounds like we need a band.
- Yeah, yeah, for sure.
- That would be awesome.
- Some sort of music.
Love the music, for sure.
The lights tend to go nuts.
We get open
and closing doors.
And rumor has it in '55
when we had the large flood
that took out everything,
including some cemeteries,
this was used
as a makeshift morgue.
so besides the lights
being manipulated with
and the apparition seen,
what other --
- when you come in here --
- yeah.
...In this area here I've had
some objects flown at me,
the jukebox would go on,
I'd shut it off, I'd get my ice,
I'd go upstairs, I'd come back,
the jukebox would be on.
Now you said you had something
thrown in here?
I was working on
a Saturday night.
They threw this
sugar caddy at me
and all the sugar packets
went everywhere.
- Weird.
That same week, a couple
that came with a small child,
I guess she was, like,
maybe 4---
...And she started
getting fussy, wanted to leave,
got upset,
her parents asked her why,
she said, "that little girl
is bothering me,"
pointing to the table
next to them.
There was nobody there.
And they actually
didn't eat dinner, they left.
They saw the ghost
of a child.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Good to know.
So what's the frequency
you'd say of activity?
Like, how often is it happening?
Several times a week.
- Okay, so regular, for sure.
- Yeah, it's regular.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
Do you want to take us
anywhere else in the building?
I would love to take you
upstairs --
okay.
...And then the attic.
So I come in at 3:00
every day.
I lock this door behind me
and check my book
because reservations
are generally here.
And a gentleman likes to talk
to me from right here.
- Okay.
- What do you mean?
"hey," I look up, I'm, "hello?"
the first couple of times
I thought somebody was here,
there was nobody here.
Strange.
I've gone up, I've tried,
no other communication.
- Definitely male?
- Definitely male.
Did it sound like
an older gentleman?
Definitely an older,
very curt.
We've had multiple stories
about who it could be,
one of them is
this gentleman sam,
so we all greet him
generally as sam.
Does he respond to sam?
With lights.
So he'll turn on the lights
and stuff.
- He will flicker lights.
- Okay.
Stacy gets more agitated
with every story that she tells.
So obviously something
in this building
is really affecting her.
And this here is
the top floor attic.
What I love about this
is you can see, like,
the original structure
so much.
It's a little glimpse
into this building's past.
And how's the activity here?
There has been
some apparitions,
lot of shadowy figures
that we're seeing up here.
I can tell you,
coming up here,
it's not something
I like to do by myself.
So, at all.
Okay.
So this chair over here
with a little bunny.
- Yeah.
- As you go through the building,
you're gonna see, like,
chairs that'll have
some stuffed animals,
some lollipop, stuff like that.
- Okay.
Those are generally customers
or other employees
that have, like,
left them for the kids.
This is an apparition of a child
in this space?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
And if you've touch
the stuffed animals,
a lot of times
you'll get some activity.
What kind of
activity happens?
Like, they can feel
hot and cold spots.
Okay.
They've caught other
shadowy figures.
Multiple people
have seen them.
Good to know.
All right, let's get set up.
Okay, let's go.
- Thank you, guys.
- Thank you. Appreciate it.
- You're welcome.
- Well, good luck.
Mike and stacy both
really want to find out
who's here and what's here
and why they're here.
They've had a lot
of major crazy activity.
Things are being thrown.
They heard voices.
They see apparitions.
Hopefully we're gonna be able
to get a lot of activity
'cause that's exactly
what we're here to do.
We're here to find out
who they are,
communicate with them
because something is going on
and we got to figure it out.
With mike and his
employees gone for the night,
we are ready to start
our investigation.
Here we go.
Adam and I are headed
downstairs to the lounge
where stacy seems to experience
the most activity.
let's see if we can play
with that sugar thing
and see if we can get it
to fall or...
Absolutely.
This thing.
What if it just
wasn't all the way up?
If that fell, though,
that's gonna hit all those.
I know. But I have seen mice
and rats in restaurants
knock entire glasses
and stuff off shelves.
Yeah, but what
about the other...
My god.
That's going off. Everything is
literally going crazy in here.
What the ****
is happening right here?
So bodies were found.
There's an unidentified body
found over here.
Although the flood
took about 87 lives,
there were a lot of people
from this cemetery
that were disturbed.
This former bank
turned restaurant
is serving up a ton of activity.
Something is here all right
and it has the employees
and patrons running scared.
I have seen mice
and rats in restaurants
knock entire glasses
and stuff off shelves.
Yeah.
My god.
That's going off. Everything is
literally going crazy in here.
What the ****
is happening right here?
Wait, how did that happen?
The jukebox would go on.
I'd shut it off. I'd get my ice.
I'd go upstairs. I'd come back.
The jukebox would be on.
I don't know.
That's going off.
That turned on by itself.
This made a noise.
Like, it came on.
That's still going off.
Okay. We get it. I'm sorry.
All right. So whoever you are,
message received.
Can you tell us
what your name is?
did I upset you?
Are you very protective
of this space?
did you work here
when it was a restaurant
or were you a patron here?
So weird.
All right,
let's listen to this.
Strange.
So what that tells me is someone
attached to the building --
yep.
...Cares about the building.
Yeah, does not like
even insinuating
something bad
about this place,
whether it's a restaurant
or a bank or whatever it is.
And this is what they live
with every day?
Like, this is
what they're working in?
That happens?
And if people are
noticing activity
and they're sitting
at a crowded bar --
- I know. That's crazy.
- That's insane.
And we're here quiet
and look what happens.
All right, well let's
go get our stuff together
and then we'll figure out
what we're gonna do next.
- Okay.
- Ay-yi-yi.
If that happened
while I was here by myself,
I might pee my pants.
So the activity
we got tonight
tells us that somebody's
familiar with the building.
Somebody is very passionate
about the space,
whether it's
a restaurant or bank.
But at this point, we're still
uncertain about who it is.
One of the big things
that happened here
was that there was
a giant flood
that actually brought coffins
up out of the ground
and washed them down the river
and apparently, this building
was used to store those caskets.
Maybe that'll have something
to do with the haunting here.
We asked the local historian
to meet us
at the derby public library
to tell us more about
the catastrophic flood.
We don't have much
to go on yet.
But a tragic event that littered
the town with dead bodies
is a good place to start.
- Hi.
- Hi, folks.
- Are you dan?
- I'm dan. Pleasure to meet you.
- I'm amy. Good to meet you.
- Adam. Nice to meet you.
I'm dan.
Pleasure to meet you, adam.
Now we were really focusing
on the flood
because the building that
we're investigating right now,
there's this idea that maybe
at one point some of the bodies
that had washed away
from the flood
ended up kind of in a makeshift
morgue in the building.
Okay, so bodies were found.
There's an unidentified body
found over here.
It's an embalmed body
found in the river
and it's likely that
these bodies were disturbed
from union cemetery,
which is upstream.
Right here, we have
a newspaper clipping
which says is the scene
at union cemetery.
That's crazy.
And it disturbed coffins
and it disinterred many people.
Although the flood
took about 87 lives,
there were a lot of people
from this cemetery
that were
unfortunately disturbed.
In 1955, anything
that is going to be told
from one person to another,
typically,
you would also find the evidence
you know,
in the form of newspapers.
- Right.
Because the newspapers
report exactly what happened.
Is there any evidence
in all of this
that the old birmingham bank
was a morgue at any point?
I have not been able to find
any evidence
to substantiate that claim.
Because I'm basing
my research on fact,
I can't prove something happened
that I don't find proof before.
Right. No, that's fine.
I mean, there may be
other things, too, you know,
during the time it was a bank.
So I was hoping
to kind of dig in some more
and see if I could find
some more information on it.
Dan, thank you so much
for all of your help.
- The pleasure's mine.
- It's super helpful.
Thank you. Thank you.
Nice to see you.
- Thank you so much, guys.
- All right.
There's so many cases where
we have to sift through, like,
lore and hearsay
versus actual fact
and at the end of the day
we want to do a service
to not only the people
we're helping at the restaurant
but to the ghosts
of the restaurant.
We want to make sure we're
telling their story accurately
and if they weren't the ghosts
of past flood victims,
who were they?
when someone comes to us
and they say that activity
happens at a certain time
or under certain conditions,
we always try to replicate
those conditions.
In this case, stacy told us
that activity really ramped up
when there were bands playing.
So right now we have
a band set up here
and we're gonna use them
as a trigger object.
No one else is here
in the restaurant.
So we're gonna investigate
while they're playing
and record them with the sls
to see if anything appears.
I can say we've never
done this before.
So I'm hoping it works.
I got cold chills in here
and I feel scared.
So I'm empathing somebody
that's been in here
that's, like, freaking out.
We've been told
the apparition
that haunts this former bank
is drawn out
when live music is played.
We're conducting an experiment
we've never tried before
using a band as our trigger
object to help lore it out.
- gone.
- Weird.
- Gone when the music stopped.
- When the music stopped, yep.
We caught an anomaly
on the sls camera
and it's just standing
in the same vicinity
of where they see the apparition
of this gentleman
in a hat and a coat.
We have a gentleman
that comes down the steps
that you guys came down,
lands on the landing down there
and then he's gone.
There's nothing.
Who was this person?
Was he involved here?
Was he someone who died
in the flood? I don't know.
So we're gonna have to keep
investigating, digging deeper,
and trying to figure out who
exactly here is in the space.
now that we lured it out,
we've released the band
so that we can try to
communicate with the spirit
using another trigger object,
one original to the bank.
We're setting up one of
the original bank notes
from the bank that was here
to a proximity sensor
so that if anything touches it,
this little alarm will go off.
We also set up the flux,
the device that can sense
if something is near it
and it also senses
temperature fluctuations.
That's weird.
It shouldn't have gone off.
The flux is going off.
Temperature.
Is there someone here?
Can you tell us your name?
There is a person
that interacts
and they call him sam.
Is that you?
what was your role
in this building?
Do you know any stories
about this bank?
do you recognize
what's on the table,
in the frame right here?
You can touch it
and the alarm will go off,
but it won't hurt you
and you're not in trouble.
what was that,
right there?
- I do.
Clearly.
Intelligent, male.
And he knows
what a bank note is.
So either he's been here
long enough to know
that that's a bank note
and he's seen it
or he's from the time period
and there it is.
Yeah.
I mean, he knows
that it's based on that.
We've got an evp that said,
"I do."
like, it knew
what the bank note was.
But other than that,
it was very quiet.
Whoever this person
is does not want to talk to us.
We've experienced
a lot of paranormal activity,
but we've got nothing
to confirm
who we are speaking with.
today we decided to use
chip to our advantage.
And so, he came in not knowing
anything about the building,
where we were,
the history of it, nothing.
We want to know
who does he pick up on
and whatever he picks up on,
how much of that correlates
with the activity
that we've been having.
old man,
the impression is,
"I'm the boss."-
I hear a very snide voice
in my head say,
"I've got the keys.
I'm the boss. Do what I say."
"do what I say."
you've got some illegal activity
that happened in this building.
- money changing hands.
- Okay.
The spirit that
roams the halls
of the twisted vine restaurant
refuses to speak
with adam and me,
so we're bringing in psychic
medium chip coffey
to help level the playing field
and move our investigation
forward.
The thing he said to me is,
"I have the keys."
okay.
interesting stuff
in this building.
Yeah.
Like off the wall interesting
stuff in this building.
Where are the other levels at?
How do you get
to the other levels?
Downstairs is this way.
this place makes me woozy,
like physically...
it's like I'm drunk.
They have stuff
that moves down here.
It's definitely
an active spot down here.
You've got some illegal activity
that happened in this building.
money changing hands.
Okay.
Whoever is here, whatever
is here is very secretive.
It's got stages of stuff
is what I'm feeling.
And it's confusing because
there's a lot of stuff
that's going on in my head.
The most prominent
that I've gotten so far
is the grumpy old man
that feels like he is, like,
in charge of stuff
and, you know, "don't mess
with me. I'm in charge."
And totally random
and out there, a drowning.
I wouldn't be surprised
if it's a child.
A little girl.
- Okay.
Anything else you want
to ask me about down here?
Do you mind if we take
just a walk through?
Yeah, just walk around the bar.
- Not a problem.
- Yeah, just kind of...
Okay.
And I just got pushed
in the back.
I got cold chills in here.
I don't pick up
anything specific,
but I pickup that people
get weirded out in this space --
okay.
...By things either moving
or touching
or something like that.
And I feel scared.
Some empathing,
somebody that's been in here
that's, like, freaking out.
So as chip walked through
the building,
he picked up on a little girl.
He also picked up
on an older male,
who seemed very protective
of the space,
who seemed very secretive.
It's interesting that chip
brought up money changing hands
because this was a bank
and so, that makes sense.
But he also said
that he got kind of a vibe
of something
not really on the level,
something shady going on.
And so, armed
with that information,
we'll go into
the investigation tonight
and start bringing
that up to see
if it triggers
any more activity.
- okay, I need to show you this.
- Okay.
I've never seen anything
like it on this dvr.
Really?
So this is the camera that's up
in the attic, right?
- Right.
- Nobody's here in this space.
It's like 4:00
in the morning.
Now when you watch it,
see how there's movement here?
- Yeah.
- Okay. Watch right here.
Okay.
- See that?
- Yeah.
Okay. What happens to the dvr
when that shows up?
It just stops.
It literally stops our entire
system for about 25 seconds.
Wow.
It just is, like, poof!
That's so strange.
I've never seen
anything like that.
I've never been to a place
where things
just constantly
get messed with.
Like, I mean, obviously,
that's been a report of ours
for a long time.
We've seen it
on a smaller scale,
but this place is like...
Like, I've just never seen
anything like it.
The fact that the dvr
just stops...
I don't even know.
okay.
Well, I just did a search on,
like, death, tragedy.
Derby, connecticut,
November 18, 1913.
Samuel. H. Lessey,
cashier of the birmingham
national bank here,
committed suicide in a vault
in oak cliff cemetery
on the outskirts of the city.
We all greet him
generally as sam.
My god.
Some time today, his body
lying in a coffin box
was found in a vault
shortly after midnight
by chief of police,
odell and officer kennedy.
A bullet hole was in his temple
and one of his hands
clutched a revolver.
He put himself in a coffin.
He literally killed himself
in a coffin.
- In a vault.
- In a vault. That's crazy.
Deceased highly respected
in derby.
Lessey had been connected
with the bank 25 years.
He was married,
had two children.
Wow!
Two worthless checks had
recently been deposited
at the bank.
So this criminal, he received
a check for $15 and one for $10,
and he added zeros to them.
So he basically took $2,500
under mr. Lessey's watch.
It was a scandal.
You've got some illegal activity
that happened in this building.
money changing hands.
So is that why
he killed himself?
Because he thought
it was his fault.
Mr. Lessey was made cashier
of the bank.
He worried a great deal
over the matters
which had come to him
with the new position.
Wow! It could be the sam
who goes downstairs,
because what if the --
- I know.
- It's like the way he's dressed.
- What if the --
- he's going to the vault.
- Yeah, the way he's dressed.
- He's going to the vault.
- Yes.
- What is he wearing?
- Yeah.
Like a long jacket,
a top hat.
Definitely
older style clothing.
- I know.
- Girl, chills, these chills.
We did get a name tonight
from a newspaper article
that I found just before
we started to investigate,
and the name happened to be sam.
We thought we'd just go right
for that and see if bringing up
that gentleman
and his job at the bank
and what happened would give us
any sort of response.
So let's go to the attic.
All right, let's try it.
You know what?
We'll bring the bank note
and use the proximity sensor.
The third floor in the attic
is one of the most
original spaces in the building
because it has virtually been
untouched since it was a bank.
It's a space
that we want to get into.
We want to investigate and we
want to try to connect with sam
because sam is an original
person to the building.
He was connected to this
building from the day
it was built.
We keep hearing stories
about this gentleman
named samuel lessey.
Is he still here?
The temperature changed.
He worked here
for quite a long time.
I hate to bring it up. I know
it's not a pleasant topic,
but it's just so hard
to believe
and your family
moved right after.
Your wife took the kids
and went to new york
and then after that...
it's going off.
Okay. After that,
your daughter...
- Shah.
again.
Temperature.
Your daughter grew up
and became a teacher.
I don't believe
she ever married or had kids.
it's really going off.
he was just up there
looking down on you.
He was?
Yep.
This is going off.
That's going off.
Do you want us to get the hell
out of your building?
The old cashier at this
former bank,
sam lessey,
may have killed himself
because of some shady
business deals.
We think his spirit could be
attached to this restaurant.
It's really going off.
so it seems we hit
some sort of nerve.
Samuel, mr. Lessey,
I'm gonna stop talking
about this for now. Okay?
So can you leave that alone
and I'll stop talking about it.
Okay? Okay,
I turned off the recorder.
okay, we're back. All right.
It's back to normal.
I'm gonna listen to this.
I mean, it really goes in line
with the electronics.
And it was when we were talking
about sam and his family,
what happened to him,
what happened to her, basically.
Yeah.
It's just so strange.
Like every time
we bring up, like, the building
and we bring up him, like,
something starts getting messed
with electronically.
So why is he choosing
to communicate that way
and what can we do
to encourage him to just
use words and speak?
This might be a case
where it comes down to chip
because chip's the only one,
like, if he picks up on this guy
and can actually talk to him
and communicate with him...
Yeah.
All right, so let's
pack this up.
If he's here, if sam is here,
chip is gonna pick up on him.-
this guy likes to mess
with equipment
so I think the idea here is that
we need to blanket this place
with anything that can be
manipulated, rem pods, k2s --
yep.
- Anything electronic.
- The flux, all of it.
This entity has been
manipulating our equipment.
We've got so much activity
in terms of equipment
going off and interaction.
And I mean,
the space is haunted
and we're hoping
that chip can connect
with whoever is doing this
and tell us who it is
or at least give the message
and figure out why this person
is in this space.
Has there been activity
that's been malicious
or threatening
in this building?
- No, it's just very...
- Authoritative.
It is. It's very, like,
the second that you can do
something wrong
or, like,
I said something potentially bad
about the building downstairs
and everything lit up.
Yeah.
He's just very protective
of the building.
He's very ocd and anal retentive
and wants things done.
And even if the staff that works
in the restaurant here
is doing something
and they're making an oops ---
You know, that may be when
he's like, "hey, hey, hey."
he was just up there
looking down on you.
- He was?
- Yep.
So he's watching already.
He knows.
- Yeah, he does know.
- For sure.
On the stairs, on the stairs.
- I saw a shadow.
- I did, too.
- What? You saw it?
- Yeah. Right there.
Yes.
It was as tall as that crook
corner where it comes in.
- That's what they see.
- And it was, like, boop,
and it would
just went right down the stairs.
So does that mean you want to
talk to us now or are you ready?
Mr. Lessey? Well, this is
your time to shine.
This is your time
to get it all out.
Did you see that?
I did.
That went off.
This went off at the same time.-
Sam's who you're
looking at here.
Just let me tell you
that's what I feel.
So sam, mr. Lessey,
did you actually
kill yourself?
this is going off.
That's going off.
This is going off.
My.
did you commit suicide?
- It's going off.
- That is pinging loudly.
He's dodging.
That's...
We're in derby,
connecticut and we're not alone.
- Did you see that?
- I did.
Going off. That went off.
This went off at the same time.-
Something has attached
itself to this old building
and hopefully
chip can connect with the spirit
so we can find out
what it wants.
mr. Lessey, I know you love
lighting up all this stuff,
but if you talk in this
as close as you can,
as loudly as you can,
and just answer
these questions for us.
Did you commit suicide?
if you did that, why?
That's going off.
Yep.
That's...
- It's acknowledgement.
- It is acknowledgement.
It's like he still
will not tell us.
Frustrating.
He doesn't want
to talk about it.
- I know. I feel terrible. Okay.
- Play it.
Sam, light that up
all the way.
I've never been anywhere
so devoid of evp's.
He's dodging.
This is going off.
It's the first time
that's gone off the entire time.
But he's just setting off
everything.
I know.
Can we ask him one thing?
Do you want
to just be left alone?
Yeah, let's just ask him that.
sir, do you want us
to just leave you alone?
- it's going off.
- That is going off.
Do you want people
to just stop bothering you?
- Yeah, it's going off.
- That is pinging loudly.
Wow. That's crazy.
He just wants us
to leave him alone.
Do you want us to get the hell
out of your building?
that's a yes. We've got it.
I mean, I think
we have answers for them.
I think they're
gonna be thrilled.
It's definitely
not what they expected.
I think at the end of the day
you have a man
who chose his position here
within this building over life.
Like, he had a family,
he had everything,
and the second that his place
in this building
that he worked for
for so long was jeopardized,
he would rather have
just killed himself.
Yes.
And that's what he did and so
he's just here continuing on.
This is a really
interesting case for us
because it's one of those cases
where we had a ton of activity
from start to finish.
All of our equipment
was being manipulated
and that is very, very rare.
Also, what's rare
is getting very little
evps but sam was able
to communicate with us
that yes, it was him.
Yes, these things happened
to him in the past and no,
he doesn't want to talk
about it anymore.
He just wants to do his thing,
make sure this business
is running smoothly
and live out
the rest of eternity,
I guess in a space
he really loved.
- hi.
- Hi, guys.
How are you? Good morning.
Have a seat.
We're good.
It's been a really exciting
few days.
So just to kind of get into it,
we'll just say right off the bat
that you have
a very haunted restaurant.
Wow.
Yeah, so we can definitely
confirm that for you.
That's crazy.
One of the most active cases we
have done in a really long time.
Wow.
The first night,
we went downstairs,
we were in the basement
and we were investigating
the claim of the sugar bowl
flying and things,
and so, we were
putting it up there.
And I've said, I investigated
a restaurant once
and what they didn't realize
was that they had rodents.
And then right at that moment,
the jukebox turned on,
all of our equipment
went off all at once --
wow.
...Everything,
which is really impossible.
- Yeah.
- Then I said, I'm sorry.
Again, I'm not saying
that's what's happening here.
We're just trying
to figure out,
so if you want to tell us
who you really are
and what's happening,
that would be great.
- Right.
- Nothing, just quiet.
While the activity
was massive and frequent,
it was just nothing
identifiable.
And so we really had
to kind of think outside the box
to figure out
who's haunting the twisted vine.
We had the help
with historical society
and they actually pulled out
newspapers from the time period
and we scoured
every one of them,
but there was zero mention
of this place being a morgue.
Okay.
It's hearsay, it's legend,
it's folklore.
But in terms of factual
identifiable information,
that wasn't something
that we were able to find.
And that's fine because you want
to get to the root of it
and you want to figure out
who's really haunting the place.
Absolutely.
As we kind of dug
more into this case,
we thought maybe it's someone
associated with the bank.
What I'm gonna do
is I'm going
to put a newspaper article up
and I want you to read it out
loud for us. Okay?
Okay.
Bank cashier ends life
in cemetery.
Samuel h. Lessey of derby
found dead in coffin box.
He had been censored Saturday
for carelessness,
which enabled an alleged
forgery of checks.
Wow.
- Boy.
- Right.
Sam.
- Yeah.
- Wow.
He was here when the bank
was made.
He's part of this bank
becoming a thing --
yeah, part of the process, wow.
...And so he essentially died
for this building.
- Wow.
- Everything was taken from him
when he was accused
of letting this happen.
He would not talk to us.
Like, chip picked up on him
right away when chip came in
and he let him know I have
the keys to this building,
is what he said right away.
Chip also picked up
on your little girl, who's here.
He did.
We did not get any evidence
of her.
But that doesn't mean
she's not here.
No.
Do you think
he'll get comfortable
if we treat him properly?
I think so.
And I think it would be great,
whenever you guys can, to just
kind of pay your respects.
We will.
And maybe just have something
here in the restaurant for him
so people remember his legacy
and what he went through.
New dinner special.
Because he wants to be here
and he trusts you guys.
How do you know he trusts us?
The way that he interacts
with you guys.
You say hi,
he says hi to you
sometimes when you in
that gruff hello voice.
Yes.
Like, he doesn't do that
for anyone else.
And that's really great so
nothing to be afraid of, though.
- No.
- No, definitely not.
I can't thank you guys enough
for bringing this to us
because it's important
to us, you know?
Yeah. Unbelievable.
Thank you.
I'm glad we could do that
for you.
What I love about
mike and stacy
is that they have a genuine
want to get this right.
And so when we came here,
they were pretty desperate
because they were having
activity constantly,
day and night,
but they just wanted to do right
by whoever it was.
They've been here so long
and they've interacted
with him so much already.
He's like family to them.
This is one of those cases
where they definitely don't have
anything to worry about,
you know.
This is a man who had
such a deep attachment
to this building that all
he wants is the best for it,
and that all he wants
is the best for them.
And so if anything, they should
feel safer in this building now
knowing that he's here,
you know,
looking over things
even when they aren't.