In the criminal justice system,
sexually based offenses
are considered especially heinous.
In New York City,
the dedicated detectives
who investigate these vicious felonies
are members of an elite squad
known as the Special Victims Unit.
These are their stories.
Dr. Lindstrom,
thank you for staying late.
Of course, Captain.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
I actually owe some of that to you.
So, what, you're coming
to thank me or...
Ah, no.
Ed. Tucker.
I've been invited to his
retirement party tonight,
and I haven't seen him
since I broke it off.
- Ah.
- It's crazy.
I've had guns in my face,
and I'm afraid...
to see an ex‐boyfriend.
Do you know what you're afraid of?
Regret...
or... the pain that I caused him.
Well, I can give you this.
Whatever your regrets or your... guilt,
it's harder in the long run
to leave things unsaid.
Rachel... you're headed out?
An old police colleague is retiring.
I wanted to help with the send‐off.
NYPD.
You sure that's a good idea?
I won't stay long,
and I won't drink.
[SIGHS]
[BACKGROUND CHATTER, MUSIC PLAYING]
Fin...
I didn't expect to see you
at Tucker's retirement party.
- I'm here for you, not him.
- Oh.
Rollins, you brought reinforcements.
Yeah, they let him out for an hour.
Yeah, barely.
Thank God I aged out of sleep.
- How you doing?
- Thanks, guys.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Who's the... who's the woman
with Tucker?
You asking us?
Yeah, we got you in the divorce.
The bartender told me that's
his... that's his new wife.
She's a nurse. They eloped a month ago.
Oh.
Good for him.
So when I decided to throw
a farewell party
for my old friend Ed Tucker,
I said he's, "He's IAB."
Where were gonna hold it,
a phone booth?"
[LAUGHTER]
So this is how it's gonna go?
The truth is when you have
a friend like Ed,
you're blessed.
I met him back in
our cowboy days at NYPD,
long before I retired
to make the real money.
Is he giving a toast or bragging?
[UNEASY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
So after we've all imbibed,
I'd like each of you to come down
and make a toast to "Mister Ed,"
like I'm doing now.
[CLAMORING, CHEERS]
- Not too late to sneak out.
- Nope, he's just seen me.
I guess I should introduce
myself to his new wife.
[MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ ♪
- Ed.
- Olivia,
I'm so happy you've made it.
Of course. Mazel tov.
Hi, I'm Olivia Benson.
Patty Tucker.
I have heard so much about you.
Oh, wow. Okay.
- All good.
- There he is!
God, you still have your hair,
you bastard!
I don't know if you've met
my old bald partner, Gary Wald.
Hey, I took a bullet for you
back at the Two‐Two, my brother.
Yeah, not on purpose, and he
never lets me forget it either.
Who's the man of the hour?
Rachel.
And his old partner Gary,
still riding high in the saddle.
Rachel, long time no see.
Rachel and I went
to the Academy together.
- How have you been?
- Not as good as you.
I hear you have a son,
you made Captain.
Those good old boys
really looked out for you.
- Rachel, she paid her dues.
- Not like I did.
Rachel, you still a bourbon drinker?
I'm good.
I just wanted to look my
fellow officers in the eye,
one more time.
Hear no evil, see no evil...
and evil.
- Oh!
Ed.
God, Ed!
I'm all right, I'm all right.
Just maybe a couple of napkins.
You look like you could use a refill.
I'll make that a double afterwards.
Ed, what the hell was that about?
I have no idea.
I could barely even place her.
[UNEASY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[SIGHS]
Anyway...
I've said my piece.
It's on the rest of you now.
Again, my name is Rachel Wilson.
I'm a former New York City
police officer...
until I was pushed out of the club
a dozen years ago.
I'm making a video at the crime scene.
I am the victim.
She has two sons.
They're good kids,
but they're testing me.
Uh, teenage boys.
I just don't know
if I'm ready for that.
I'll have to use some of my old
IAB psych tricks to keep them in line.
[CHUCKLES]
[GUNSHOT]
[CROWD COMMOTION]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪ ♪
It's the car.
- It's locked.
- Oh, my God.
[HANDLE CLUNKS]
[OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
Uh, this is
Captain Olivia Benson of SVU.
10‐13 from 1‐6‐9 and Broadway.
Off‐duty P. O. shot. Rush a bus.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Liv?
She didn't make it?
She knew what she was doing.
She shot herself through the heart.
I'm sorry.
Well, I saw her
throw a drink at Tucker.
- What was that about?
- No idea.
You know, I knew her, we were friends.
I hadn't seen her in awhile
and, uh, she was bright,
she was ambitious, and then...
and then I knew that she had
a rough time over at Vice,
and she just... she just
crashed and burned.
Rest in peace.
We've been saying that too much.
[SIGHS]
Heard you guys had a rough night.
Been a lot of those lately.
Captain knew her?
She doing okay?
That and the loss
of her brother, it's a lot.
She's been on the phone
with 1PP all morning,
the grief guy's in there with her now.
Chief Garland says we all
gotta check in with him.
All of us? Is that necessary?
Yeah, I mean, we need
to start talking about this,
and not sweep it under the rug.
Okay, everybody, listen up.
Listen up.
- Is that the grief guy?
- Yeah.
- You okay?
- [SIGHS]
Not great, but I'm dealing with it.
Thanks, Fin.
So as you all know,
we lost one of our own last night.
She was a good woman.
This is an epidemic.
More of us are dying by our
own hand than somebody else's.
Dr. Lindstrom is here
to speak...
with every single one of you.
Thank you, Captain Benson.
I know the last thing
many cops wanna do
is talk about feelings or fears.
And we know that this is a stigma,
but the department policies
have changed, thank God,
and asking for help is
no longer a sign of weakness.
We've all been to way
too many police funerals.
We can't afford to lose another
brother or sister.
Thank you.
Like I said,
I've got a supportive family.
They survived the Civil War in Lebanon
and came here with nothing.
We look out for each other.
I'm glad you have that.
- Thanks for humoring me.
- Yeah.
You're up.
Sergeant Tutuola.
I'm guessing Kat didn't open up.
I can't really talk about
another officer.
Everything anyone says
to me is confidential.
Is that right? Let me ask you this.
If someone came in here and told you
they were going through
a really rough time,
you'd report that?
We're setting up a system
that allows cops
to make appointments
with outside therapists
completely anonymously.
But you work for the police department.
In this capacity, yes.
But the department is more
concerned that people get help,
rather than worrying
about their records.
Yeah, but NYPD can still
take my weapon away.
Well, if it's warranted, yeah.
And send me to the rubber gun squad.
So why would anybody
ever tell you anything?
The thing that gets me
is that way that Rachel
was talking last night.
It was like...
it was like I had the life
that she should've had.
I'd take that with a grain of salt.
Back then, NYPD...
being a woman was hard enough,
but being a woman of color?
Yeah, I get that, but it was
probably more than one thing
that pushed her over the edge.
It just bothers me
because a few years ago,
we ran into each other and we
said let's get a cup of coffee.
And then I adopted Noah
and I got promoted
and just never followed through.
And you can't be responsible
for everybody.
- I know, I just wish...
- [KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hey Captain, you got a minute?
Sure. What's up?
- You need the room?
- Yeah, yeah, kinda.
It's not about you.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
What's going on?
It's about Rachel Wilson's suicide.
The investigators recovered
her cell phone from the scene.
She made a video statement
right before she killed herself.
Several years ago,
I was violently assaulted and raped
by a superior officer.
I went to my sergeant, IAB.
They all conspired
to protect my attacker.
I'd name names here, but...
it doesn't matter anymore.
He won. I lost.
I so was proud to be a cop...
But the system betrayed me.
NYPD will always protect
who they see as their own...
And they didn't protect me.
Anyway...
I've said my piece.
Now we know why she threw
that drink at Tucker.
And he said he has no idea why.
And you believe him?
I don't know what to believe,
and I don't know what to do about it.
Yes, you do.
[SIGHS]
_
You've got to forgive us.
We just closed down the house last week
so everything's at sixes and sevens.
Oh, I know what that's like.
Ed, you have company.
- Olivia.
- Hey.
I'm sorry, to barge in.
I'll leave you two.
Thanks.
What's going on?
- Is this about Rachel Wilson?
- It is.
It turns out that Rachel,
made a video before...
she shot herself.
She said that she was
sexually assaulted
by a colleague on a job.
Did she give a name?
No, but she said there was a cover‐up.
She brought it to IAB, but
there was nothing in the files.
First I'm hearing about it.
Really?
'Cause it seemed like
she knew you at the party.
What was that about?
I'm not sure.
How long ago?
I was hoping that you could tell me.
Ed, she... she threw a drink at you.
I'm sorry.
I'm at a loss, Liv.
I must've done 600 cases at IAB.
I'd, you know,
have to dig out my notes.
I want to believe you, Ed. I do, but...
you just did something
that you never did
when we were together.
What's that?
You lied to my face.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Tucker lied to you?
Or Rachel lied in the video, but...
I don't think so.
Tucker seemed off.
Never trust an IAB cop,
no matter how close you've been.
- Fin.
- You know,
how do we even work this case?
Are we supposed to go back and check
every supervisor she's ever had?
Okay, before we cast the net that wide,
let's look into who was
in her life now.
Maybe she disclosed to someone.
_
NYPD, huh?
You people didn't honor her in life,
but now you're gonna
honor her in death.
Why do you say that, Reverend?
You threw her away.
Not only one of the finest cops
I've known,
but one of the best people.
That's what we hear too.
I knew her since she was a child.
I saw her go from being
top of her class
to a step from homeless
these past few years.
I'd been letting her sleep
in the church basement.
Mental health? Drug problems?
Yes, but don't let yourself
off the hook that easy.
Department pushed her over the edge.
Rachel made some accusations
about being abused on the job.
Now did she tell you
anything about that?
Damn right she did.
She said she'd been raped
by someone she worked with.
- Did she say who?
- No.
Just that it was when she was at Vice.
Now, pardon me, I...
I have a eulogy to prepare.
Thanks.
Vice?
I ran Rachel's NYPD records.
She was there in 2004.
I think my rabbi was at Vice back then.
If he knows something, he'll tell me.
Yo, Ralphie!
Ah, baby girl!
- [LAUGHTER]
- Hey!
Captain Benson, meet Sergeant Morris.
- Hey, how you doing?
- Oh, so you're the one
who stole her from me.
Keep an eye on her, she's going places.
- Oh, she's already arrived.
- Yeah.
What can I do for you?
We're taking a closer look
at what happened to Rachel Wilson.
[SIGHS] Rachel.
Terrible thing.
Aleha hashalom.
Third cop I know.
Rachel made a video, before she died
accusing someone she worked with
of raping her.
She did?
It may have been someone in Vice.
Well, uh, I didn't know her that well.
I mean, a few months after I came in,
- she transferred out.
- Sergeant...
I told the Captain that
you were a straight shooter.
I don't like speaking ill of the dead,
but Rachel had a rep.
Look, Kat here is a good girl,
but Rachel...
She got around.
Anyway, the guys who were there
before me could tell you more.
Okay, well,
it's a matter of public record, but...
Anyone in particular?
Top of my head?
Our captain.
Gary Wald.
I just met him.
He runs a security firm, right?
Yeah, big shot now.
Hey, can I ask a favor?
He's got a lot of juice.
Keep me out of this.
_
I landed in clover after retirement.
U. S., international, cyber security.
- Looks like it pay.
- Yeah, it does!
And we hire a lot of ex‐cops.
Beats a foot post on
Pitkin Avenue, right, Roscoe?
But I'm guessing you didn't
come out here to talk security.
We're here about Rachel Wilson.
- You mind?
- No, no.
We all just saw her.
She had really fallen apart.
And to take her own life...
it's heartbreaking.
You were her captain at Vice?
Yeah, yeah. She was, um...
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, she was something.
What is that? A euphemism?
- You were on the job, right?
- Yeah.
She was a talented undercover,
but she had issues.
Turns out she made a video in the car.
Yeah, I heard your captain
already talked
to Ed Tucker about that.
You ever hear any talk about
Rachel being assaulted
while she was at Vice?
Rachel. Cone of silence?
Yeah.
She was like a live sex grenade
with the pin pulled out.
She rolled from man to man,
and when he started to back away,
she'd threaten to blow his life up.
I warned Tucker about this
back when he called me
chasing some story,
but Rachel put new meaning
into Internal Affairs.
So Tucker really did look into this.
Yeah, he came to the same conclusion...
that Rachel was a fabricator.
I mean, I tried to help her,
but you know,
sometimes when you try to save
a drowner, she pulls you under.
Now take it easy, boys.
I haven't finished paying off
my last credit card bill.
Hey Tucker, you cracking the whip?
Trying to fast‐track a
new kitchen for my wife,
with nonunion labor.
Guys, just put it down
on the inside of the door,
- I'll be right in.
- Actually, Captain,
we need you to come with us.
We have a few questions.
You couldn't call first?
Avoid embarrassing me
in front of my family?
You do that when you were IAB?
That was different.
I was dealing with dirty cops.
Can you give me a minute and
let me tell my wife where I'm going?
We'll wait right here.
[TENSE MUSIC]
Why'd you tell Benson
you didn't know Rachel Wilson?
No, what I said was,
"I couldn't place her."
But you were at IAB
when Rachel Wilson claimed
she was assaulted
by somebody at Vice, right?
I was.
That was 15 years ago.
I honestly had no memory
of it at first.
At first, but... but you do now.
Yeah, it, um... it came back to me.
She, uh, she talked about
filing a complaint,
but it never went anywhere.
She accused Gary Wald,
Right?
Your former partner?
Yes or no, Tucker?
Yes, she did.
We looked into it.
There were charges and countercharges.
Between Rachel and Gary?
About the assault, yeah.
But also about other relationships
she was having
with other guys on the job.
If she had filed,
a formal complaint
against Gary at that time,
there would've been
four broken marriages,
her career would have been ruined.
It was ruined anyway. She fell apart.
Yeah, I know,
and I feel terrible about that.
But at the end of the day,
it was her choice,
not to pursue.
"Her choice."
It sounds like she was slut‐shamed
into keeping her mouth shut,
and Tucker made sure she understood
exactly how that was gonna play out.
I just can't, I can't see Tucker...
covering up a rape.
Even...
Even if she had a rep.
It happens all the time, Liv,
and if you ask me,
he's still covering it up.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Kat, we're in the middle of something.
Sorry, um, I just...
What? What's the matter?
Um, my old sergeant, Ralphie Morris,
he just killed himself.
[DARK MUSIC]
Two hours after we talked to him.
[BACKGROUND CHATTER]
Get away from me Katriona,
I got nothing good
- to say to you.
- Mrs. Morris.
We're so very sorry for your loss.
You the other one he was
talking to before he shot himself?
- Proud of yourself?
- I understand that you're upset,
but something as horrible as this
doesn't just come out of nowhere.
Marie, you know Ralphie
meant the world to me,
and I pray that
it was nothing that I did.
It wasn't just you,
this had been coming a long time.
- I had no idea.
- No one did.
But I must've called the department
a half dozen times the last few years,
telling them to take his guns away.
Why? What was the matter?
What wasn't the matter?
My Ralphie was an ox,
but this job wore him down.
People dumping buckets
of water on him in the street,
politicians blaming the cops
when anything goes wrong.
We're upside down on a second mortgage
to pay for our son's rehab.
Being a parent and being a cop,
believe me, we... we all get it.
Then tell me why couldn't
he get the help he needed?
Look, I'm so sorry
to ask you this, but...
Can you tell me what happened today?
He came home distraught,
talking about killing himself.
I was on the phone
begging with 911 while he...
he was screaming into
his phone in the other room...
Right before I heard the shot.
Any idea who he was talking to?
He made a few calls,
but I know the last one
was to his shrink.
This is awful news, Olivia.
I can't imagine how you're feeling.
I can't imagine what you're feeling.
I don't think I understand.
Sergeant Morris was your patient.
How would you know that?
His widow told us that
he made a series of calls
before... he shot himself.
The first two were to burner cells.
We're triangulating those.
But the last one... was to you.
You heard his final words.
Olivia, when you told me
you needed to see me right away,
I thought it was because
you needed help.
I do need help.
You have information
that is relevant to our case.
We have spent a lot
of time establishing trust.
If you wanna question me for a case,
you can't come here under a pretext.
And I hear you,
but if Ralph revealed anything
to you that could help us...
I cannot reveal it to you.
I am sworn to protect
my patient's privacy.
- And he's gone.
- He's gone,
but confidentiality
extends beyond the grave.
Well, so you know...
if you can't see a way to help us,
then the DA's office
is going to subpoena you.
Well, then I'll see them
in court, Olivia.
Now, you'll excuse me.
I lost a patient tonight.
It's not your problem,
but I think you can understand
what I'm feeling right now.
_
Your Honor, we believe that
Dr. Lindstrom has evidence
that is crucial to an ongoing
SVU investigation.
Now, it's evidence
we can't get any other way
because the complaining witness,
and another key witness,
Dr. Lindstrom's patient,
are both deceased.
Dr. Lindstrom,
without asking you
to reveal anything specific,
can you advise the court
as to whether you might
have information relevant
to this investigation?
I'm not prepared to answer
even that, Your Honor.
There is a precedent here.
We are all profoundly aware
that the NYPD is in the middle
of a mental health crisis,
and it is more important than ever,
that police officers
who have the courage
to seek counseling know,
that their records,
their conversations
remain privileged...
even after their death.
So Carisi's taking Lindstrom to court?
Yeah... I wouldn't count on
that working either.
Where are we?
Well, in 2004,
Rachel made Detective
under Captain Gary Wald
and Sergeant Ralph Morris.
She partners up with Detective Guevara.
From Tucker's file,
she hooked up with
all three of them plus a UC.
Ralphie?
I don't believe that.
It would explain
Gary's leverage over him.
We were able to trace the burner cell.
Gary and Ralphie exchanged
calls before he killed himself.
Okay, so after Rachel's suicide,
Ralphie feels guilt,
Gary leans on him to keep quiet, and...
Ralphie just doesn't see
another way out.
I respect the principle, Your Honor,
but in this case,
the two suicides may well
have been the result
of the crime and a cover‐up.
And Dr. Lindstrom has a duty to warn.
He may have information that
could stop yet another officer
from committing suicide.
Mr. Carisi, I've heard you
use phrases like, "maybe,"
"may well have been," "we believe."
All words that tell me
this evidence you seek
is speculative and secondhand
and maybe even third‐hand.
You've failed to show
that the interests of justice
outweigh the deceased's
interest in confidentiality.
_
Oh, my, Dr. Lindstrom, are you okay?
I'm fine.
This must've happened
while I was at the hearing.
- I'm sorry.
- They broke into my desk,
but they didn't bother
to take prescription samples
- or my checkbook.
- Was anything missing?
Two things.
My laptop and Ralph Morris' file.
They must have been
worried that the court
was gonna order you
to turn your notes over.
And now they have them.
Well, we'll call CSU,
get a team in here and run prints,
look for touch DNA.
Yeah, I can save you the time.
I had a visit to my office
here late last night.
- From who?
- Gary Wald, ex‐cop.
Yeah, we... we know him.
What did he want?
The same thing you want.
To know what Ralph Morris said
just before he took his own life.
But you didn't tell him.
No.
I can't.
But without breaking confidentiality,
I can tell you,
that your friend Ed Tucker
must know everything I know.
[HEAVY MUSIC]
[SIGHS]
- You still take milk?
- Ah, thank you.
Boy, four times in a week.
First, you couldn't wait
to get rid of me,
now I need an order of protection
- against you.
- Ed, we need to talk.
Walk with me.
I'm not going far.
What's on your mind?
Rachel Wilson,
Ralph Morris,
you and these games that
you've been playing.
Trust me, Liv, I don't
have time to play games.
No? Did you know your friend
Gary Wald broke into
Lindstrom's office,
and stole the file on Ralph Morris?
No. I had no idea.
Well, he did.
Lately, I'm realizing I had
no idea about a lot of things.
Yeah, and I want to believe you, Ed,
I really do, but...
I still get the feeling that you're not
being straight with me about...
about any of this.
Ed, what are we doing here?
You can't tell my wife.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[DOOR BELL CHIMES]
Hey.
Did I ever tell you about
where I worked after 9/11?
I asked.
They had me detailed to the
Fresh Kill Landfill recovery site,
looking for remains.
12‐hour shifts at the conveyor belt,
sifting through the debris,
watching credit cards,
baby pictures, and wedding rings go by.
Every once in a while, a...
A finger bone or a rib.
That sounds like how I picture Hell.
You start thinking about
your own life, you know?
All the things you missed.
- Oh, Ed.
- Wished you'd done.
They caught the cancer in my lungs
before I started seeing you.
Now it's in my brain.
They say there's no connection, but...
But... but they can treat that, right?
They can...
But... the doctor just told me
I have six months to a year.
Oh, my God.
It is what it is.
Well, pretty soon,
I won't be myself anymore.
Maybe you notice I'm starting
to have memory lapses.
That's why you didn't remember Rachel.
I had no... idea how I knew her.
I was too embarrassed to tell
you that when you asked.
But Gary called me after you left.
And what did he say?
He was just making sure
that I had his back,
like when we were partners.
Ed, are you saying
that you covered up a rape...
to protect your friend?
No...
I would never.
Back then, Gary told me
he'd an affair with her,
and when he went to break it off,
she only accused him of rape
just to get back at him,
and I was stupid enough to believe him.
I don't... want Rachel...
Or Ralph on my conscience.
While there's still time.
I need to make this right.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Mrs. Morris, we just wanted
to say again how sorry we are.
May Ralphie's memory
be a blessing for you.
Ralphie adored you.
You know that, don't you?
You were the daughter he never had.
He was a beautiful man.
He'll be missed.
_
108 bucks, Porterhouse steak for two?
Most expensive steak I ever had.
Yeah, the private sector's been
very, very good to Gary Wald.
Evidently.
And it could be very good for Eddie.
Six‐figure salaries,
yachts, private planes,
unbelievable women.
You wait till I'm married
to tell me this?
Well, I'm married too.
Or at least my wife is.
[CHUCKLES]
So, uh...
Did you get anything from Benson?
[SOFT DINNER MUSIC PLAYING]
They know what happened during Vice
and that it involved a supervisor.
All right, got it.
Did Ralphie's shrink
give them anything?
No.
Not even after somebody
broke into his office.
We don't need to worry
about that, do we?
No. No, those notes are gone.
Now this gets easier.
Just pin the rape on Ralphie.
Ralphie?
Well, I have proof he was
having an affair with her.
Whew.
She really got around, huh?
You, Ralphie?
Remember I told you they called her
the Hotbox of Midtown South?
I remember,
but then she started
giving you a hard time.
More like stalking me.
She called my wife.
I can't have that.
I had to tune her up.
Tune her up?
You never told me that back then.
It was a different time, Ed.
I had to protect my home,
my family, my job.
No, I get it.
I roughed her up good,
she got the message.
And now she's gone,
and Ralphie's gone.
All ties up in a bow.
The dead don't speak to the living.
These IAB guys know how to reel 'em in.
One thing you can say
about Ed Tucker...
He settles his accounts.
Whoa... hey, bud,
I didn't think
you had that much to drink.
What can I tell you?
I'm turning into an amateur
now I'm retired.
Hey, you want a ride home?
I got my driver.
Nah, I'm good.
It's... it's out of your way.
Well, you stick with me, kid,
you'll be riding in the back
of that Rolls Silver Cloud
we always talked about, all right?
[SIGHS]
[BREATHING HARD]
Hey. Hey, you okay?
- Yeah.
- Take it easy.
You okay?
Did you get enough for an arrest?
Yes, yes. It's all good.
It all ties up in a bow,
and the dead don't speak to the living.
So are we good to go on the
arrest warrant for Gary Wald?
Wald runs a global
security firm, right?
So if there's anything out there
on Tucker, he's gonna find it?
Is Tucker okay testifying
against his former partner?
- Tucker's clean.
- And you believe him?
Took him long enough
to come around on Rachel.
If this goes to trial,
how long will it take?
- Months?
- Could be years.
Why are you asking?
There's a reason that Tucker
wasn't himself before.
Captain, what are you talking about?
Don't make me spell it out.
So we need to do this without him?
Yes.
Okay.
We have the tapes...
I'll get you the search warrants.
Also see if you can flush out
anybody from Vice from that time.
- Anything else?
- Yeah.
Pick up Gary Wald.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
If you guys are here to talk about
working for me after retirement,
you should've called ahead
for an appointment.
- Guess again.
- Gary Wald,
we've got a warrant for your arrest
for sexual assault,
witness tampering,
and breaking and entering.
Based on what?
The word of two cops,
who were having an affair
and then killed themselves?
You better watch your mouth.
Damn, what is her problem?
You heard what she said.
Let's go.
So Gary's on his way
to Central Booking?
Yup.
One of my best friends, my partner,
and I never even knew it.
[SIGHS]
I think of all the people
I never let get close to me
because of IAB.
- Don't blame yourself, Ed.
- Why not?
It was my job to root out bad cops,
and I missed one of the worst.
He was standing right in front of me.
If I hadn't,
Rachel might still be here.
Ed, a lot of people missed it.
I have missed some things.
[SIGHS]
I didn't realize
we'd changed the subject.
We're talking about us now?
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC]
I'm sorry...
For the way that I ended things.
I think underneath it all...
I was afraid.
And your dance card was full.
The job, Noah.
What I wish I had.
And what I wish we had...
Is more time.
It's okay.
We'll always have Paris.
You know,
I've always wanted to say that.
Did the son of a bitch make bail?
No, once the judge heard
about his private plane,
his multiple passports,
if he's not a flight risk, no one is.
He can cool his jets at the jail
they were going to name after him.
Oh, my God.
What?
[HEAVY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
I heard about Tucker.
How you doing?
He took his life with his old .38.
I just don't know what to do with that.
There's nothing you can do with it.
It just is.
He left his wife a letter,
his benefits, his pension.
He told her that he didn't want her
to spend the best years of her life...
Taking care of a dying man.
He had brain cancer.
Oh, I didn't know.
He was suffering, Liv.
That's not how he'd want
to be remembered.
I know.
It's just a lot of rain in one place.
You don't need to be here alone.
Let me drive you home.
Just give me a minute. I'll be okay.
I'm good.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
synced & corrected by PopcornAWH
www.addic7ed.com