Hakodate, Goryokaku.
The last stronghold of the Shogunate army.
In October 1868, Tokugawa supporters landed in Ezo,
drove the forces of the new government of Fort Goryokaku and installed in Ezo, their rules.
Wanting to create a state independent of Japan, they chose Enomoto Takeaki as their President,
Ootori of Keisuke Minister of war, and Hijikata Toshizo - his assistant.
However, the new government soon launched a counter-offensive,
and by may 1869 the city of Hakodate and the surrounding area of Gorekaku
remained the last stronghold of people who remained loyal to the shogun.
May 1969 (second year of the Meiji era)
Of Ezo (Hokkaido), Nanahara
A Member Of The Shinsengumi
Shimada Kai
Soma Kazue
That's right, that's the tent over there.
Move!
Well. Nominate.
Are you sure it's time?
We can't wait any longer. We must attack on our own.
What is it?..
The Shinsengumi?..
Hijikata-San!
Tired of waiting?
You're late!
That's enough. This isn't the only place to watch, you know.
Hijikata-San is the commander, so be respectful.
Yeah, you're climbing higher.
Enough, enough...
In the old days, in Kyoto, Hijikata-San was not so arrogant.
He's always been on an equal footing with us, hasn't he, Ozeki?
I was just a little late! And you are immediately dissatisfied!
Don't forget, we're still in ambush...
Where is their wagon train?
Yonder.
Well... Go ahead!
Ozeki!
Yes, Yes!
Ozeki Of Masajiro
Go ahead!
Dorama " Shinsengumi!"
Bonus 50th episode
Last day Of Hijikata Toshizo
Everyone is already assembled, it's time to go out.
Don't rush it.
Enomoto-San, the war is entering a crucial phase.
Of course, a real soldier must be careful, but to such trifles...
But I'm the head of the army.
Are you saying that I can go out to my subordinates in an inappropriate way?
I want to demonstrate how great European soldiers can be... even in war.
Well, let's go.
Sit, sit...
Move.
We're back!
Hakodate, the Shinsengumi camp
Hush! Hijikata-San is about to make a speech.
Guys, you showed the enemy your fighting spirit! I'm happy with you.
We were able to prove to the Satsuma and Choshu clans that loyal Tokugawa vassals fight better than they do!
Our victory should be noted.
After the battle, the soldiers must rest, so now we will drink sake!
To be honest, I can't guarantee its quality - it was repulsed from the enemy.
Now there is a war, and you need to be prepared for everything, so you should not drink too much.
Let us drink to our winning the Cup! Soma, pour.
Everyone takes the cups - and in the queue!
We promise not to drink too much!
Can I get in line again?
Hijikata-San is much better with people than before.
You wouldn't think they called him "demonic Vice commander."
He replaced us with Kondo-Sensei.
Yeah...
Pay attention.
All his subordinates love him.
In Kyoto, he oversaw the implementation of The Shinsengumi rules.
In the conditions of war, it has become softer, and now it is loved, as once Kondo.
Thank you.
Mr. General, may I address you?
Ceremonies and titles aside, keep it simple.
Why?
I'm not used to this kind of treatment.
What should I call you then?
Well... call me Vice commander.
Well then...Vice commander, may I address you?
About?
We're new to the squad, and we don't know where it all started.
How did the Shinsengumi samurai start?
When we arrived in Kyoto, we were called Rosenhane.
Rosenhane?..
In the squad was and Now Rosigui, and Mibu Rosenhane...
In the end, we formed the Shinsengumi.
Is it true that you were only thirteen at the beginning?
When the Roshingumi organization broke up, only thirteen people decided to stay in Kyoto.
It can't be!
Well, here's the next example...
There were only eight of us in Edo, counting Kondo-San.
Eight?!
At the beginning, eight.
Kondo-San, ya, Soji, Nagakura, Sanosuke, Heisuke, Gen-San... and Yamanami-San.
Yamanami-San?
This is the one that seppuku committed for violating the rules.
Yamanami was the best samurai among us.
Without it, the Shinsengumi would not exist.
Really...
Okay, enough talking about the past.
Now Shinsengumi is us.
Support our honor.
There is!
Having fun?
Good have enemies sake.
Well, then we'll make another RAID.
Hijikata-San, we can handle this ourselves...
That is?
And you would go to Musashino. I heard President Enomoto is having an evening there.
Yes, it's boring there...
I think they're waiting for you there.
I'll leave later.
But...
Nothing... bosses are not late, they are late. ^_^
Exactly?..
Let's go, friends.
Yamano, Aritoshi you too.
There is!
Uridashi Cango, Yamano Yasohachi
What do you think about the situation at the front?
It's as if there are fewer of them.
You can immediately see the scout.
But what would that mean?
We must have been scared.
They have dispersed their troops and are going to attack.
Really?!
The enemy is determined. It is very likely that tomorrow will be hot.
I don't feel right...
Remember when we all broke into Ikeda-ya?
This is not forgotten...
Of all our comrades, only five of us remained.
So you've been with us for so long?
Don't talk about it.
We are the last Shinsengumi samurai.
So that...
As Vice commander, I order you to hold your position in Hakodate until the last moment.
This is a matter of life and death. If the OTA will fall...
...we're all dead.
Hijikata-San, what will you do?
I'm going back to Goryokaku.
Aren't you going to stay with us?
I will take command of the entire army.
I'm with you.
Prohibit.
Hijikata-San, I'm with you!
And me!
Take us with you!
You have to stay.
No way!
What objections!
You're leaving us!
Is it the duty of the Shinsengumi was not to protect civilians?
I understand, but...
Here and stay here!
Then let's go like this: someone will take charge of everything here, and I will go with you, Hijikata-San.
Well, well...
Ozeki is a veteran, so we can rely on him...
Shimada, come on! You all have to stay here!
Yes, let it be Ozeki. Soma would be fine, too... He's a smart guy, he'd make a good commander.
Shimada!
Hijikata-San! I want to go with you!
This is an order!
No!
Shimada-San! Enough!
We will protect Hakodate while our hands are clutching swords!
I'm counting on you.
Shimada. Ozeki. Yamano. Uridashi.
You are now in charge of the Shinsengumi.
Don't worry.
The war is not over yet.
We will fight together again.
Is everyone here?
Everything?
There is no Hijikata-San yet.
Again! Does he even realize that we have an attack on the nose?
This may be the last night when Mr. President and I can have a drink in a small circle...
Hijikata-San was here this afternoon.
Did Hijikata come?..
Yes.
Does he have fun when the situation is like this at the front?!
Come on. He just came in to pay us off.
Thank you.
Thanks for the care.
Not worry. He himself knows that a decisive battle is coming.
Recall...
When we collected money from Hakodate merchants for military needs, only he was against it.
He is a man of honor, and does not like to shift his burden on others.
Of course!
Weren't the Shinsengumi units a bunch of ronins who were not averse to plundering the population?
Why would Hijikata change her Outlook on life?
You are mistaken, Ootori-Dono.
Commandant Of Hakodate, Nagai Naoyuki
Shinsengumi samurai ruthlessly punished robbers in their ranks.
By the way, Nagai-sama, you must have known Kondo Isami quite well...
And I remember other rumors!
It was said that they were typical bandits and collected real tribute from merchants.
It's all Serizawa Kamo.
These rumors gave rise to the behavior Rosigui, and about the Shinsengumi then and not heard.
Kondo and his colleagues have created five rules of the Shinsengumi, according to which all had to behave like a true samurai.
And they certainly weren't engaged in extortion!
All right.
Can we start now, Ootori?
Are you sure?
There is no need to delay.
Attention, please! The President wants to address you.
Lord. We've been protecting Ezo for more than a month.
We fought bravely against the armies of Satsuma and Choshu.
However, our forces are exhausted.
We can't win, and therefore no further sacrifice is meaningless.
So, I, Enomoto Takeaki, am sorry to inform you...
We will capitulate tomorrow morning.
Tetsu, drink like a man!
Ichimura Tetsunosuke
If you don't want to, don't drink.
No, I like it!
There is nothing wrong with not drinking. Warriors who can't do without sake are no longer samurai.
Really?
Tetsu, let's walk.
There is!
Tetsu, how old are you?
It's sixteen.
You've been in the squad for two years, haven't you?
Yes.
That was the last time we recruited people in Kyoto...
Thank you for still being with us.
I'll follow you anywhere, Sensei.
You were a very useful person.
There is no greater honor for me than to be near you, Sensei.
I just wanted you to know that I'm grateful.
Do you like Shinsengumi?
I have nowhere else to go.
So you're staying forever...
Sensei, which animal is the strongest?
And why this question?
We started talking about this...
I saw a bear for the first time in these parts, and many said that it was the strongest.
I thought it was a tiger...
Sorry, this is a stupid question...
Nothing... I will answer.
The strongest is the nue.
Well?
You don't know? Well, you'll find out.
Obey...
Hpp.
Yes?
I have a request for you.
I'm listening.
Important assignment.
What should I do?
This is a difficult task.
Ready to execute any order.
Leave here right now.
So...
Go to Tama.
In Hino, you will find a man named Sato Hikogoro - this is my named brother.
I need you to give it to him.
Take it and leave immediately.
But wait...
I warned you: the task is difficult.
I can't do this!
You have to do it.
But I run...
This is not an escape!
But after all!..
This is a cause worthy of a warrior.
The Shinsengumi are fighting valiantly with Satsuma and Choshu in Hakodate, and I want the people in Tama to know that.
Let me fight with everyone!
If you don't follow orders, you will die.
Someone has to do it.
And who else can I assign this task to?
It's written about you, too.
Hikogoro-San must find out about this.
Then you find a woman named Okita Mitsu and give her this.
Ask Hikogoro-San where she lives, he must know.
This is Soji's sister.
This?..
It's impossible to explain.
Pass it on.
If you lose it on the way, only seppuku will remain for you.
Will be delivered.
I hope for you.
Obey.
Hijikata-Sensei...
Don't ask me anything.
Sensei, are you preparing to die?
I...
Stay out of sight of the others.
Especially Shimada or Ozeki.
Obey.
Go.
Enough for today!
Okay!
Look, what is the most powerful creature in the world? A tiger, right?
I have heard that the lion is also strong.
A lion?.. I've never seen him.
They say the lion is the king of beasts. He should be strong.
I think the strongest is the bear.
I happened to fight him with my bare hands once.
It was a big beast.
Did you win?
I'm alive.
Well, then, he's not that strong.
Soji!..
Nagakura-San, what do you think?
A tiger, perhaps.
Yes, tiger!
But no! Kato Kiyomasa, I Think.
What does Kato Kiyomasa have to do with this?
Don't you know? He put the tiger down.
But we are talking about what kind of creature is the most powerful in the world...
Isn't Kato Kiyomasa a creature?
Yamanami-San, what do you say?
Well... I've never seen a tiger or a lion, so I can't say anything about them.
But I'm sure there are still many living things in the world that we don't know anything about.
And one of them may be the strongest.
I still think it's Kato Kiyomasa!
Hijikata-San, what do you think? Well, who is the strongest?
Yes, it's obvious.
Well, who?
Well.
What is this-well?
You don't know, do you? Well, well.
It has a monkey's head, a Tanuki's body, a snake's tail, and tiger's paws.
Come on!
Tiger paws?! Does he have a tiger attached here?..
No, only the feet of the tiger.
Does such a thing really exist?
Aha.
I wouldn't say that... I think nue is created by the human imagination.
I don't think it really exists.
Perhaps the most dangerous creature is a human.
Why?
People deceive each other. Animals never lie.
Oh, that... Yamanami-San, as always, you are looking at the root.
Here after all wrapped...
Enough of this...
That was your question!
And let's call Kondo-Sensei? It's boring for him to eat there alone.
Call... Heiske!
Coming!
No. Sensei inherited the Tennen Rishin Ryu school.
From now on, he is not allowed to sit at the same table with us.
But it's more fun together!
This is the lot of all the great.
All of them are already dead...
Hijikata-San decided to die.
Shimada-San!
I go to Goryokaku!
Wait!
I will die with him!
Don't you understand yet?
He also assigned us to lead the Shinsengumi.
I don't care!
You don't care about his orders? Shimada-San!
Ozeki!
I realized that Hijikata-San wanted us to stay alive.
But this is nonsense!
He told us to move on and take care of the Shinsengumi.
It is our duty to stay alive, no matter what happens.
Shimada-San, everything will be fine.
Hijikata-San is not so simple!
He would fight with all his might - they called him the "demonic Vice commander"for a reason!
Go.
Yes...
In any case, do not get caught by enemies.
Obey.
Run! And don't stop until Tam!
Yes!
Hijikata!
Nagai-sama!
How was the meeting?
I don't understand a damn thing...
What, not all in the collection?
No, that's not the point.
I'm not in the mood to sit there and drink.
Enomoto-San was very sorry that you didn't come.
I don't have any warm feelings for him.
Well, well, don't.
Yeah, he's changed since he came back from Europe.
While everyone is fighting, he is sitting in his room like a European General.
I don't believe such people.
However... he's a stubborn man.
Yes, I admit that he is persistent.
But Enomoto-San is a theorist, not a practitioner.
Nevertheless, he led the remaining Tokugawa forces.
That's what I'm grateful for.
He gave me the opportunity to continue fighting.
I wish he could hear it...
By the way, Nagai-sama...
Yes?
We were behind enemy lines today.
It looks like we're really going to be attacked tomorrow.
Similar to that. Enomoto has already made a decision about this.
It seems to me that this will be a decisive battle.
We will not allow it to go according to Satsuma and Choshu's plan.
We will show them the power of loyal Tokugawa vassals!
You see, Hijikata...
Tomorrow we surrender.
Secret negotiations with their headquarters have already begun.
It can't be! We haven't lost yet!
We were told that this was necessary to avoid tomorrow's senseless slaughter.
That's why you can't put an army in the hands of theorists!
The outcome of the war is at stake.
You Know, Hijikata...
I think so, too.
Nagai-sama...
But... we could have stopped there.
Nagai-sama, I don't want to hear such pathetic words from YOU.
We fight like demons, although the enemy has a numerical advantage and a secure rear.
How many more people should die? May be quite a sacrifice?
Why do you think I'm still fighting?
Because I would be ashamed to look Kondo-San in the eye!
On the day of his execution, I also died.
But I will fight dead, too!
If we lose, Kondo Isami will remain an executed criminal!
How am I going to look him in the eye if we surrender to these scum tomorrow?!
Just ask him to forgive you...
It is not in Kondo-San's nature to be angry at this.
You did a great job.
Gorekaku has not yet fallen due to the fact that Hijikata Toshizo is fighting with us.
We've all been fighting until now - isn't it time to start living in peace?..
...and watch what kind of world Saigo and Katsura will build?
I apologize.
Where are you going?!
I'll Visit Enomoto.
Don't you dare!
I won't let him give up.
He will not back down from his decision!
So I'll have to kill him.
Hijikata!..
Not here!
Higher up.
Dig here.
(Border (posthumous name) of the Condo is. The characters "kanten" and "daikoji" were usually inscribed in the border of high-ranking samurai.)
Kantan indan janusary of daikoji.
When you think of him, that's all you can think of.
Do not write a lifetime name?
Not worth. It is not known what the people of Satsuma or Choshu will do if they understand who is buried here.
Right...
Hijikata...
I'm listening.
Nagaoka has fallen, now it's Aizu's turn.
We have no chance of winning.
This is still unknown!
Morale is high, as always.
Not to worry.
We will protect you to the last.
You don't need to do this.
Master?..
I cannot leave this region; but you are not Aizu's vassals, and there is no need for you to remain here.
But!..
Go to the North. Join Enomoto Takeaki.
Gather the remaining Tokugawa vassals, repel the forces of Satsuma and Choshu.
But you're staying here...
And Kondo, too...
Don't worry about me.
Think only about winning.
The Vice-commander.
I think I should stay.
Saito...
I will protect the master and Kondo; you fight and don't worry about it.
I rely on you.
Obey.
This is our last duty.
Hijikata-San has arrived!
Not too late...
He insists on meeting with President Enomoto.
Do without.
But he...
Tell him to wait. I'll be right there.
And the President...
...you don't have to tell me.
I've been waiting for you.
I don't care about you. Take me to Enomoto.
He had already gone to his room.
I have a very urgent matter.
I'm listening carefully.
And you don't have to hear that.
Well, I'm the Minister of war.
Is surrender your doing, Minister of war?
We haven't lost yet, but for some reason we're giving up.
To avoid complete destruction.
I won't let anyone destroy us!
Mr. President has made a final decision.
That's why I say: take me to Enomoto!
I don't quite understand... did you come in the middle of the night to challenge his decision?
He was expecting you earlier, but you weren't there.
I thought you were getting ready to die...
And you are here to celebrate and have fun?
So you're going to enjoy life?
Why did I have to come to this disgusting gathering?
Hijikata Toshizo still has the honor.
All these are words, and our situation is getting worse and worse.
And we, as leaders, must do something.
And it doesn't have to be an attack.
And whose fault did we get to this?!
You were about to capitulate, and my men fought and died a few hours ago!
Don't worry, I've decided to take your people back.
Soooo! So you are going to get us out of the way, because we are the last obstacle for you?!
You forget yourself!
War is a dangerous business, and you are afraid to take risks for the sake of victory!
Hijikata-kun, I can see your fighting spirit, but you know what this is all about...
Yes, I offered to capitulate.
But in fact, I intend to continue fighting.
What do you mean?
We are supported by Ezo - weapons, ammunition, and supplies.
In addition, due to the advantageous location of Goryokaku can we stay here at least another six months.
A long siege?..
In six months, winter will come, and the enemies are not used to the local frosts.
The enemy will not attack for a while,
meanwhile, we will gather a huge army of our supporters...
Coward!
That's rude!
You're a theorist, so you don't know much about people.
That is?
The Aizu clan has fallen, and so has Nagaoka.
Who will support us if we lose again?
We will have to look for allies outside of Hokkaido.
Yes, even if we talk only about Ezo-where are the guarantees that even existing allies will not run away?
Do you think there's nothing you can do?
Isn't it prudent to think through all the options?
Chips on the table are one thing, but life is another.
Morale is all we have left.
What are your suggestions?
Attack.
It is useless to move the entire army.
You should scatter and sting the enemy in weak places.
When the enemy moves to the sea-attack from the mountains.
When the enemy turns to the mountains-attack from the sea.
What is the goal?
When the enemy realizes that we have started a guerrilla war, they will be afraid.
Because such wars can go on for years and decades.
Breaking the spirit of your enemies is what you need.
Good plan! Sooner or later we will be crushed.
I won't allow it!
Swear.
Enough!
Everything has been decided long ago! Change something...
That's why I came!
Hijikata-kun!
You must obey me.
Once, in Shinsengumi, Kondo Isami could turn a blind eye to your arbitrariness, but now...
Hey!
I demand a meeting with the President.
I'm the Minister of war!
It's useless to talk to you.
What impudence!
Get out of the way.
Stupid!
Enomoto thinks the same way I do!
Then I will kill Enomoto and then you.
Somebody!
Hijikata.
President...
Go to the office.
But!..
No matter.
Then I did...
You are free.
Bring wine and two glasses, and these... sandwiches.
Since the President himself is calling , we'll have to go.
At the end of last year, taking Goryokaku, we chose the President, remember?
So what?
Enomoto-San said that this is how the head of state is elected in America.
He always does what they do abroad.
So?..
Enomoto-San received 149 votes out of 150.
I remember it now...
There was only one vote for you, wasn't there?
So what?
Only one person wanted you to be President...
...you know, it's not very fair to vote for yourself.
And now this has nothing to do with it!..
You don't have to talk about it...
You and Ootori are such funny people...
Once you meet, it starts all around you...
I'm sorry, Mr. President, but he is...
Well, well, don't.
Ootori always starts bickering with you, even if he wasn't going to.
In your disputes, the right decision is born - it also does not yield to the last.
We never found a way to win.
True, but thanks to you and Ootori, we've held out so far.
And at the moment we have the strongest army in Japan.
The most... strong?
I really think so.
I would not have achieved such success myself, even if all the gods had helped me.
Mr. President, let me address you.
Yes, I just wanted to talk to you in private.
Since you didn't attend the Banquet ...
You will have to drink alone.
Thank you, I don't want to.
Keep me company.
Foreign sake? I will not.
It feels strange at first, but then you get used to it.
No, thanks.
Then try this.
You don't know, do you?
Playing cards are very popular in Europe, and since you can only play cards with one hand,
they invented sandwiches.
Really, it's so European.
We have in Japan is the onigiri.
For me, eating them is much easier.
Well, if you don't want to eat yet, don't eat.
You are a really interesting person, Hijikata-kun.
What?
You don't like anything European very much.
I hate the West.
That's my character.
And you look at yourself.
I heard that you are the only one of the Shinsengumi who has cut his hair and dressed in the Western style.
European clothing is just more convenient.
During the battle, it is much easier to move in it.
And the Japanese hairstyle needs to be taken care of.
Really...
I hate all useless things.
That's what I'm saying-you have a European way of thinking.
We have a lot in common.
You're joking.
It takes you out of yourself, but nevertheless
What's that under your nose?
This?
How long does it take you to take care of these European things?
I like to take care of my mustache.
Many useful Western inventions are impressive, but not this.
Appearance is also important.
It's just an imitation.
I only adopt what I really need.
I'm sorry, of course, but you and I are the exact opposite.
Okay...
It's delicious.
Why are we giving up?
This is our only way out.
It doesn't lead anywhere. Cancel the decision.
I won't do that.
Then I have no other choice.
You can kill me.
But what will you do then?
I will take command of the army.
You know...
Well.
I'm sorry, but you can't do it.
They won't even let you leave the room.
Then I'll do seppuku, right here.
Really...
I've made up my mind.
How inconvenient it is...
In this case, my death will be completely meaningless.
Exactly.
I'm sorry, but I can't stand pointless actions any more than you can.
Okay, I'll reverse the decision. Let's stop this farce. Lower your sword.
Do you want us to fight to the end?
Yes.
What should we do?
The war is not over yet. We have a chance.
A chance to win?
Give me a hundred men and I will turn the tide of the war.
Uselessly.
Why?
Explain more?
You see... you're not going to win.
This is not true!
You sound very confident.
But you see what it is... one of us is very smart and knows better than the rest of us that we are finished.
This person is you, Hijikata-San.
Are you going to die? In the next battle, right?
You think that honor is more important than life, and you want to die.
And to such a man should I entrust the lives of our people?
I don't want senseless sacrifices.
So you're going to give up, no matter what?
No matter what.
I've fought the enemy so far, and I'm not going to retreat for no reason!
Are you such a fool?..
After the surrender, my life's work will be destroyed.
I'm already dead. You don't have to kill me - I'll make a seppuku no later than twenty-four hours.
And my death will save thousands of people.
That's a lie...
It's true.
I'm a samurai, no matter what I look like.
You are serious , and I am no less serious.
Can I leave everything to you?
If so, I don't need troops.
Let me kill myself, and then you can give up.
Sorry, you can't do that either.
Why?
I decided so, Hijikata-kun.
Only I should die, and no one else.
What am I supposed to do?
What to do? Well...
I think we should have a drink.
You shouldn't judge unfamiliar things strictly, right?
Do you know the difference between sake and grape wine?
In the method of preparation.
Rice no matter how much you press, it will not become sake; and this makes grapes wine.
Grapes begin to ferment themselves, they do not need additives.
So the wine is obtained in a completely natural way.
This is very European.
Not bad, is it?
Well, not bad.
But not very well.
No matter what you say, time doesn't stop.
One day they will make wine in Japan.
Especially here: the climate in Ezo is similar to that of Europe.
You will see that the wine here will be drunk all over the world.
Try a sandwich.
Enomoto-San, there's something I don't understand...
What?
You.
And, there's that!
I don't always understand myself, so it's okay.
When I first heard of your plans to go to Ezo,
I was amazed at how out of touch they were with reality.
You said you were going to come here,
little by little, gather strength and eventually become a separate Republic.
You said that you want to build the future of the Japanese on a par with Satsuma and Choshu.
It was so absurd that it inspired me.
Thanks to you, our morale has risen to an unprecedented level.
But you must have realized that all this is just a dream.
You could not hope to be allowed to separate from Japan.
But there's nothing wrong with that.
All we wanted was to prevent Satsuma and Choshu from reshaping the world to their own standards.
That's why I bet on Enomoto Takeaki.
So why are we now bowing to them without fighting to the end?
I admit I was disappointed in you.
I can only apologize.
I am ashamed that I, who followed Kondo Isami, believed for a moment in Enomoto Takeaki.
You thought I was a follower of the Condo itself and was disappointed.
Yes, I think it's unbearable.
Kondo-San was a man of high ideals.
He followed the path that he believed was the only right one.
And though it was not easy, people followed him, won over by his directness.
I'm sorry, you're a different person.
Naturally.
I Am Enomoto Takeaki.
However, Hijikata, you made a mistake.
I was quite serious then.
You seemed to think it was a utopia, but I really wanted to create a new country.
Go.
I didn't expect you to be so realistic.
A realist?..
Realists are those who, like you, live not in dreams, but only in reality.
Accurate judgment about what is happening on the battlefield is most important to them.
They don't catch cranes in the sky.
But I'm not.
What are you?
I'm a hopeless romantic.
Satsuma and Choshu shout that they are building a new country, but what are they really doing?
They destroyed the Tokugawa regime and continue to destroy Japan.
And I wanted to start a new state from scratch.
See.
Around such open spaces, not occupied by anyone, clean water, fertile land, rich in iron and coal subsoil.
When I set foot on this earth, I immediately wanted to build a new world here.
Unlike you, I didn't kill people.
I studied for a long time in the Netherlands, and previously taught in the Naval Department.
I've never been a real samurai.
But that day, I decided that I had allowed Satsuma and Choshu enough to run Japan, and it was time to stop.
You were right: up to this point, I was only looking for death.
And you yourself, it seems, until this moment, and really intended to win...
Certainly.
You're a fool.
Thanks for the compliment.
But now the dream is over...
And since it's over, I, like any honest samurai, must give up.
Now my task is to save the lives of those who helped me maintain this crazy dream.
In fact, after the war ended, I wanted to raise cows ...
Cows?
Countless herds.
Sounds impressive...
Have you tried cow's milk?
No.
I don't want to!
For Europeans, milk is a very important product.
They also make butter and cheese out of milk.
Cheese?
You tried the sandwich. That thin inside...
Was it cow's milk?
Was it delicious?
Yeah.
I would like the Japanese to eat it, too.
For this purpose, I wanted to establish pastures here, raise cows, and raise agriculture here,
to make people westernized and wealthy.
To do for his country something more than what you do Satsuma and Choshu.
But all this remained a dream.
President!
I was looking for you...
Is something wrong?
All the squad leaders returned.
Thank you, good.
Everyone is concerned about your decision and wants to talk to you.
I'm coming.
Go.
Attention!
Sit, sit.
Mr. President will speak!
Sit down.
Thank you for your efforts.
The war is over.
For being with me so far, I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
After all this , are we really giving up?
But we can still fight!
Why should we give up?
Hijikata-San!
Mr. President, we will hold on to the end!
And what do you think?
You heard them.
I've already decided we're giving up.
Don't give up!
You amaze me.
What have we been talking about for so long?
I noticed something.
I thought only of death.
And all you have in mind is surrender.
But we overlooked something important.
So what?
You should never give up.
You are, of course, a fool and a hopeless romantic.
But I put my life on the line for another hopeless romantic...
...make the best samurai in Japan.
I guess my purpose is to follow such people.
I am ready to fulfill your dream.
But I told you it was over.
This is not true.
We still have until dawn.
Enomoto-San, shall we try?
Now it will not be a battle to die in.
It will be a battle for survival.
You know...
You mispronounce the word "romantic".
Don't shorten it.
I knew it.
Rely on me.
We understood each other.
In the first place?
First of all, the military Council.
Hijikata-kun.
I owe you an apology.
For what?
I misjudged you.
In what sense?
The most hopeless romantic is you.
How do I win?
Would you like more wine?
Not now. We will win-then as much as necessary.
And the sandwich?
Please don't get distracted.
Okay.
In Kyoto, did you make plans the same way?
Yes.
And then, when was the incident in Ikeda-ya?
At that time, we made a plan together with Yamanami-San.
By whom?
This was my friend from Edo.
I came up with a plan in General terms, and he worked out the details.
This was done in Shinsengumi.
Well, I'll try to replace him.
No way.
Come on, you're good in your place.
What's so funny?
Don't worry so much.
Okay.
I think I know the map like the back of my hand, but it looks strange...
In what sense?
I used to think only about where I was going to die.
And now I intend to survive, and now the map looks completely different...
Concocted.
So, let's start the Council!
I beg.
It will be like the battle of Okehazama.
Okehazama?
The essence of our previous actions was that Satsuma and Choshu attacked and we defended.
When protecting Hakodate, this is the best way.
From the South we have a natural wall - mount Hakodate, in the Bay is our fleet.
The city is patrolled by troops of the Shinsengumi.
If we don't falter, it won't be easy for the enemy to land.
Is everything correct so far?
Yes.
Our enemy thinks the same way, so he will divide his forces into three parts.
To surround us from the North and West.
Their goal is Goryokaku, and during tomorrow's attack, they will shrink back.
How can this be avoided?
And we will not avoid it.
They have about ten thousand people.
They'll try to outnumber us.
If you just push the armies, the one with the most soldiers wins.
But there is one way to overcome the superior forces of the enemy.
Don't pull!
The more forces the enemy has and the more dispersed they are,
the worse he sees his own vulnerabilities.
This is our goal.
We will strike at the weakest point.
This is how Nobunaga defeated Imagawa.
When the commander has little strength, it makes no sense to defend - you need to attack.
So you mentioned Okehazama?
In these parts, there are trails known only to the locals, which can be used to infiltrate the enemy in the rear,
attack the headquarters at the Tomikawa river and behead the enemy.
The chief of staff, Kuroda of Recca...
Yes.
How many soldiers will you take?
Fifty is enough. A large squad won't help.
The enemy has a large army, so confusion in the headquarters will be fatal.
After killing Kuroda, we will immediately turn around and attack the enemy from the rear.
And you, Enomoto-San, when you notice the panic of the enemy, then attack from Goryokaku.
And we'll get your favorite sandwich.
The enemy will be caught between us.
Really...
If we succeed, the outcome of the battle will not depend on the number of troops...
...and from the one who will have more courage.
Impressive.
Do you like it?
I think we can really win.
I have not lost a single battle on land during my stay here.
Well thought out.
Our enemy is nue, consisting of Satsuma, Choshu, and Tosa.
But the man is able to defeat any monster.
What are you talking about?
No matter.
President...
What else?
We can still win this war.
Battle for survival, right?
Yes, for survival.
Minute.
When you go on a sortie, who will command the army?
I rely on you.
I can, of course, but wouldn't it be better to leave it to Ootori?
I don't think our plan will please him.
So that leaves only you.
Well, what do you think of Hijikata-kun's plan?
Stop hiding.
You noticed...
It was obvious when you looked at your feet.
What were you doing there?
I was going to get rid of you first, so you wouldn't talk nonsense.
Then I listened to about completely hopeless plans...
Stop!
Hijikata...
Thanks.
For what?
For inspiring President Enomoto to fight on.
Defense is my specialty.
You don't have to worry and fight as much as you want.
Ootori-San, I noticed something while looking at you...
What are you talking about?
When the President announced the surrender, you looked the most unhappy of all those present.
A person who lives only on theories cannot have such a face.
I rely on you.
Uh, wait a second!
Have you already decided everything without me?
If we win tomorrow, the enemy will be defeated.
Satsuma and Choshu will think about it and perhaps give us the opportunity to develop these wild lands.
When this bright moment comes, we will begin to build Ezo-a new country.
A country where Kondo Isami won't be a criminal?
Of course.
He will be one of the heroes who gave birth to this country.
May the memory of him not be blotted out for centuries.
For a long time I was interested in: what kind of greeting is this?
Hijikata, this is our greeting now.
Our new country.
Don't get into trouble!
Take care of your strength, move carefully, lure the enemy!
Understand?
Where did this come from?
from the North.
Send a scout!
Yes!
Begun.
The enemy went on the offensive at Fort Akagawa!
Fort akagawa has been captured!
Are we just going to stand there and watch? We can go to the rescue!
Hijikata-San's order to wait!
He told them not to move until they entered the city.
FORTS Syracuse and Kangin fell, the enemy's heading this way.
As soon as the soldiers return from those FORTS, we gather the main forces and prepare for battle.
I leave everything to you.
Well done!
However, the real battle is just beginning!
Keep your head up!
The enemy moves quickly, will soon come to Fort Kikino.
They are so wrapped up in the onset that he could not see anything except Goryokaku.
As we expected.
Kuroda's headquarters remained unprotected.
Key point.
Kondo-San...
Sorry for the delay.
I'll catch up with you soon.
Our goal is their bid. We need the head of the BOJ's Resca!
Go ahead!
Listen!
The enemy is still far away, but the order can come at any time!
Everyone be ready!
What for?..
Enemy soldiers on top of the mountain!
What ?!
Don't back down!
Haridasi!
Forward.
They are on mount Hakodate...
It looks like they landed at night and somehow climbed the mountain.
I can't believe it... as with Headache...
If the Shinsengumi at the foot of Hakodate retreat to Benten Fort, the city will be taken and the battle will lose its meaning!
How annoying, there was only one step left!
Unbelievably...
Hijikata...
Where Is Hijikata?!
Hijikata!
Where is Ootori-sama?
Sending reinforcements to Hakodate.
Oh, good.
Since they've taken the city, we'll make our sandwich right here.
I leave the rest to you.
Hijikata!
Don't go there, stay.
Come on!
It's just beginning.
I think best when plans fall apart.
I'll help out my old comrades and get Kuroda's head.
Don't try to die.
I promise.
Enomoto-San!
Do something to stay alive.
And make your dream come true.
A dream?..
How about: develop this land,
start herds of cows, make cheese...
This is only you can do.
Hijikata-San! The enemies were suddenly on the mountain!
Calm down! As long as I'm here, we won't lose!
What are the Shinsengumi?
Probably...
They are now...
Look! The enemy ship is sinking.
This is the first sign of our victory!
Now is the time to attack their bid.
As long as you are with me, no one will die!
Follow me!
Hijikata-San!
Get ready!
Fire!
Attack!
Run!
Don't back down!
Attack!
Who is it?..
Vice commander of the Shinsengumi, Hijikata Toshizo.
Enomoto-San, I'm sorry...
Toshi...
Kat-Chan...
Hijikata?..
Enomoto-San...
It's over...
Don't give up!
Hijikata-San will come to the rescue soon!
Stand to the death!
Shimada-San, Mr. Nagai is here!
Nagai-sama!
Shimada!
What happened?
Hijikata...
Hijikata-San?..
Died in a skirmish...
Thus speak.
Hijikata-San?..
It can't be...
The scouts told me.
This is not true... He can't die!
This... are you sure?
This can't be happening!
Hijikata-San can't die!
Shimada-San, stop!
The battle is over! Don't ruin yourself for nothing!
You must survive! Survive!
Continue the Hijikata business.
Continue...
Live and see a world where there will be no Shinsengumi.
This is his last wish and your last duty.
Nagai-sama!
I'm here.
The enemy's parliamentarian wants to talk to you.
Really...
Time to give up, huh?
We are performing.
Shinsengumi samurai will never die in our hearts!