At that time...
I did not know what
they could do to us
or what we were capable of.
I had my brothers, and a family,
but I had not yet met
my sisters in arms.
I still can not believe
how fragile our happiness was
and how much this war
was about to change me.
Keiro!
It all began that morning...
Hello.
Forget it.
Yazidi girls only marry Yazidis.
Go.
Since the attack on Mosul,
soldiers were watching over our village.
They were only a few
and not prepared
for what was coming.
Thank you dad!
- How did you get it?
- In English, darling.
How do you expect
to find work in the USA
if you don't practice your English?
It must have been very expensive.
Don't you worry about that.
I was so exited to finish my painting...
I did not see how
worried my father was...
or the soldiers leaving.
I was just hearing my mother
singing her favorite song.
It's beautiful!
Thank you.
Do you know who it is?
That's Malek Taous,
God's favorite angel.
And... why is it
his favorite angel?
Because he worships God
and only God.
I knew it!
It's not true.
I swear Juror, it's true!
Let's go.
Hold on.
Yes.
Our religion forbids
us to spit on the ground.
I didn't really spit.
Keiro, it's even worse to lie.
- You understand?
- Yes.
There coming!
Quick, go upstairs!
Devil worshipers!
In his mercy,
the army of God,
Praise be to Almighty God...
gives you the chance
to redeem your apostasy.
Lay down your arms,
give your valuables
and nothing will happen to you.
They want the money.
Give it away, they will leave!
Especially not, they lie!
Don't do that.
I am Sunni! Sunni!
The devil is here!
Put it here!
Only men,
not women.
Where are you taking them?
Don't talk to Abu Mariam!
Dad!
We also take the old?
Yes, but on another bus.
Not with the fresh ones.
Devil worshipers,
convert to the true God.
Praise be to God.
Praise be to God!
Who are you to force us?
Your book says:
"No compulsion in religion."
Who are you to talk about the holy book?
You don't even have one!
So what?
Where's my yazidie?
I wish I could buy one
with blue eyes,
or two with brown eyes!
Don't move!
Please, not a woman.
Let a man kill me!
Girls,
you see a man out here?
There is no men here.
They attacked all of our villages.
I saw lots of girls from school.
Age?
16 years old.
- Height? Weight?
- 1.70 M, 55 kg.
Age?
Height?
It's not your business!
Go to hell!
We're going to watch you!
Not in the face, you moron!
We have to sell her?
Do you know how much she is worth?
Take her for inspection!
By what right?
Holy war!
Age?
Height? Weight?
19 years old.
1.60 M.
Weight?
I don't know?
Virgin?
Is this your son?
Is this your mom?
No.
It's my sister.
Don't move!
Hello, Colonel Sharan.
Grégory Mendez.
Coalition office online.
Great shots.
Have they gone to the front yet?
Of course.
Jihadists men are terrified
when they see them.
Really?
They think that they
killed by a woman
keeps them from getting to Heaven.
and from getting virgins,
that come with it.
Fucking morons.
What would you do
when the war is over?
Will you live with the Arabs,
peacefully?
I mean...
you guy's didn't even managed
to do that between you Kurd's.
We dream of a Kurdistan that
respects every culture and religion.
- Do you really believe that yourself?
- Yes we do.
Who the spiders?
The Snake Brigade.
Special Forces.
How special?
Quite special indeed.
Can I interview them?
Hey don't use all the
water like last time!
It wasn't me,
it was already low when I got in!
Yeah right...
Have you showered?
Too hungry.
Bless Oh Lord this meal and
those who prepared it.
And give bread to those in need.
So be it. Amen.
What?
Nothing.
Eat! You said you were hungry.
The kitchen did a great job.
So finally!
You even found time
to put make-up on!
- Waterproof?
- Actually it is!
How do you say
"Yummy" in Kurdish?
Zero clue.
Come on you have a Kurdish father,
right?
Kurdish father,
English mum and I grew up in Zanzibar.
But why else would you think they
put me in the international brigade?
Chief how do you say
"Yummy" in Kurdish?
God is dead.
Whatever!
I heard you did well at the checkpoint.
No, there were too many of them.
But we managed to catch a
group that were lacking behind.
That's good. It will worry them.
You're alright?
It's just so hot.
It's even worse than back home.
Your the one who that should
have been born in England! Not me.
Hey come on,
let's clear our heads. We deserved it.
Welcome!
We were here before!
They are lieutenants of Abu Mariam.
This is our first choice.
She mutilated her face
but the rest...
is intact.
This one is very fresh.
Very, very fresh.
Look at her bright eyes.
And she has beautiful teeth.
Look.
Now I can see that.
But now I recognize her.
She was in the group
when we took Sinjar.
She must give us a good price.
Of course.
I'll take her.
Keiro!
He is my little brother!
Buy him and I will do
whatever you want!
No I can't.
Please!
Stop It!
Sit down!
What are we going to tell to my sister?
The truth.
What do you mean?
That's God's will.
And that's the way it is.
By the law of God it is
forbidden to listen to music,
to smoke, to play cards,
to be alone in a room with
someone of the opposite sex.
Were going to put her in your room,
it will be easier to keep her locked up.
You will sleep in the living room.
Tell me she's not staying?
Clean her up and
give her some clothes!
Repeat after me.
There is no God but Allah.
Repeat after me!
Dramatic events here in Paris,
three terrorists seized
hostages at separate locations
and triggered a wave of terror
right across the french capital.
This is the scene right now
at Arc de Triomphe in Paris,
a banner "Paris is Charlie",
in solidarity with
Charlie Hebdo .
They will pay for this.
At least
this time the whole world
will see what's happened.
You should have told me about it.
It's a good sign.
Our cause is becoming popular.
What's wrong?
New recruits.
Young?
Younger and younger.
I can't take sending coffins back to
countries I don't even know anymore.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
I’m Laura.
Welcome.
New comrades from France.
Our Kurdish people are very
grateful that you left your homes
too come to fight with the
oppressed against our enemy.
Our revolution has no boundaries.
It is global, political,
social, ecological.
It Is a feminist revolution.
Right?
Yes, you are right it is
also a feminist revolution.
Our mothers have fought,
our daughters will fight
We want to free women.
This is our goal in life.
We want to create a new better society.
What is "Phew"?
They love it.
Really.
That's enough.
I can ask a question?
Yes.
Can we get our phone's back?
No phone's no sex,
no life. You are here to fight.
Here are your room.
Tomorrow, training.
I leave you with your comrade.
Long live free Kurdistan!
I don't get it?
Why can't we have our phone's back?
You'll get it back after a month.
When you get used
to living disconnected.
On mission,
you can take propaganda photos, selfies.
But without a SIM card.
Not to be spotted.
Smiling.
By the law of God it is
forbidden to eat tomatoes
whose heart resembles a cross
and make love to a corpse
more than an hour after his death.
Bathroom.
Bathroom!
Wake up.
Stand up, comrades! Wake up.
Come on, practice.
I volunteered as a nurse.
Not to fight.
When these bastards want to catch you,
you'll be happy to have it.
Now he's your best friend.
My best friend is flat,
fits in my pocket
and you took it from me.
Six years in the army.
Eight months in guerrilla warfare.
Comrade Kurda!
Kurdish father.
Comrade Yael!
Military service in Israel.
Comrade Belkacem.
Silence!
A long time ago,
when Mesopotamia was not divided
between Persians, Kurds and Arabs,
men respected the Mother goddess.
It was with the arrival of
monotheism and capitalism
that the system of male
domination has imposed its laws.
You are not the first fighters.
Viking women,
our Kurdish grandmothers
against the Turks.
But when women rebel,
they are erased from history,
of the society.
And we send them home.
We send them home
to be slaves.
Not this time.
You are there to tell the world:
not this time.
What is that?
Where is your rage
You did it!
It's so far!
It's part of training.
Why didn't we take one
of the all-terrain vehicles?
They looked great.
We used them for
Operation "Free Iraq".
The Americans gave
them to the Kurds.
But we don't have enough,
so we spin them.
Since we are talking about it...
you Americans
what a mess you screwed in Iraq.
We're going to sleep here.
Finally.
Bless us Lord
and bless this food. Amen.
Seriously? After
walking for hours?
Thank you.
Sometimes we don't eat
during many days.
But you are not trained enough...
What luck!
Why do you say we screwed up?
It’s not America that fucked up,
it's that fucking religion.
Sooner or later,
all religions screw up on shit.
No. Not all.
You just have to see the Crusades,
the Inquisition...
You say that because
you are Muslim.
No, because I am French.
"French secularism"!
Yes and so...
Did you lost your mind?
Are you serious?
Snake.
What snake?
Shit!
Are there really snakes nearby?
I don't sleep here!
No way!
By the law of God it is forbidden
to eat cucumbers recalling
the masculine attribute in public.
If you go away,
I warn the virtue committee.
Hello my sister.
I am Nadia El Frankaoui.
Married to El Britani.
Nadia El Britani?
Long live the caliphate.
Pass.
God bless you
of this unfaithful.
This dog
is not a brother,
he is a traitor.
He reads forbidden books,
he lives like an apostate,
he serves the enemies of God,
just like these books.
Only fire
can purify it.
The almond beats the rose bud.
Whatever!
So why was the date
beating the almond?
Because it smothers it with its honey.
She's there!
Hide everything.
You'll see. You will have looked for it!
Why did you let her out?
To wear shopping.
It's your job.
You have to punish her.
Stop telling me what to do.
Punish her!
What did I say?
My uncle?
Zara,
is that you? Where are you?
With a foreign commander
in the city center.
I'm going to exfiltrate you
but you have to escape first.
I can not.
Listen. Get out of this house.
Hide and then call me.
Promise me.
Promised.
You have to know,
your brother is alive.
And we were able to buy your mother.
Don't worry, everything will be fine.
SLEEPING TABLETS
That's enough, hurry up.
Eat.
It's better than your cooking.
Hold on!
Do you really want me to stay?
Standing! She ran away!
Shit!
I lost myself.
- Where are you?
- On the market place, I think.
Calm down.
The smuggler will take
you outside the city.
Follow the main
street and wait for it.
Okay.
Zara?
You took some time.
Go up!
Do you see the hill?
The free zone is behind.
Other refugees are heading there.
Join them.
You are supposed to take
me there. My uncle paid.
You are too late.
It is too dangerous.
Get out!
Run!
Go for it!
Protect the refugees, we attack!
Take shelter!
Warning!
They killed our guys!
Let's go!
I got it!
El Tounsi!
Fight!
Shit!
Faster!
They're rushing at the refugees!
Pass me Snoopy!
Come on!
What is that?
Mad Max.
A suicide tank.
Give!
Fire!
Shit!
The phone!
Now!
Run!
I Don'tsee it.
Go for it! What are you waiting for?
Come on...
Look at the!
This is why we are here.
They took us all...
on top of the mountain
to execute us.
I felt
the ball cross my body.
When they left...
I was still breathing.
The chief arrives.
Are you okay, chief?
A sip?
Come on, for once!
Come on, take a sip.
She's going!
Its good!
Keiro...
Your husband?
Yes.
Let me guess...
He is also in the army.
He was.
He died 5 years ago.
An ambush in Iraq.
Shit, Snipe.
Sorry.
I did not know.
worry.
"My beloved brother,
"forgive me.
"I'm leaving to avenge
our father and find Keiro.
"It must.
"I need it.
"Otherwise, I will go mad.
"Take care of mom.
"Take her to Germany.
"I need to know you are safe.
"One day,
"maybe,
if God and the angels are with us,
"I will find you and
we will live as before.
"I love you.
"Like no sister has
ever loved her brother."
What's your name?
Zara.
Me, it's Laura.
Here I am called Mother Sun.
We all have a code name.
She is Lady Kurda.
Welcome aboard.
Our chef
is known as the Lioness of Kobane.
The one driving
is American Sniper,
but it's called Snipe.
Why, Yael and I,
we don't have cool names like you?
It will come.
Sure?
Top.
In the meantime, my name is Yael.
And me, Kenza.
I am French. We are...
And that is Dushka, our goddess!
Zara, you will see,
after training,
we always walk for hours
and you never know where you're going.
We're going to the front.
OK, comrades?
We all need to rest.
Can we stop here?
Yes, let's rest.
Girls!
Come see, we can soak!
For once,
she won't take all the water.
- She is good?
- Too much!
Admit it is frozen.
Frozen!
You don't want to go there?
We can just dip our feet.
Zara!
Are you ready?
She's crazy.
You are not married?
It's the only stupidity
that I managed to avoid.
But I have a boyfriend waiting for me.
A cemetery?
Do they go after the dead now?
These tombstones
belong to the Yezidi temple.
The jihadists destroyed it.
They hate you even
more than the Jews.
Really?
Still not.
This is the 74th time that my
people have suffered genocide.
Still...
Turks and Arabs have been
trying to eliminate them for centuries.
Even some Kurds...
Not all Kurds.
Don't start confusing them.
Perhaps.
Comrades!
Come! We found a place to camp!
Now!
In fact, we are the same.
To know?
But if...
cool Muslim, cool Muslim.
Do you see these mountains?
It's my only religion.
Your parents angry with God
by worshiping the devil.
That is why
your false angel
did not protect you.
Now,
you are His army
and you will fight His enemies.
Well done,
you deserved the key
for paradise.
comrades
it's time to choose
your war names.
Comrade Belkacem?
"Kahina".
A very, very long time ago,
maybe a thousand years,
it was the name of a
Berber warrior queen
overlapping
to terrorize his enemies.
Comrade Kahina,
Welcome to you.
May this name protect you.
And you, Comrade Cohen?
"Sashka".
Sashka?
It was my grandmother's nickname.
She was deported
when she was your age,
She died
just before I join you.
Sashka,
that this name gives you
the strength to save the world.
What about you, Zara?
"Red Snake".
The Red
is an important
color for yazidis
and you, the Serpent Brigade,
you saved me.
Welcome, Red Snake.
Welcome.
Always keep one
last ball for yourself.
So as not to fall into enemy hands.
It seems that you are drawing.
If you give me a drawing,
I can tattoo it for you.
I haven't drawn since...
Did you stay there for a long time?
Too long.
My little brother...
He is always with them,
somewhere.
What's his name?
Keiro.
We'll find it.
It's my sister.
Katia.
She died before I was born.
In the 90s in Algeria,
jihadists warned that
they would kill any woman
going to school without a veil.
She refused.
My father
found her lying
in her own blood.
Our neighbors had killed her.
We've been circling
them for weeks.
But we lack reinforcements.
Stand back.
Nice shot.
The infidels attack from the south
Pray, my brothers.
You can still pray. We arrive!
And now?
We wait.
What?
Sugar delivery!
It.
Are we going to bomb the village?
There are lots of civilians.
Be the first to.
What a smell!
Jihadist barbecue...
Stop.
The bastard couldn't
set off his bomb.
Don't touch it! They trap toys.
See the yellow
thread? It is a mine.
They even erase the image
of women on shampoos?
I have my first aid kit.
We are not there to
save their supporters.
What supporter, Rosalyn?
He's a kid.
What are you doing?
Do something!
Where are you going?
In your opinion?
I'm going to take her!
Covered!
Lower yourself!
You see it?
I Don'tsee him.
Bend down!
Do you want to kill us?
Stay down.
It's over for me.
It's finish.
I love you, my sisters.
We share but I go first.
Don'tmove!
I got it. Let's go.
Hide yourself!
Search the houses!
Come on! Come on!
Chief, this one is alive!
It's El Britani.
It's him.
He's an officer.
We need to make him talk.
Our code of honor prohibits us
to torture.
Not like you, bunch of animals.
Too bad.
In your place, I will enjoy myself.
I know where Abu Mariam is.
I'll tell a man if he
swears to kill me for you.
How do you know where Abu Mariam
is? It changes hiding all the time.
There will be a ceremony
to offer her slaves this Thursday.
I had to bring him your heads.
Your brother will be there.
What?
What are you talking about?
I'll tell a man,
if he swears to kill me afterwards.
You'll have it.
But only if you tell the truth.
If not,
I'll cut your throat myself.
I feel it inside me all the time.
His smell...
His face disgusts me...
You'll get out of it.
But it takes time.
Believe me.
I was 16 when it happened to me.
It took me years to understand
that it was not my fault.
And it wasn't my fault.
It's a war.
If it's a war,
why am I so ashamed
When men come back from the front,
they show their wounds,
we look at them as heroes.
Whereas I...
I'm so ashamed.
Zara, you are so brave.
Look at me.
The invasion you suffered
is deeper
and more cruel than bullets.
And yet you are there.
Standing.
You are fighting.
You are strong.
Wars have always been
waged on the bodies of women.
But there, for once,
they fear us.
This fear is our strength.
Finally, we hold the laptop
of a lieutenant of Abu Mariam.
We know that it never circulates...
without guards or human shields.
But we will be able to track it.
You will not dare.
Where is my brother
It's a lion cub now.
Abou Mariam transformed him.
It is his favorite.
Always by his side.
One day he will be a martyr.
He will explode in a
crowd of disbelievers.
No!
- You lie!
- Not at all.
There is a video online.
It's enormous. Go see
if you don't believe me.
You will not do it.
You are weak. Like your father.
He was screaming when Abu
Mariam shot him in the head.
He was screaming like you,
when I entered you.
You liked it, right?
Come on, admit it.
Women enjoy when you force them.
I felt you enjoy a hundred times!
This gift
is for you.
Following!
Keiro...
This gift is for you.
Cover me!
I advance!
I've got your back!
Free way!
I arrive!
Your brother! Go!
Come on, little lion.
You're ready.
Come on!
You can do it. Join the Lord!
Damn it!
Slowly slowly...
Bring back Abu Mariam.
Okay.
Whore!
It's okay?
Keiro.
Look at me.
It's me.
He is mine.
Don't smile.
There will be no paradise for you.
Zara!
What do you have?
The Coalition abandons us.
It will not support
our independence.
We will create an independent Kurdistan
without them.
Kiss Me.
Here?
You are crazy?
So what?
We didn't fight
to live like them.
Come on, kiss me.
I want to show you something.
Come.
I wanted to finish it before you leave.
Like that, Kenza will always be there.
It's beautiful.
You are a real artist.
Zara,
who is the woman in the drawing?
An angel who shows us the future.
Are you sure?
It's a girl.
Juror, spitting.
Subtitling: Clog.