Not everything we did
was because of Chuck.
It was us...
The blood, the sweat,
the tears.
That's us.
There's no way that Chuck
lets us die like this.
Hi, Sam.
You're weak.
We're connected
by these wounds.
But all good things
must come to an end.
You cannot
change my mind.
- God lied to me.
-  will help you.
To bind
the spell together,
the nectar from
a Leviathan blossom
that only grows
in one place.
Purgatory.
Sam, smash it.
Now!
I can't.
I'm sorry. I...
Sammy lost hope,
and now I'm free.
Grigori.
They were some of
the first angels on Earth.
Sam: And they've been hunting
humans, feeding off them.
It's time.
- Being normal...
- Is fine.
But you and me? There's zero
about our lives that's normal.
If we don't fix this,
we might kill each other
by accident.
So, uh...
Alaska?
Alaska.
- ♪ To Alaska ♪
- ♪ North to Alaska ♪
- ♪ Go north, the rush is on ♪
- ♪ Big Sam left Seattle ♪
- ♪ In the year of '92 ♪
- ♪ With George Pratt, his partner ♪
- Come on, Joey. Give me a chance.
- ♪ And his brother, Billy, too ♪
- ♪ They crossed the Yukon River ♪
- ♪ And found the bonanza gold ♪
- ♪ Below that
old white mountain ♪
- ♪ Just a little southeast
of Nome ♪
- ♪ Sam crossed the majestic mountains ♪
- Bank side.
- ♪ To the valleys far below ♪
- ♪ He talked to his team
of huskies ♪
-♪ As he mushed on through the snow ♪
- What? No.
♪ With the Northern Lights ♪
No, no.
No.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no!
Hey!
No fights.
♪ Lonely, lonely man ♪
- ♪ I'd trade all the gold that's buried... ♪
- Aah! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Stop! Come on!
You know the rules.
Just... Just one more game,
please.
You know I'm good for it.
Aah!
Sorry, pal.
You're out of luck.
Come on!
♪ Remember, Sam, a true love
is so hard to find ♪
♪ I'd build for my Jenny
a honeymoon home ♪
G-Great, Leonard.
- ♪ Below that old mountain ♪
- Great.
♪ Just a little southeast of Nome ♪
♪ Where the river is windin' ♪
♪ Big nuggets they're findin' ♪
♪ North to Alaska ♪
♪ Go north, the rush is on ♪
*SUPERNATURAL*
Season 15  Episode 11
Episode Title: "The Gamblers"
Sam?
Dean?
Alaska.
Silent mode's always
an option.
Yeah. Right.
Sorry.
And how's Eileen doing?
She's hanging in there.
She thinks our plan
sounds a little too good
to be true.
You know,
maybe she's right.
I mean,
how long
have we been on the road
looking for some
place Garth says
will supercharge our luck,
maybe?
And I mean,
luck?
Is that really even gonna fix
our whole "problem"?
Well, it couldn't hurt.
And I don't know how much more
of this "normal life" crap
I can take,
between the credit cards,
the car trouble,
the constant freaking heartburn.
Well, you know,
if you changed your diet...
You...
all I'm saying
is that this place...
it's not even
in the lore.
Other than Garth,
no one's ever even heard of it.
No, it's there.
It's gotta be.
I mean, Chuck didn't do this
to us
just...
to teach us some messed-up lesson.
You know,
he wants us off our game.
He wants us weak.
'Cause he's coming for us,
Sammy.
And when he does,
if we haven't figured this out,
we're DOA.
Hello?
Uh, yeah, uh, uh,
Jeb Evans,
Sheriff's Department,
Cushing, Oklahoma.
Uh, uh, I'm looking
for an FBI Agent Watts?
Um, yeah,
Agent Watts is working a case in,
uh, Alaska.
This is Agent,
uh, Lizzo.
Hmm.
Well, I guess a fed's a fed,
right?
Listen, we got a homicide
down here,
and
my file says that our suspect
might be one of yours.
The murderer is someone
we're looking for?
It says Agent Watts started
a file on him last spring
and to call
with any information
regarding
a, uh, Jack Kline?
Jack.
That name ring
a bell?
Yeah.
Hey.
What are we doing?
Why did we stop?
Last call on food
for the next few hundred miles.
Grab something
out of the cooler.
Oh, yeah, no, I polished off
the last of the sandwiches
while you were out.
We're on a budget.
What can we get for, uh,
$4.60?
Um, a slice of pie
and a cup of coffee?
Of course.
Two forks?
Damn it, I was hoping
for a cheeseburger.
You can't even digest cheese anymore.
Dude. Lactaid.
Alright.
So, if Garth is right,
we take this road,
but, honestly,
it doesn't look like
there's anything up there.
Hey, how long have you
lived here?
- All my life.
- Great.
Can you tell us
what is up that road?
No.
Are you for real?
Did Candy put you up
to this?
No,
nobody put us up to this.
We're...
We're just headed that way
- and wanted to know
if there's anything up there. - Um,
forget it.
Sounds nuts.
Nuts is good.
Yeah.
A couple of
Mister Freakin' Peanuts here.
Okay. There's... There's
kind of this, um, urban legend
around here,
about this place
in the middle
of nowhere.
It's a-a pool hall
that is...
magic?
Magic pool hall?
I told ya.
They say that
if you get up there and you win,
then you come back lucky.
Like,
hit the Powerball lucky.
Sounds good to me.
Except for no one
ever does.
What do you mean?
Um, one of our regulars,
Leonard.
The bank was coming
for his house,
so he went out
to find the place
and he never came back.
Heard he had
some sort of accident.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Okay.
I guess now we know
what the downside is.
Eh, not from where I'm sitting.
A-A pool hall that makes
you lucky or might kill you?
I mean, it sounds like
a demon or a witch or...
Or it could be awesome.
It's pool. The... The...
The game of champions, kings.
My game.
Hell, our game.
How many honest-to-goodness
great memories
do we have
hustling pool?
Yeah,
because we had to.
To eat.
Okay, well, my point is,
is that if pool is the way
that we get our mojo back,
then maybe we ain't as screwed
as we thought.
Hey, you guys drive
an Impala?
I, uh, think you have
a flat.
Okay, you got the video,
right?
Uh, yes.
Okay, so, so,
Vic was
a local doctor,
and the office security
cameras gave us
a good idea of what went down.
Just an idea?
Y-You'll see.
Now, Dr. Sariel was
a good man.
He delivered
both of my kids.
Jack.
This thing's got people
pretty spooked.
I don't understand.
Me, neither. Signal goes out
for about 2 and a half minutes,
during which time, the suspect
kills the doc in his office.
Why?
Keep watching.
Is that... ?
That's his heart.
Relax.
We might actually have some fun.
Right.
Dean, we don't even have
beer money,
much less whatever
the buy-in is here.
Hey,
we'll figure something out.
Get you something?
Yeah.
Two waters, por favor.
Hey, uh...
- Evie.
Say, listen, if, uh,
me and my brother here
wanted to get ourselves
a game... ?
Pax.
Two more for ya.
Hey, you remember a guy
who was in here a few weeks ago?
Uh, name was Leonard?
No. Sorry.
Follow me.
Oh.
So, how'd you guys find us?
Uh, a friend.
Did your, uh, friend say how we wager?
Yeah, listen, uh, money's
a little tight right now.
Yeah,
we don't bet with money.
We use this.
Okay.
What are we looking at?
Go ahead.
Touch it.
Not great.
Not the worst, either.
And that means... ?
Well, you see,
everybody walks in here
with a certain amount of luck.
That glow...
that's you.
About average.
Yeah, that sounds about right.
But you set that coin
on... on that table,
you get yourself a game.
And you win?
You just might see
your fortune improve.
And if he loses?
Play again.
Have a good time.
You know, keep playing.
But if the coin goes blank,
that means you're out of luck.
You gotta leave.
Questions?
Yeah.
What is this place?
Who owns it?
I just work here.
Look, if you don't like it,
uh, the door's open.
When I win,
can I split it?
The luck?
It's yours.
You do what you want.
Yeah.
Uh, just give us a second.
Thanks.
No, no, no. No, no, no, no, no.
No way.
Man, I've been
slinging pool cues
since before you were born.
What? When you were 4?
Really?
What, between nap time
and snack?
Look, we barely made it out of
that monster fight club, okay?
We need this.
And you know it.
Now, look, you're better than me
at pretty much everything, okay?
That's okay.
I'm not mad.
I'm proud.
But I can wipe the floor
with you when it comes to pool.
Good. Alright.
Okay, pal,
let's give it a go.
I'm a Grigori.
Each of our names
inscribed on our swords.
A brotherhood of perfectly
crafted beings.
So, how long are we supposed
to just wait around?
You know,
if the fish aren't biting,
throw 'em a little chum.
I don't know, Sammy.
I'm a little rusty.
Go on. Rack 'Er up.
Mm, yeah. Yeah.
Decide not to play?
Uh, yeah.
It's not really my thing.
Hmm.
So, what's her deal?
Who? Moira?
Been here a while.
Guess her sister's
still in a coma.
So, she's playing
to wake her up?
Everybody wants something.
Yeah.
Hey, do you ever smell
anything weird,
like rotten eggs,
or... ?
Just Charlie.
Right.
What about...
Have you ever noticed
little bundles laying around?
Uh...no.
Look, you're new.
I get it. You're trying
to figure this out.
I guess
it is pretty unbelievable.
Places like this don't exist
for no reason.
Most people think
it's a Godsend.
Take that guy.
Loves his wife,
but she has expensive taste.
He came here
from Atlantic City,
not a dime left
to his name.
Or her...
Three kids, works doubles,
buys a scratcher
every night.
They both deserve
a lucky break.
And they almost got one.
They went on a streak,
could have walked away winners,
but they kept on playing
till their luck went sour.
They're not
actually winning?
Not anymore.
Like I said,
they should have walked away.
Damn it.
Why are you
following me?
It felt like a warning,
like...
like she was telling me
to cut our losses.
Come on, man.
I'm on a roll.
Dean, you won one game.
Listen, I think this place
sucks you in, right?
And if you keep playing,
you'll lose.
And if you keep losing...
You go all Leonard.
Exactly.
Alright, so, we need
to minimize our risk
and maximize our profit,
right?
It's kind of like that action
we took back in Tallahassee.
Remember that?
The... The... The "Fast Eddie"?
I don't remember.
It was Dad's favorite,
from the movie.
Paul Newman. "The Hustler."
Alright, fine.
One more game. One.
Okay.
Now we just gotta find
our Jackie Gleason.
What did you say
your name was again?
Well,
my name's Dean Winchester.
And I'm gonna kick
your ass.
Now, what kind of name
is, uh, Joey Six?
Oh, it's just something they
used to call me back in PBR.
Professional
bull riding circuit.
Nice.
Tell me.
How was that?
Corner pocket.
Good times.
And some not so good.
Double or nothing
says you miss that shot.
You trying to hustle me,
Rodeo?
I thought you were gonna kick
my ass.
Alright.
Helluva shot.
Hey.
Good game.
Guess you can hustle
a hustler.
Yeah,
I guess you can.
Stay back.
Damn it.
Let an old man go die in peace,
huh?
Wait, you're dying?
Cancer.
I came out here
to beat it.
I did win me
an extra year.
Been saving this.
Yeah, I liked that leathery
son of a bitch.
Yeah, when he bet
double or nothing,
you cleaned him out.
Okay, well, plan worked.
Let's hit the road.
What about everybody else?
Just give me some time,
alright?
I-I need
to figure this out.
Dude, we're in a fight with God,
okay?
And...we just got
our mojo back.
You really think
there's enough luck in that coin
to make up
for whatever Chuck took from us?
- Why don't I give it a whirl?
- How?
I'll go for a quick drive.
If Baby treats me right,
then I know
we're out of the woods.
But when I get back,
it's adiós.
Oh, uh,
Agent Liz-- Lizzo.
Evans.
Hi.
Glad you came.
Glad you called.
So, local transient
spotted our boy
in some sort
of an altercation.
Did they say
with whom?
No.
She ran the other way
when she saw the other guy
had a...sword.
Looks like he used it.
Are there any abandoned
buildings in town?
Yeah, I-I guess.
I mean, there's, uh,
plenty
of old cattle barns,
empty warehouses, old church,
that kind of thing.
Church.
Where's the church?
Uh, two blocks down
on your right.
Thank you.
Uh, agent?
I called you
for answers.
I know.
And I intend
to find them.
And then the Vikes
finally win the Super Bowl.
Right, that's great.
It is.
But is it really worth
your life?
Look, man, just...
just one more game.
Nice try.
Too bad
no one will listen.
None of us
are going anywhere.
Are they trapped here?
Are you?
Well, car's dead. Again.
Didn't even make it
out of the parking lot.
This coin...
blows.
I think you're right.
Didn't have enough juice.
Hold on.
No way.
At first, I thought maybe
these coins were...
were hexed or cursed.
Like the rabbit's foot.
When you win, you're...
you're taking luck
from whoever you beat,
right?
Right. But Joey Six beat
how many people?
30? 40? More?
All of that accumulated luck
should have been passed to you.
Well, tell that to Baby.
Exactly. It didn't.
Because what if
someone's stealing,
every game,
skimming luck off the top?
What... What do you mean?
Like, the house?
Her. I think.
"Atrox Fortuna"?
She's the Roman Goddess
of Luck.
Okay, say you're right.
What do we do?
I-I can't help you.
I'm sorry.
Then why warn me
in the first place?
So you'd take your brother
and go.
Wait,
why are you here?
Does she have something
over you?
I came to play.
I lost.
I'm only alive
'cause she lets me stay.
Long as I keep working.
So, if you don't play yourself
to death,
you work yourself to death.
Is that it?
Yeah, that's it.
Is she here?
I don't know.
I only talk to Pax.
Her son.
You should heal that.
I know what you are.
You're powerful.
Why not use it?
Fight back?
As a soldier,
I respect your silence,
tactically misguided
as it may be.
For example,
when I ask
why are you killing my kind,
you should answer
so I won't hurt you.
Why did you kill them?
We Grigori have our own
frequency of angel radio.
Did you know that?
Before he died,
my brother called to me.
Did you want him to?
To draw me out?
Kill me, too?
Pax.
Hey, uh, can I ask you
a question?
Where's your mom?
Fortuna!
We have your son.
Enough.
Fortuna?
That's one of my names.
We know you're skimming luck
off what we won.
We want it back.
Or I kill him.
Well, you probably could.
His daddy was human.
But, no.
Mom.
I'm sorry, baby.
I can always make
more sons.
Then play me for it.
I played you already.
Then we go again.
When I play someone,
I get a read on them.
And you...
you're just a beach read.
Sexy, mm,
but skimmable.
Beach read?
Lady, I'm Tolstoy.
That's very funny.
This one here...
He could be interesting.
Wait. No, no, no.
That's... Unh-unh.
Fine.
Yeah, I'll play.
But not for our luck.
I'll play for the lives
of everybody in here.
No.
Only for your luck.
And if you lose,
I get your lives.
Come on,
you threatened my baby,
my livelihood.
An example must be made.
So ... are you in?
You can't kill me.
I can make you
uffer.
You killed
the last of my kind.
You ate their hearts!
This is more than fair.
Fair?
The last one I killed
was pretending to be a doctor.
Feeding on the souls of humans
he was supposed to heal.
You do it, too.
Only you like children.
Who told you that?
Death.
Jack?
Guess that makes me
solids.
So, why do you need this luck
so bad?
Girlfriend problems?
Liver failure?
Accursed by God.
Life's a bitch,
then you die.
The God...literally
cursed us.
You've met?
Yeah.
Little guy,
squirrelly as hell.
Yeah, that's him.
Well ...
welcome to the club.
The club?
Yes, the club.
God created the world,
but you know
who created us gods?
You did. You humans.
Sort of.
When you apes first climbed down
from the trees,
you didn't pray to him.
You prayed to the...
the sun, the womb, the rain,
and the stars.
Well, at first,
the creator was furious.
How dare you not recognize
his beneficence?
But soon enough,
he birthed us...
Ra, Anu, Hera, Mixcoatl,
all the rest.
Why?
To take the blame.
Bad harvest?
Stillborn child?
Our bad. Not his.
Plus, we made
for epic stories.
But his ego could only
handle that for so long.
Now he's happy
to hide behind whatever religion
has the best
syndication deal.
While we survive on scraps
in the wilderness.
Most gods,
they're forgotten.
But I'm old.
I hold a grudge.
Oh, well.
What are you gonna do?
We're gonna fight him.
Are you, now?!
And when you lose...?
Sam: We lose swinging.
Eight ball,
corner pocket.
You little minx.
You got me talking.
You're good.
I learned
from my brother.
Alright,
you know the deal.
Even up.
What do you say
we make it interesting?
Okay?
You're gonna fight God.
That's the stuff of heroes,
right?
So, you're gonna need
the luck of heroes...
Hercules, Cuchulain,
Gilgamesh.
I helped them all.
I can help you, too.
What's the catch?
Another game.
Double or nothing.
Double.
That's how
the cowboy died.
Yeah.
Deal.
But not for more luck.
For them.
If I win,
you have to let them go.
Honey,
I'm not stopping them.
Okay, then when I win,
you have to give back
the luck you stole.
Close up shop.
What is with you
and these loser?
They're nothing!
They don't matter.
They matter to me.
They matter to us.
Well, fine.
Rack 'em up.
Eight ball,
corner pocket.
You challenged the Goddess of Luck
in her own joint.
What did you think
was gonna happen?
Well, we had to try.
Well, that was stupid.
Thought
she was gonna kill us.
Yeah,
she doesn't have to.
Our luck will do that
on its own.
Dean,
we can't just...
- Just leave them.
- No. I know.
Alright, well,
let's go find some Wi-Fi
and see
what kills Lady Luck.
Then we'll circle back.
Hey.
What... What's going on?
What happened?
-She...
She shut it down.
- What?!
- Why?
Because of you.
She said she thought your kind
had gone extinct.
Our kind?
Heroes.
Like the old days.
And, uh,
she gave me a message.
She said,
"Don't play his game.
Make him play
yours."
Come on.
We're back, baby!
Alright, this is it.
Last scratcher.
Come on, come on.
What the hell?!
I mean, so much for
that "Luck of Hercules" crap.
So, we didn't win
the lottery.
But no car trouble.
Uh, credit cards work.
Oh, and back-to-back
bacon double cheeseburgers
didn't kill you, so...
That was beautiful,
by the way.
I'm just saying
would it have killed her
to give us
a little extra?
Well, she thinks
we're real heroes.
Maybe they don't get
all the shortcuts.
Friggin' gods, man.
Cass?
Hey.
Everything okay?
Hello.
Jack?
It's really him.
Jack, you...
you ate their hearts?
I...had to.
And you let him?
You could have called us.
Every day I wanted to come home,
but...
..I couldn't.
Why not?
Because if I don't
stay hidden,
if I use my powers,
my grandfather...
he'll know I'm back,
and he'll try
and kill me...
again.
He's afraid of me.
And that's why
we had to wait.
Billie kept him hidden
in the Empty
until Chuck
went off world.
She let me out
when it was safe.
Safe to what?
Eat a bunch of angel hearts?
Safe to do
what I have to.
The hearts,
they were just the beginning.
They made me strong,
but I-I'm not strong enough.
I...
If I do
exactly what she says,
if I follow her plan,
then I'll get stronger
and...
I'll be able
to kill God.
Synchronized by srjanapala