[bird crowing]
[cat meowing, mouse squeaking]
[elephant trumpeting, lion roaring]
♪ Go! ♪
[opening theme playing]
♪ T-E-E-N ♪
♪ T-I-T-A-N-S ♪
♪ Teen Titans, let's go ♪
♪ Teen Titans, go ♪
-- Addic7ed.com --
[gasps]
- I gots the book!
- You mean, the book?
That's right, yo.
- The book!
- The book?
The book!
Let me see,
let me see, let me see!
What book could possibly elicit
so much of the excitement?
This be The Giant Book
of Recorded Records, yo.
It chronicles the most amazing
human feats ever accomplished.
In the realm of the track
and the field?
Anyone can win a race.
These are people who have truly
pushed human capability to the limit.
Behold!
[Robin gasps] The largest person
to ever ride a motorcycle.
[Cyborg] That dude who ate
the world's longest sandwich.
[Raven] Check out how much weight this
lady can lift with just her tongue.
These are truly the most
special of people.
[sighs] I wish I were
the special like them.
What? Star,
you are special.
Everyone is specials
in their own specials way.
But not as special
as the people with the records.
I can't argue with that.
I mean, they got records
and everything.
Then perhaps I can do
the setting of the record.
Hmm, setting a record
is a big commitment.
These things take a lot of time
and effort to accomplish.
Then I shall do the sleeping
prior to the decision-making.
[sighs] One day, I too, will
be in the book of the records.
Then I will be the special.
[snoring]
You got what it takes, Star!
Oh, do you really think so?
Well, setting a record
ain't no joke.
Are you willing to dedicate
yourself to the task?
With all of my heart.
[mumbling]
I cannot understand
the sandwich mouth.
But you have inspired me to try.
[crowing like rooster]
Good morning, fellow Titans.
[whirring, clangs]
I have the greatest of the news.
I have decided
to set the record.
In fact, I have already begun.
Which record?
[chuckles]
Can you not the see?
[humming pointedly]
- No, dude.
- [giggles]
I shall set the record
for the longest fingernails
ever grown.
[gagging]
That's be so unnaturals.
I've never seen such a thing
in all my days!
Star, it'll take years for you to
grow your fingernails out like that.
Yeah, that dude
took 50 years to grow his.
Time matters the not,
for I have dedicated
my whole heart to the task.
Whys you pick something
so nasty, yo?
So I can be the special.
At least consider
an easier record to set, like,
world's most likable Teen Titan.
[Robin and Cyborg burp]
- [Beast Boy munching]
- [Raven farting]
Thank you, Raven.
But it is decided.
I will never give the ups.
No matter the cost!
It may be a terrible idea,
but I support you, Star.
I's bets you won'ts be able
to last two months
before you realize how shameful
a goal this be.
[teeth chattering]
Everything okay, Star?
Ugh, at this pace,
it will be the forever before
I do the setting of the record.
You don't have to do this, Star.
You're already special
just the way you are.
That is very nice, Robin.
But your opinion
does not matter to me.
[crunch]
[retching]
- [snipping]
- [all screaming]
- [grunting]
[pigeons cooing]
Robin!
Robin...
What? [groans]
I have an itch under my nose
that requires the scratching.
Oh, yeah.
That's the spot.
Yeah.
Do you have any idea how close
I am to setting the record
for the longest fingernails
ever grown?
What?
Very close!
[sighs] Just a few more
of the years.
[thudding]
Okay, this has gone far enough.
That's right.
We're cutting those nails.
Why would I let you do that?
Just look at those hands.
You've been in misery
the last 50 years.
And we can't let it go on.
My hands are in the pain.
The weight of the fingernails
is so very great.
Then that settles it.
You're getting a manicure.
I would not try that
if I were the you.
Oh, yeah?
What if we try it anyway?
[Starfire growling]
[grunts] I will show you,
what I will do.
[straining] Once I am able
to aim my hands at you.
Your fingernails are so long, you
can't even move your hands around.
You'll thank us when we're done.
And then we can have
some matzo ball soup.
Do you know how many personal
sacrifices have been made
in the setting of this record?
I gave up being the superhero.
I gave up
all of the human contact
because I cannot do the hugging.
And, worst of all,
I have not held a single kitty
in over 50 years.
I have wasted my life
in order to be special
when, in fact,
I shall never be special.
You don't need
to set any records.
You're special
just the way you are.
Do you mean that?
I've been saying that for years.
Yes, but I do not care
about your opinion.
Oh!
There's no reason
for any more pain.
[sighs]
All the right.
Do it.
[alarm blaring]
[Starfire gasps]
What is the emergency?
[Cyborg] An asteroid
is going to hit Jump City
and destroy all life
as we know it.
We may be old,
but we're still superheroes.
And we can still save
the planet.
There we go.
Almost there. Just about.
Here's the plan.
We gather our remaining
stock pile of explosives.
We load the explosives
into the Titans rocket.
[beeps]
Then launch it into space
and blow that asteroid
into dust.
[electricity crackling]
There's a problem
with that plan, dummy.
The Titans rocket
is currently inoperational.
What?
Now, before you get mad,
just know this happened
in our younger years
a long time ago.
- Two weeks ago.
- That's right. Two weeks ago.
Yeah, yeah. We, uh, filled up the
cockpit with hot, bubbly water
and made ourselves a hot tub
space rocket.
Hot tub space rocket!
Oh, [chuckles] that was...
Let me tell you something.
Of course, the water fried all
the circuits so, you know...
The world is going to end
because of you!
[all crying]
[gasps]
[straining]
[cracking]
[computer beeping rapidly]
[grunting]
[creaking]
[sighs]
- [all crying]
- [alarm stops blaring]
[computer chimes]
[videogame music playing]
[all cheering]
I knew you had it in you.
I'm so glad you had
them fingernails all nasty.
You go, girl!
You saved the planet.
That's what's up!
Yes, great job, Star.
Oh, you are making me feel so...
special.
- [waves crashing]
- [birds squawking]
Would you look at that.
That guy set the record
for crushing the most kumquats
with his biceps.
That is a most
praise-worthy use for a bicep.
Sorry you didn't make it into The
Giant Book of Recorded Records, Star.
That is the okay
- because I did make it into the book
- [glass shattering]
of People Who Have Stopped
an Asteroid.
[Beast Boy] This is you,
Superman, and Bruce Willis.
[all cheering]
- [Beast Boy] That's what's up!
- [Cyborg] You kept them nails going.
Everybody told you they was nasty!
-- Addic7ed.com --