The film material of this movie
has been preserved...
...by Filmoteca de la UNAM.
This movie was digitalized by
the Laboratory of Film Restoration...
...of Cineteca Nacional, from a
35 mm negative nitrate film.
"The Kneeling Goddess" belongs to
the Collection of Fundation Televisa A.C.
This version is the result of a joint
conservation project...
...between Cineteca Nacional Mexico and
Fundación Televisa A.C...
...in order to preserve Mexican Cinema.
THE KNEELING GODDESS
- How many days now?
- Why think about that?
It would spoil the little time
we have left.
Is it little, then?
This time it is.
What I mean is time
will be completely ours someday.
Don't worry, Antonio,
I understand.
I never ask you anything.
I've never wanted to ask you anything.
That's a proof of our love.
Never inquire about the mystery of
the past, if we truly love our love.
But it is so difficult to be strong
in loneliness and we meet so seldom.
Let us never abandon each other.
It would be like dying.
Then, let us shut our eyes...
...and live that dream.
I will keep them closed so my soul
doesn't escape from this dream.
Kiss me again, Antonio.
Mexicana Airlines announces the departure
of flight 505 to Mexico City.
Passengers, please board the aircraft.
I can't help it, Antonio.
Everything between us is so brief.
Don't get impatient, I'll write.
I'll be back on September 25th.
Goodbye then.
What? Are you moved?
It's funny, you've become sentimental.
A serious flaw in business.
Don't tell me you're falling in love.
Stop it.
This is stronger than my will.
Antonio is different from the rest.
But don't worry, Nacho.
We said that nothing could
destroy our bond...
...except for ourselves.
Don't blame me.
I'm the one who is destroying it.
Neither of us
should have a past. True.
But if you were ever to hear about mine,
you'd know I don't deserve you.
I don't want to go on deceiving you
and I can't let you know the truth either.
Forget me.
Goodbye.
Come in, José.
Here is the letter. You shan't forget
the instructions, shall you?
Don't worry, Miss Raquel.
As soon as that man comes,
I'll deliver him the letter.
- If he asks where you went...?
- Tell him you don't know anything.
- Good night, José.
- Good night, miss.
And believe me,
I am going to miss you dearly.
"So, ratifying our contract...
...we'd like you to send us your
approval as soon as possible.
Sincerely.
Mexico City.
September 25th".
September 25th.
This is the act from yesterday's
council for your approval, sir.
WEAR DESIRE
LOVERS' PERFUME
Let's leave it until
I return from Guadalajara.
Good day, sir.
Everything is ready.
- Here is your airplane ticket.
- Thank you very much, Esteban.
I almost forgot
that you were coming.
Look out the window
across the street.
Yes, sir.
That sign they're putting up...
a perfume.
- "Desire"?
- Yes, "Desire".
Tell me, Esteban.
What does desire mean to you?
The word itself says it, sir.
It is what one longs for,
what one wants...
That is, what one desires.
Exactly. It's also a force that makes you,
that drives you to get what you want...
...and to keep it
if you already have it, right?
Yes, sir.
That force can grow, take on a shape,
become free, greater than you.
Then, it ends up destroying you.
And, what's worse,
destroying those close to you.
Elena?
- Yes?
- I want to say goodbye.
I have a surprise. I decided
to put off my trip to Guadalajara.
But, wasn't it urgent?
It is no longer necessary.
The matter I had to handle...
...I have solved definitively.
Yes. I'll be right over.
Goodbye.
My talk about desire
must have bewildered you.
But there was a purpose to it.
For a long time, I've gotten
the feeling you desire...
...to take a vacation. Here.
Sir, me... on a plane...
I've never flown before in my life.
Flying without an airplane
would be dangerous.
Miss, let's finish the dictation.
Come at once.
Wait for me outside.
We'll go home together.
Yes, sir.
Antonio, I was so happy
that you put off your trip.
Now... Now, I am completely happy.
Come. We're going
to do many things together.
We'll refurbish.
We'll pretty up the house.
- Yes, Elena. Anything you want.
- Look, finish the fountain.
It'll be ready long before
our anniversary.
- Don't you think it'll be beautiful?
- Yes, very beautiful.
But incomplete. What's the same
as saying: "Not so beautiful".
Something incomplete does not lack
in beauty. There is Venus de Milo.
True. And Schubert's
Incomplete Symphony.
Venus of Milo?
That's it! You got it. That's what the
fountain will need once it is finished.
Something like the Venus, would be
the best anniversary present for me.
You're terrible.
Really.
Go to Demetrio's studio
and pick out a nice sculpture.
- Something in your taste. All right?
- All right.
The package of books you ordered
from the library is in your laboratory.
Doctor Vidaurri has arrived, madam.
I will be right there.
Elena.
Have you been feeling ill again?
It's nothing, darling.
The usual treatment.
I will call you as soon
as the meal is ready.
Raquel and I bade farewell
with our usual secret inquietude.
Would we meet again?
Would that be the last time?
Or, would there be others?
Now I can answer
those questions.
After a terrible struggle,
I defeated desire.
Raquel...
...the woman who reincarnated it...
...has been banned
from my life forever.
The Kneeling Goddess.
That's what Demetrio called her.
Although she is really...
...a simple woman on her knees,
just like all men like to see women.
What are you doing here?
Why are you talking that way?
I warned you, you'd be disappointed
when you saw the real me.
You warned me?
Antonio, fancy meeting you here!
You've come to see her, haven't you?
Look, isn't she fabulous?
Her name is quite adequate.
The Kneeling Goddess.
The name, it's my masterpiece!
Who told you that was its name?
Mysterious voices in your studio
explain it all.
Look, such pureness in lines.
Her torso is absolutely classic...
...the outline of her leg is
the prettiest thing I've seen...
...and the whole form
is the consummation...
...of the most perfect equilibrium.
Difficult to surpass by anybody.
- I've come to buy her from you.
- Buy her?
Naturally. I wouldn't have expected less
from a connoisseur like you.
It is a gift for Elena.
Nothing more fitting. You are giving
your wife immortality.
That means that I am entitled
to a part of it.
How much does the whole
immortality cost?
Let's not discuss money now,
it makes me nauseous.
Tell me about her. So, you have fallen
in love. That would be my greatest feat!
I made her to inspire love.
To bring about desire.
You fulfill your mission.
When I look at her
I feel like I know her.
As if a distant evocation
had turned to marble.
Exactly! That is how I felt in Rome
when I saw the work of Michelangelo.
When may I send for her?
It's hard to say. She isn't finished,
though she seems to be.
- I'm a blasphemous. What is missing?
- Everything.
The last strike of the chisel.
The one that will give her life.
You'll have to wait
a month, a year perhaps.
If it's less than a century,
let me know and send the receipt.
Goodbye, Demetrio.
She's ready! The receipt
shall be ready tomorrow.
- Does he usually buy statues?
- What do you mean by "usually"?
- Is it an addiction?
- That's not what I meant.
He seems like a strange fellow.
No. Different.
Of course, not at all like us.
What about her?
She's so fake and supernatural
you could call her a true wife.
- Somewhat insufferable, of course.
- Quite the opposite, at least from him.
He adores her.
He sees through her eyes.
Even when he looks at other women?
He would never do such a thing.
You'd be wasting your time.
Could be.
No, Antonio, this shows that
we are trying to flee from each other.
Don't blame me, Raquel.
Sometimes what we do is determined...
...by dark, secret impulses.
When I saw you today, my memories
suddenly blended like an avalanche.
Memories?
What good are words?
We have before us a reality
greater than all words.
We live in different worlds.
That is our reality.
But we have met again and
we cannot deny what it means.
Yes. Our madness was to imagine
that we could live without the past.
Don't take away my right
to the one thing I've left.
My own future.
I'm not taking it from you.
I want to be a part of it.
Take me home, Antonio.
We'd better say goodbye here.
Goodbye.
There is nothing worse
than deceiving oneself.
All my struggle was in vain.
I understand
that it is stronger than I.
Madam shouldn't have come down.
Don't worry, I feel well.
Please reconsider,
the effort is too large.
I shall have to make
larger efforts yet!
Antonio!
What are you doing here?
You shouldn't have come down.
The doctor forbade you to.
I'm the one who should reprimand you.
You haven't slept a wink.
I... had to finish an analysis.
Besides, that doesn't matter.
You haven't been taking
care of yourself, Elena.
I should be taking care of you
although it may seem like a contradiction.
I get the feeling you're
in grave danger, Antonio.
It's your imagination. The only way
nothing will happen to me...
...is knowing you are in good health.
Rest assured, I am a lot
stronger than you imagine.
Nobody will tear me
apart from you.
Why do you say that?
Women always feel a threat
as it approaches.
You are surrounded by ghosts
and schemes that don't exist.
Love is never deceived!
I can see beyond your eyes,
your sleepless nights and worries...
I don't want you to be alone. I've decided
not to return to the Rochester clinic.
What?
That is madness.
- Don't play games with your health.
- Our love's health is first!
Stop insisting!
You could truly compromise it
If you stay.
All right.
I will return to the clinic
after our anniversary.
There is the risk
that it may be the last.
POISON
Maybe I'll find a door out.
A determination.
The only one.
Although it may be the most
extreme and painful.
I am like a man returning
from a storm, Raquel.
I wandered for hours
and didn't even notice.
Lonely and isolated, as if
I were in a big, empty house.
I would have liked
to walk without stopping.
Not interrupting an escape that
suddenly seemed impossible.
Then, I decided to return,
do you understand?
Taking your shadow with me was foolish
for I couldn't get away from it.
The image of you was everywhere.
Alive and terrible to despair.
You wanted it this way,
Antonio.
I tried to leave, but you
united our fates again.
Now you must have the courage
for your truth.
For the truth about both of us.
Either you are mine or you destroy me.
There is no middle ground.
Because our love speaks another language.
It says life to death.
Fire to cold,
and words to silence.
You must understand this language
with your own life.
I too either am yours or destroy you.
With no middle ground, either.
And if we love each other
there shall be no before or after.
It shall be like
the beginning of the world.
I have the strength for that love.
I swear.
Decide within yourself.
If you too have the strength...
...go back to your wife and tell her,
for she will understand.
Is that your condition?
Yes.
Now, go. I'll wait.
No news, sir.
Nobody knows where he is.
But that's impossible.
Keep looking,
he has to be somewhere.
I'll be expecting your call.
Thank you.
Come in.
Her husband must know
her condition.
She has to stay in bed and may not
leave her quarters under any circumstance.
I'll be back after midnight.
Antonio.
It's me, madam.
Have you any news?
Where is he?
He's coming, madam.
He shan't be long.
Naturally.
He cannot be absent on our day.
I have to get ready.
Tell Maria to come up and help me.
Madam, don't you think
it would be wiser...
...to wait for him here,
without such agitation?
That's madness! Are you forgetting
that this is our anniversary?
It will be as always.
The same friends, the same bliss.
Go on, tell Maria to come.
I'm sorry, Elena.
You're home now.
I don't want to hear anything.
- Good evening.
- How are you, Antonio?
Is The Kneeling Goddess there?
I waited for you in vain.
I came only to know the reason
of your determination.
Is it lack of love or courage?
You will understand if
you allow me to explain.
And if it isn't too late
for an explanation.
Time doesn't count between us.
You know that.
That's what's so terrible.
I told you before, I will allow you
no middle ground.
There will be no before or after.
You don't need an introduction.
You immediately recognized her.
The Kneeling Goddess.
Demetrio insists on saying
that nature copies art.
It's not my quote,
but it may as well be.
Everything is ready, madam.
Let us go to the dining room.
MRS. ELENA G. DE ITUARTE
DIED YESTERDAY
THE FAMOUS MODEL RAQUEL SERRANO
IS GOING TO MAKE ONE'S DEBUT
AS A CABARET SINGER IN PANAMA
I got married
I got taken
I have fallen in the trap
Set by the woman
In order to marry well,
You've got to be smart
You've got to be submissive
For the catch
But once you're married
You've got to show your temper
For by then we must
Not care about our husband
When you get married,
Find yourself a wife
That is elegant
And very beautiful
Because that way
All your life
You may have
A lot of time to lose
And now, gentlemen
You can see for yourselves
What happens to the man
Who searched for a wife
I don't know what love is
I am ashamed to confess
In my arms you will know
Why I am a professor
If I do not correspond
Don't hold it against me
My lovely little wife
You have a crystal soul
I knew love once.
It is very beautiful.
But for me it was
brief and betraying.
At first it was glorious,
but later became despicable.
Its law is pleasure...
...for money.
Love
For you, I drank
My own tears
Love
You were my cross
My religion
Vengeance is fair
And in the meantime
Let us live
Deceiving our hearts
Love
For you I drank
My own tears
Love
You were my cross
My religion
Vengeance is fair
And in the meantime
Let us continue
Deceiving our hearts
To be happy
And live without a care
Don't let your heart speak out
You will live your life
Oblivious to pain
Better to enjoy it,
Better to laugh!
- For you
- For me
- It must be.
- The best
Not to marry,
Not to marry
Because, I believe
We will enjoy love more
If we're not married,
Not married
I won't get married,
If I did I would die
Being single,
That is what I prefer
For you, for me,
For everybody
It is best to forget about love
I won't get married,
If I did I would die
Being single,
That is what I prefer
For you, for me, for everybody,
It is best to forget about love
So, what are you?
I am Panamanian
Because through my veins runs
Sensual blood
So, what are you?
I am Panamanian
From that garden of dreams
That is my Panama
So, what are you?
I am the owner
Of the joy of my Panama
Panama, tropical bliss
Raquel!
What's wrong? You are
insufferable these days.
The way that man drinks is intolerable.
He hasn't been sober since he arrived.
I think you've taken
this affair much too far.
You don't even know
what his true intentions are.
It seems strange he traveled
thousands of miles only to get drunk.
There's more than meets the eye.
Don't complain,
you've put it to good use.
But if he stays here,
he could get us into a mess.
We should get a good
indemnity out of him...
...and then send him off,
in all courtesy, of course.
It would be best...
to send him off.
What do you want?
For everybody to drink up!
To the last drop.
Until there's nothing left.
No middle ground.
To extermination
or to surrender.
You know what I mean,
don't you?
Here.
Go get a taxi.
Go, what are you waiting for?
Antonio, when will you tell me
what brought you to Panama?
Tell me.
This man is mad.
He meant to kill you.
- We should hand him over to the police.
- I know what's wrong with him.
He will bring us trouble. The sooner
we get away from him, the better.
Your taxi is waiting, sir.
Take him to the hotel.
I'll talk to him tomorrow.
Come in.
It's me, Antonio.
I came to say goodbye.
Wait for me. I'll be right out.
I brought you your lighter.
You left it in the dressing room.
How do you feel?
I'm fine now, thank you.
I must go, Antonio.
Wait, we have to talk!
I don't want to be late for rehearsal.
I'll see you at the night club.
Did you get the wire, sir?
- What wire?
- The one I took to your room.
Oh, yes.
Here.
Figaro, Figaro, Figaro
At last.
What a mess!
A woman wears so many clothes,
and I had to fix your bags myself.
I packed my stockings,
my panties,
I packed my girdle, I packed...
So much...
The ship leaves at five in the morning.
Sky and sea to open destiny.
To return to our free
and pilgrim existence.
Isn't this wonderful?
"Goodbye...
...Panama".
Nacho, I'm not going with you.
What?
You are joking. That's like
throwing everything away.
I have always lived doing that.
We have always walked together.
It was our only bond.
- Wandering senselessly. Now, it's over.
- What made you change so much?
This.
So, then it wasn't natural
death, was it?
Did you know his wife had died?
Why did you hide it from me?
I thought it was best for us both.
From your perspective. Can you
grasp the meaning of that wire?
Yes. Her death under strange
circumstances means many things.
Do you mean to tell me that now...?
I have come to understand
Antonio truly loves me.
I am not just a simple whim for him.
Now that he is free he comes to me.
He is free by his own hand.
Listen to me.
Antonio has killed for me.
You are so easy to deceive
by your own fabrications!
You made up a triumphant and
extraordinary world...
...where you are the goddess at whose
feet all sacrifices are consummated.
Don't be blinded by the
idea that he killed for you.
You don't know Antonio.
He is capable of any extreme act.
You won't always find a man
who behaves as I do.
Of course.
Spite is blinding you.
Am I to blame for not loving you?
Maybe you're right.
Raquel...
...today was the happiest
day of my life.
Try to understand, Nacho.
I may just be assuming things,
but I found this hidden in his lighter.
Cyanide?
There is enough poison here
to kill a horse.
Could it have been
intended for you? I'm sorry.
You may be right.
It looks like Antonio
poisoned her.
Isn't this irrefutable proof?
What do you think?
You know? It isn't my own love
that has me trapped anymore.
I must have the strength to play out
Antonio's fate...
...without fearing the consequences.
Our passion made me his accomplice.
Be warned!
Our farewell number.
To be happy and live
Without a care
Do not allow
Your heart to speak
You'll live your life
And never suffer
It is better to enjoy it,
Better to laugh!
- For you
- For me
- It must be
- The best
Not to marry,
Not to marry
I believe we will
Enjoy love more
If we're not married,
Do not married
I will not get married,
If I did I would die
Being single,
That is what I prefer
For you, for me, for us,
It is best to forget about love
- For you
- For me
- It must be
- The best
Not to marry,
Not to marry
I believe we will enjoy love better
If we're not married,
Not married
I will not get married,
If I did I would die
Being single is what I prefer
For you, for me, for us,
It is best to forget about love
I will not get married,
If I did, I would die
Being single is what I prefer.
For you, for me, for us,
It is best to forget about love
Eleven thirty in my room.
So, what are you?
I am Panamanian
Because through my veins runs
Sensual blood
- Shall I come and serve?
- I will do it myself.
- Happy New Year, sir.
- Happy New Year.
- Good evening, Antonio.
- Good evening.
Did I keep you waiting?
I didn't mean to.
Just enough time to make
the kind of scenery you deserve.
Didn't Demetrio use to say
"The perfect frame for a work of art"?
Demetrio... all that
is so distant, isn't it?
Yes, very distant.
I think we have had to wander such strange
roads just to get to the same point.
Everything has been so strange.
Also my presence here.
Maybe.
Why did you flee this morning?
What were you afraid of?
Of so many things.
A happy fear
I have not overcome.
That doesn't answer my question.
Why did you flee like that?
I saw things differently.
I submitted myself to
the inevitable presence of your wife.
But now that I know everything
I have no reserves.
If you were capable of killing for love
I too feel capable of sharing your crime.
Here.
Now you shall have me
completely in your hands.
The fact is we are
in each other's hands.
I am also adrift.
I too destroyed
the rope behind me.
Would you rather
I read it to you?
Everything depends on
your attitude after I read it.
You have to know what it says.
It's the honest thing to do.
It is presumed your wife
didn't die of natural causes.
Your lawyer seems
to foresee some difficulties.
I was scared to give it to you.
I only opened it because it was from her.
Such a difficult battle
to win your heart over.
God! We're overlooking
the year is dying.
The year has ended.
To our listeners,
all sorts of happy wishes.
Joy and well being for the living
and a memory full of gratitude...
...for who are no longer with us.
Joy and well being
for the living, Antonio.
For us, the living.
Thank you, sir.
- Only unpack the things you need.
- Are we leaving right away?
We will be here
as briefly as possible.
I am so glad, Antonio!
Now I believe in our new life.
I have to leave you a few hours.
I need to see my lawyer.
The ticket agency will call
to confirm the time of departure.
We will fly to New York at dawn.
New York, then to Europe.
We will get married in Italy.
I'll be right back.
Sir, I was expecting you
a lot earlier.
- Did you have a good trip, sir?
- Yes, Esteban. Thank you.
Counselor Jiménez
has called several times.
What did you say?
That Counselor Jiménez
has been looking for you.
You wanted to rest.
I will arrange your
bedroom immediately.
Wait.
It seems as if...
...nothing has changed since then.
Who knows, sir.
It seems things never change
and they are always in their place.
But they are not the same.
They are lacking in warmth.
They die, too.
Whole months without
lighting the fireplace.
Everything has become dull
and cold in this house, sir.
Counselor.
Just a minute.
- What should I tell him?
- I don't want to talk to him.
He asks you to excuse him...
...and to give me a message.
All right.
I'll convey your message,
counselor.
Goodbye.
Counselor Jiménez said
he will be right over.
He wants to discuss some issues
concerning your late wife's insurance.
Besides, he says it is urgent you
give the names of the witnesses...
...in order to apply
for your new marriage license.
God has granted me life
to contemplate such things.
What am I to do?
You regret it,
don't you, Esteban?
Who am I to regret it, sir,
but a mere old...
...servant who knew your
late wife...
...since she was
barely more than a child.
You cannot tell a heart
by looking at a face.
How can I know what is
going on inside your heart, sir?
You must have you reasons
for doing what you're doing.
Although I agree, that
loneliness is easy for no man.
For none.
There is no worse punishment
than loneliness, Esteban.
Don't go yet.
Stay a bit longer.
Talk to me about her.
I am afraid to sadden you with my memories
which will also make me sad.
This fireplace...
...has aged so much...
that it lets the smoke leak now.
You want memories, sir.
It is natural. Your trip was meant
to help you get over this.
Wasn't it?
My trip!
It was like trying to put out
a fire with a sea of fuel.
But...talk to me.
Tell me about her.
If you will excuse me,
she was a sweet, quiet child.
But inside she was stern
and full of willpower.
I had to save my love from
the dangers that were threatening it.
Elena felt it.
To protect us,
I was prepared to everything.
I must finish with the desire,
by killing the woman that embodies it.
But destiny was
preparing me something different.
It was the night of
our wedding anniversary.
I was about to complete my purpose.
That was the decisive moment.
But, the gaze of Elena got in my way.
I felt she knew everything.
So I had to postpone...
...the terrible moment of what
I thought was going to be my freedom.
Come!
You have to light on the candles.
It was me who suggested Demetrio
to bring Raquel to the party.
I prepare everything
so they could stay at the end.
That way, I could prepare everything
I've planned for Raquel.
- Let's go, Demetrio!
- Don't go! Take one last drink!
What do you prefer?
By chance, as if something was
helping me for my crazy purposes...
...each one had asked
for a different beverage.
Elena wanted champagne.
Demetrio, whiskey...
...and Raquel, cognac.
My chemical knowledge
had helped me to calculate all...
...in a few hours, taking into account
Raquel's physical conditions...
...I will achieve the desire effect,
and no one could blame me for her death.
Sir!
But in those moments,
something got my attention.
Dr. Vidaurri wanted to talk to me
about my wife's health...
...and about what had happened
that day, it was severe.
He waited for me at the lab,
he didn't want Elena to see him.
Your wife can live, just if she has a
rigorous diet and if she doesn't have...
...strong or unhappy emotions.
If not, I won't be responsible.
Your wife's life is in your hands.
Good night!
Elena's life is in my hands.
I stay there, thinking about
this terrible fact.
I promise to wholly dedicate
myself to Elena.
Meanwhile, in the living room,
the desire must be vanishing...
...Rachel must have drunk the poison.
One minute later, I don't know why,
she left my home with Demetrio.
What happened?
Why did they go?
What are you doing with that drink?
Elena!
Elena had drunk the drink.
Trying to kill Raquel, an ironic tragedy
made me finish with what I love the most.
I tried all to save her.
But everything was in vain.
Those words were so terrifying and truth.
A man can kill what he loves the most.
A coward man with a kiss,
a brave one with a sword.
These few words surround
my entire tragedy.
I'm the murderer of my wife.
Excuse me, sir.
Mr. Jiménez has just arrived.
I'll be there in a minute.
What are they suggesting? It has been
a murder, not a natural death?
They just want to defend themselves.
The expert doctors
doesn't anticipate a sudden death.
Knowing that the policy was bought
by your wife when she was very healthy.
That's why I sent you the telegram.
Assholes! Don't do anything
to obtain the money from that insurance!
Any amount can help me
to compensate Elena's lost.
Ok! Good night!
Hello!
The plane takes off in half an hour,
you have 15 minutes to arrive.
At your service.
707.
Raquel...
...I have to explain you something.
If you prefer not to do it,
I'll understand it.
On the contrary...
...now it's better than ever.
Both of us need this confession.
A confession?
I thought everything was clear
between us.
I told you everything on time.
I don't want to go back.
Listen to me.
This is the end.
We can't keep on with this.
I've tried to kill you and...
...I can do it again.
I don't understand anything.
You are mad!
What's going on?
I have to tell you everything.
You are very proud because
you're telling me the truth.
Now you think you're so big.
You've always wanted to be like that.
Generous, honest, worthy, pure.
Why did you tell it to me?
Because you feel mercy for me
or for my rotten life?
Are you feeling mercy for you? Or is just
compassion for your own sufferings?
You've never thought
in anything else...
...just in yourself
and in your own salvation.
Your selfishness is wild and strong
because you hide it.
You want to purify your faults
through the others.
Yes, I can see everything.
You tried to kill me and why?
Because you love me
or your wife?
No. You don't love anybody.
You just love yourself...
...your moral and integrity.
Now you're defeated.
You can't kill anybody.
You can't kill me.
You lost your last weapon
when you confess.
It was the strength
that your silence gave you.
You understood everything.
Those are my own words.
I repeated them constantly,
day and night.
Let me get lost!
Don't make me take you to hell.
Why have you come? Why are you
looking at me that way? Go away!
Don't repeat insults
you will regret later.
Now it is my turn to speak.
I don't want to hear it.
Especially not from you.
Of course. It's like hearing
your own conscience.
But I don't want to make reproaches.
Did you forget I'm your friend
in spite of everything?
- What has happened with Antonio?
- I don't want to give explanations.
- I can handle it myself.
- It takes a stubborn person.
I just want to help you as if
nothing had happened. Speak!
You can imagine what happened.
He left you.
- I told you so.
- Unfortunately, you were right.
I was blinded by the idea
that he killed for me.
Explain yourself.
He killed her. But only due
to a fortunate mistake.
- He tried to kill me.
- That creep.
How did it happen?
Did he tell you?
He confessed it himself.
He was becoming very bitter.
Forget your sensitivity, try to
grasp what that confession means.
I don't understand.
You changed since you met him.
If he behaved poorly, why not pay
him back with his own medicine?
I mean charge him the harm
done in real, counting money.
After all, it would be a fair pay-back.
I won't use your methods.
Allow me to use mine.
Oh, yours. You are in no condition
of considering any methods.
You have behaved in a childish,
ridiculous way.
And I'm being kind with words.
I could use others.
You walked out on me in Panama
like I was disposable!
Now it turns that you won't take
advantage of a privileged situation.
Nobody said that.
But I claim my right
of doing it my way.
We would be in
unsurpassable circumstances...
...for the creation of a chemical
industrial subsidiary.
The advantages of this perspective
are obvious to anybody.
We'd have access to more raw
material than up to now.
Excuse me, Mr. ITUARTE. There's a lady
who wants to see you.
How you dare interrupt?
I'm sorry, but... she says
she is your fiancé.
Hello, darling.
I'm sorry, I had to see you.
I was at the insurance company.
There is an unacceptable clause.
The company reserves the right
to perform an autopsy on me...
...if it is deemed necessary
to pay in case I should die.
Isn't that hideous?
Or perhaps I misunderstood it?
Aren't you going to introduce me
to your friends?
Gentlemen...
Miss Raquel Serrano,
my fiancé.
Miss, at your service.
- Miss.
It is a pleasure. Forgive my intrusion.
Believe me, it was involuntary.
I was outraged.
I'll go now. You are all invited
to our wedding, of course.
Oh, certainly.
See you, Antonio.
I'll expect you for dinner.
Mr. Antonio in the name
of my associates...
...and mine,
our greatest congratulations.
And now, Mr. Villarreal
will read the project...
...presented by Mr. ITUARTE
in regard to the creation...
...of a mercantile corporation.subsidiary
of Industrial Chemical, Limited.
"Project for the creation
of a limited company...
...between Mr. Antonio ITUARTE,
Mr. Rafael..."
Autopsy!
Now she knows my secret,
she will use it to the end.
She will force me to marry her.
I am my wife's murderer.
To marry her! If they exhume
her body they will find evidence.
My wife's murderer.
There is no possible alternative.
Marry.
I declare in the name
of the law and society...
...that you are legally joined
in matrimony...
...with all the rights and prerogatives
granted by law...
...and the obligations it implies.
Why do all my orders
seem to upset you?
I obey them, madam.
Yes, but against your will.
Tell me what's wrong.
I'm listening.
I wish I had told you
before you asked.
You have tried to obliterate Miss
Elena's memory from this house.
She is only a shadow now,
but...
...it is stronger than you,
and will win in the end.
You mustn't forget it.
That is all.
Mrs. ITUARTE.
The perfect frame
for a work of art.
More than a goddess.
Now you can say
that you're at the peak.
Beauty, luxury, fortune.
What else can you ask of life?
That's what it comes
down to for you.
What else can it come down to?
I am acquainted with life.
Demetrio made a sculpture
of you. I made more.
I made a woman.
You are my best piece.
I sculpt living flesh.
But then...
...that's not what
I wanted to discuss with you.
Although I am very modest...
...even a man like myself
needs certain fees.
Could you provide me with, say,
one hundred thousand pesos?
That would solve everything,
including my silence.
Try to understand my position.
Mrs. ITUARTE has the word.
I am listening eagerly.
In that tone, Nacho. I don't know how
to explain, but things have changed.
- Oh, I can tell, I can tell.
- Ask me for anything but money.
I don't want to be a vulgar
crook in Antonio's eyes.
He would not understand.
I see you have changed,
and I congratulate you.
But although you consider your
husband's crime a declaration of love...
...for me it is still a blank check.
The facts are brutal, but...
...they are the facts.
I know your pride is hurt.
I've told you it isn't my fault.
If you want vengeance, go ahead.
I am determined to everything,
I have my own weapons.
All right.
- Is this your way of ending it?
- Yes, this is my way of ending it.
Speak Raquel, tell me everything.
Take me out of this horrible nightmare.
It was more than that, Antonio.
Worse than hell...
...was the risk of you
having a bad image of me.
But, when you went to say
goodbye to me...
...I realized in an instant
that you loved me.
That you had never
stopped loving me.
And giving up that wonderful
truth was impossible.
I was about to believe that you
would never utter these words.
It is clear that we are united
by something indestructible.
Something beyond ourselves.
We cannot turn back now, Raquel.
We shall go together to salvation
or to death.
I will help you dissipate
the shadows that bind you.
As terrible as our sin may be
we have a right to our piece of heaven.
Mr. and Mrs. Antonio ITUARTE.
Upon your arrival in New York
your funds will be available.
- Thank you, counselor.
- Have a good trip.
- Mr. Antonio ITUARTE?
- Yes.
You cannot leave the city,
there is a warrant.
How is that? I am his lawyer.
Please explain.
On grounds of murdering
his first wife.
That is insane! Calm down.
I will immediately apply
a recourse and post bail.
It's a maneuver based on interest.
It is not so easy to get rid of
a willing shadow.
- What did you say?
- Nothing. I was thinking of stalking you.
You may rest assured that everything
will be settled satisfactorily.
Nothing matters if we are together.
ANTONIO ITUARTE IS ACCUSED
OF MURDER
HE POISONED HIS FIRST WIFE
ANTONIO ITUARTE PRISONER
I swear he is innocent!
Can you give us objective
information on his behalf?
Material facts; no.
Like I can't prove that you
are a murderer either, Officer.
Antonio did not kill.
Nobody who truly loves
could be a criminal.
Your words couldn't be more touching
but they are completely worthless.
I ask you to strike her statement...
...due to lack of grounds,
from the offender's wife.
In any case, she could turn
out to be an accomplice...
...if I can prove it, as I hope I will.
I wouldn't care if I were.
He is innocent!
Based on the chargers, I ask
the body to be exhumed...
...and an autopsy to be performed.
TODAY WE WILL KNOW
THE RESULT OF THE AUTOPSY
This document ratifies
Dr. Vidaurri's certificate.
"The forensic doctors commissioned
by the District Attorney...
...render the following statement:
One:
No evidence at all was found
that Mrs. ITUARTE was poisoned.
Two:
Cardiac collateral
hypertrophy was found.
And three:
Mrs. Elena G. ITUARTE
died of a sudden rupture...
...of an aortic aneurysm."
In order to confirm the facts,
I'd like to call one last testimony.
Granted.
Although the doctor forbade it,
she joined the party downstairs.
When all the guests parted...
...except for Mrs. Raquel and
her companion; Mr. Antonio,...
...has been called by Dr. Vidaurri,
and my Miss Elena...
...in a sudden manner and
seemed to be very nervous.
Very nervous.
Your mission is over in this house.
You are dismissed.
Let us go, Demetrio!
Good night, madam.
It looked like she was
about to faint again.
As if she didn't have the
strength to hold on to it...
...the content of her glass
spilt on the carpet.
Esteban.
Call my husband.
I didn't have to call him,
he arrived at that moment.
Naturally, I retired
as not to be indiscreet.
Antonio!
You are free now, Antonio.
Faith in our love
has saved us.
The strength of our love
produced a miracle.
You didn't kill her,
Antonio, no.
She died her own death.
No shadow will ever come
between us. Never.
Nobody has been able
to untie us!
The night is gone forever,
Antonio.
Antonio!
The End