There's a big old nostalgia trip
under way.
NEIL: We don't know how Marie
was killed.
They never established
a cause of death.
But there's something, or someone,
that Drew and Izzy
aren't talking about.
DI McKinven's been given
the go-ahead
to reopen the investigation.
But while Kathy's working
on your mum's case,
you can't be employed by SIFA.
We hope to find further evidence.
The first dig was amateur.
How far do these go back?
Don't want nosy bastards
poking about in our paperwork.
Something about me threatens him.
I strongly believe he knew my mum.
What is your problem with my dad?
I don't want it. I'm not having it.
And I don't want you!
Well, I don't want you!
Did you see Phil at Tall Ships?
He was visiting his wife.
He wasn't with me.
Drew's a greedy wee bastard
who wouldn't let her out
of his clutches.
You're causing a lot of trouble.
We both know it can be very painful
raking up the past.
♪ Baby, you understand me now?
♪ Sometimes you see that I'm mad
♪ Don't you know that no-one alive
can always be an angel?
♪ When everything goes wrong
You feel so bad
♪ Oh, I'm just a soul
whose intentions are good
♪ Oh, lord, please don't let me
be misunderstood. ♪
How can I help?
I'm looking for Emma Hedges.
Just a moment.
KNOCK ON DOOR,
DOOR OPENS
Hello. Hi.
I'm looking for Emma Hedges.
She doesn't work here any more.
How come?
That's not something I can share.
Is she still in Dundee?
I don't know.
Well, is she back in Manchester?
Sorry, I don't know who you are.
Daniel MacAfee.
I'm Professor Gordon.
Could you possibly tell me
where she is?
No.
I need to get in touch with her.
Look, I know her, right?
Her aunt's called Julie.
Julie has insomnia.
The GC-MS machine's called Bobby.
You're all obsessed with cake.
If you've tried to contact Emma,
which I presume you have,
and she hasn't responded,
she doesn't want to be contacted
by you.
All right.
I actually really liked him.
Me too.
NEIL: We've reopened
the investigation
into the murder of Marie Monroe.
We have some new leads to pursue
and the investigation
is progressing.
I'm hopeful we'll be in a position
to finally bring to justice
the perpetrator of this
awful crime...
...and be able to give Marie's family
some peace of mind.
The police are ready to do a raid.
They think they've found
a clandestine drug lab.
If it is, they want me to go.
Fantastic.
I'm taking you with me.
Seriously? Of course.
It'd be great training.
Emma would love all this.
I know.
How are you, Dan?
Me? I'm OK. What's up?
Why do you need me
to turn the house upside down?
I told you,
it's to do with the court case.
Anything with Secrets nightclub
on it?
Yeah. It'll be summer 2008.
Aren't you curious?
I'd be curious.
About what?
Where I think your father might have been
the night DI McKinven was asking about.
Well, it sounds like you want to
tell me.
He'd have been with a woman.
When you had cancer? Yeah.
Or when I didn't.
How come you didn't kick him out?
Well, if you remember, I did.
It just took me ten years to do it.
I take it you're not interested
in Secrets before it was Secrets?
Why?
There's one here for Tempo Tyres,
which is what Secrets used to be.
Can I take all this away with me?
Is there something
you don't want me to see?
No, I just want to file it properly.
The first investigation
didn't record anything
about the spoil heap,
so we can't say whose spoil heap
we've found.
Ah, the person that dumped the body,
or the people that dug it up.
Well, that's a blow.
Yeah, but this isn't.
We thought we were
at the base of the grave,
because it's compacted,
but it's like a false floor.
There's a pocket of undisturbed soil
below it.
It looks like the first dig
didn't go deep enough.
So, you're getting to the soil
the first investigation
never searched?
That's the plan.
Where'd you get this?
The garage at Mum's.
It's the invoice for the supplies
when we did the refurb at Secrets.
I can see what it is, son. OK.
Plasterboard, cheaper than
half-inch, which is standard.
Half-inch board skimmed with plaster
gives you a half-hour fire rating.
This one doesn't.
I know that now.
And I didn't know that then.
Check out these doors.
These would have burnt in no time.
I mean, it makes me sick
when I see what an idiot I was.
Try not to be too hard on yourself.
Well, it's pretty disgraceful.
But you must have thought
this stuff was fit for purpose, too?
You signed off on it, Dad.
Of course I did.
I was a director.
You sign things in your sleep.
And you checked the work.
And do you think you pointed out
to me
how you left a gaping void
above the false ceilings?
Or do you think you just wanted
to impress me with how you'd come in
on budget and done it on time?
Of course I wanted to impress you.
You keep saying that,
for the purposes of the court,
we did nothing wrong.
I want to know, for the purposes
of you and me,
if you really think
we did nothing wrong.
I think you did a crappy piece of
work, and I was too busy to notice.
Right.
Cos you'd never do a crappy piece
of work.
Look, when Shuggie turned
his tyre place into Secrets,
he did it by the book.
He'd got everything signed off
with an unfinished area.
Then he got us in to do the refurb,
after the fact,
on the cheap.
Did Shuggie know we used
poor-quality materials
in those rooms?
Of course he did.
No doubt about it.
What else have you got up
your sleeve?
Were you unfaithful to Mum
when she had cancer?
Is that what this is about?
It's one of the things.
You need to make your mind up
what we're talking about here.
Cos if you're just out
to have a go at me in general,
you can get to fuck.
In fact, it's the same thing.
Which is what? You...
...getting away with it.
You talk to me about getting away
with it?
You're the fucking little prince
of getting away with it.
You never had the builder's eye.
Ever.
Not got it in you.
Your job comes from me.
Your car comes from me.
Your apartment comes from me.
You're a spoilt wee bastard
with no talent.
I'm smarter than you are, Daniel.
So, if you're going to take me on,
the thing to remember is...
...I'll win.
I wouldn't bank on it, Dad.
Clasp your hands behind your back
so you're not tempted to touch anything.
Just look.
LOUISE: God, they're all there.
Every single one.
I wish Emma was here to see this.
This is the original grave.
You can see by the marks
it was dug with a pickaxe
and a spade.
Someone did a good job.
Yeah. 11? 12?
A rib.
Come on, Marie.
Oh, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You can't see it?
No.
It's a boot print.
Let's check shoe sizes.
Vincent, Izzy, Drew, Phil, Jimmy.
TAPPING AND SHAKING
Kathy, come here.
Hello, little hyoid bone.
They never had a cause of death.
Maybe now we do.
CLATTERING
PHONE RINGS
Hello?
SKYE: Emma, sorry, I need to speak
to you.
My mum's terrible.
She's stable now,
but the doctors have told her
to get her affairs in order.
No.
I'm phoning you to eat humble pie.
She wants to talk
to the two of us together.
She says she needs
to make her peace.
Will you come?
So, is Daniel MacAfee
your boyfriend?
Not any more. Good.
I nearly died when that bastard
told me about the two of you.
He thinks I set you up.
Which bastard?
Phil MacAfee.
How'd you know Phil MacAfee?
Who's Phil MacAfee?
Daniel's dad.
Did he know my mum?
Yes.
Your mum was cheating on Jimmy
with Drew.
Phil was cheating on his wife
with me.
Well, we all liked to party.
Emma, this is news to me.
IZZY SIGHS
How much do you remember
about Tall Ships?
I remember us dancing.
I remember Mum in her pink dress.
Pink dress.
That's right.
And I remember wanting to stay
with Mum
and being annoyed
I had to go home with Jimmy.
Aye. I remember wanting you to stay
so we could go on the teacups.
We went on those teacups
after you'd gone.
Marie thought
she'd had too much to drink,
so she said she'd meet us after.
And she never did.
She texted me - she was going home.
And the next day,
Jimmy reported her missing,
and we all got jumpy.
Why?
We didn't want anyone else
finding out what we were up to,
and we knew it was nothing
to do with Marie going missing.
So, we dropped each other
like stones.
Was Phil at Tall Ships?
No.
He was with his wife.
Hospital.
You should have told someone
that he knew my mum 18 years ago.
I should.
After they found your mum's body,
I went really wrong.
How do you mean?
I started using heroin.
Skye was taken away from me
for a while.
Mum... you've been a brilliant mum.
I haven't been addicted to anything
in over ten years.
But, see, the stigma, it never goes.
You will be judged.
You will not be trusted.
What about my dad?
Drew did what Phil told him.
He dropped me like a stone.
I had no-one.
So I never said
what I should have said.
Phil MacAfee knew who did it.
I used to bother Phil for money
sometimes when I was in a bad way.
He called me the sheep tick.
I was on a loop about Marie once,
and he says to me,
"If you don't shut up about Marie,
"you'll end up cut up
just like she was."
He says, "I know the guy who did it,
and he will do the same to you, too."
Phil MacAfee kept me scared
for 18 years,
and now he's threatening you two.
Did he kill my mum?
All I can tell you is
when... when Marie went missing
and we were all getting jumpy
about the police,
it was Phil who insisted
the three of us drop each other.
It was Phil who insisted
we destroy the phones.
What phones?
Phil got them for us.
One for each of us.
Then, if we wanted fixing between
each other, we used those phones.
When she went missing...
...Phil said,
"Get rid of the naughty phones,"
cos that's what we called them.
What happened to them?
I melted mine in the microwave.
Drew threw his off the rig.
Did you keep your naughty phone?
STAMMERS: Get in.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about cheap phones
Phil MacAfee bought you, Izzy and my
mum so you could get up to stuff.
I...
Look at your face.
You know what I'm talking about!
OK, OK, I do, but I don't have it.
I think I've seen it.
I think it's in that suitcase
in there.
It's not.
Emma, leave it.
Get off me!
Leave it alone!
DREW GRUNTS
Phil told Izzy
he knew who killed Mum.
Izzy never said as much to me.
How could she, when you dropped her
like a stone?
Phil told her he knew who did it,
and that the same thing
would happen to her
if she didn't shut
up, so she shut up.
Do you know what Izzy's
been through?
Well, you left her to it, because
a man you barely knew told you to.
Why did you keep it?
It's a perfectly good phone.
You're a liar, Dad.
And you should've stuck by Izzy.
Even if Phil did know
who killed Marie,
even if,
that phone won't prove it.
It'll just prove
that four people were feckless,
which we were,
and took drugs, which we did.
It'll prove the link between
the four of you, and that's a start.
You've got to take this
to DI McKinven.
I don't even know what's on there.
No clue where the charger is.
Look, Phil MacAfee always had cash,
so he funded me.
I bought drugs and I sold them on.
Can I just tell you something?
My girlfriend's having a baby.
I'd like to be around.
Hm. I'll take that into
consideration.
Thank you.
OK.
What was the relationship
between Marie and Phil MacAfee?
What? I didn't even think
there was one.
There was no sign.
Mind you, there wouldn't have been -
they wouldn't have wanted Izzy to know.
Did you ever hear Phil say
he knew who killed Marie?
Never.
Why'd you keep the phone?
Don't know.
Phil rang me, "Ditch the phone.
"Chuck it in the sea."
Were you suspicious?
No.
Phil was visiting his wife,
Izzy had Skye, I was on the rig,
Jimmy had the kids.
We knew it wasn't any of us.
How'd you know
Phil was visiting his wife?
Because he texted Izzy on her,
you know,
her, you know, one of them.
Why did you keep yours?
I don't like being told what to do.
Well, when...
Maybe...
...some part of me
I didn't listen to...
...knew I was being played.
Pretty bad, when you think about it.
When we first spoke,
you mentioned that Marie had trouble
reaching orgasm.
That there was a trick to it.
Aye.
What was the trick?
Bit to the left.
Take it slow.
Was she into rough sex at all?
No.
God, no.
The opposite.
DISTANT SIRENS
Hello, Phil.
Hello. How's it going?
Fine.
That looks like a nice coffee.
You were asked to keep away from me,
darling.
It was the other way around,
actually.
Sorry to interrupt your coffee.
I just wanted to ask you something,
if that's OK.
Is that OK?
Sure.
Did you kill my mum?
HE SIGHS
I don't care what the police say.
I think you did.
You're not well.
I'm fine.
She's not well.
See you later.
I want my name left off the
indictment for culpable homicide.
I'm prepared to give evidence
against my father to do it.
What's your evidence?
Well, I can prove
how he ran the business.
I can show I did the same,
just imitated him, basically.
But I can prove how,
since I've been running it on my own
and learned from different people,
that I've got better.
Much better.
OK.
This is the invoice for
the materials we used at Secrets.
This is a fake one my dad cooked up.
Lied about the materials
we used to bump up the profit.
Shuggie Brook thought
he had fire doors.
My dad conned him.
This shows intent to deceive.
Does your dad know you've got this?
No.
Do you want me
to pass this to the prosecutors?
What would happen?
Your father will be the only
accused,
and you will be a witness
against him.
This is going to be
a huge problem for him.
I wouldn't like to be defending him.
Do you want to think about it?
No.
Pass 'em to the prosecutors.
KATHY: These are Marie Monroe's
exhumed remains from the cemetery.
Several bones are missing.
And here are the bones
we recovered from the dump site.
This is how she was dismembered.
The striation pattern
on the edges of the cut bone
indicate a saw was used.
The nick marks are knife cuts.
The flesh was cut with a knife.
The bone - with a saw.
Imagine doing it.
You already had the trauma
of killing someone.
Now you've gotta get rid of a body.
Maybe rigor mortis set in.
You don't know it'll go away again,
so you cut 'em up. It's traumatic.
It's a double trauma.
The hyoid bone.
When you squeeze someone
by the neck,
the greater horns can displace
inwards and break.
This was still wet and bendy
when it broke.
So, it happened before she was dead.
There she is.
Marie.
PHONE BUZZES
Hello?
I've nearly rung you so many times.
So, Janine said,
"The principal wants to see you,"
and I thought, "Oh, what now?"
So, I trotted along,
and the principal says,
"Do you know you've been nominated
for a police commendation
"for tracing the supply of killer
drugs back to the factory?
"I suppose I'd better stump up
and give you your own lab."
- No.
- Yeah.
Photos from the scene
have been sent to the international
drug investigation database,
and this is all the result of you
spotting that unknown, so check you.
Must be hard... with your mum's
investigation going on.
Yeah, it has been hard.
Feeling kept out of things.
Daniel MacAfee came into SIFA.
What did he say?
He said he needed
to get in touch with you.
SUPERINTENDENT: Look, it's clear
there's been sterling work
on retrieving and reassembling
these remains.
The hyoid bone
was a significant find.
Thank you.
But you haven't linked anyone
to these remains or productions.
You've got a size ten boot print.
Three of the people you're looking
at are size ten. I'm size ten.
Not one DNA match out of your
five persons of interest.
Nothing gained from your positional
with Vincent Keir.
Nothing solid on Jimmy Levin.
And you still haven't spoken
to MacAfee.
As I said, boss, I don't want him
to know we're interested in him.
We are!
Circumstantial evidence
coming out of your ears,
but nothing that would stand up
in court.
And to add insult to injury,
your statement to the press
effectively guaranteed
tying the whole thing up
by the end of the week.
Sorry I'm late. It's fine.
Do you want to get a coffee?
No.
Do you want to walk?
Yeah.
What did you want?
I wanted to ask you about my father.
What about him?
What you think he did.
So you can tell him?
I'm not speaking to him.
I don't know if I can trust you.
I'm not my dad.
I can see him now.
We're not going to be possible
if I tell you.
I know that.
But we're not very possible now,
are we?
No, but we were.
I know.
We were.
We really were. I've never felt...
Me neither.
I'm ready.
Your dad and Izzy had a thing.
2001? Yeah.
Your dad and Izzy and my mum
and Drew all hung out together.
DI McKinven's got proof.
Was my dad at Tall Ships?
He told Izzy
that he was with your mum.
He wasn't.
Hey, he's right.
Eh...
He's a fucking bastard for doing it
in front of everybody,
but... we haven't got the evidence.
All that work... and hope...
...and the money.
"Whit's fur ye'll no go by ye."
Do you think that's true?
I think... I think it's true.
PHONE RINGS
Excuse me.
Oh.
Daniel? What can I do for you?
My dad did work on Secrets
when it was a tyre place.
Bought bags of cement and six
bollards,
fitted them in the car park.
August 14th, 2001.
Two days after Tall Ships.
I don't know what any of it means.
All right.
I appreciate you letting me know,
but would you be willing
to put that down in statement form?
Yeah.
DRILLING
Philip MacAfee,
I'm arresting you under Section One
of the Criminal Justice
(Scotland) Act 2016
for the abduction and murder
of Marie Monroe in 2001.
You've got the wrong guy, pal.
Were you at the Tall Ships Festival
at Dundee City Quay,
Sunday, August 12th, 2001?
No comment.
Did you arrange
to meet Marie Monroe there,
or anywhere else, that evening?
No comment.
Your wife's diary states
that you weren't with her
and that your son Daniel
was staying with his grandmother.
Could you tell us where you were?
SOLICITOR CLEARS THROAT
I made it clear my client would be
giving a "no comment" interview.
I remember.
Drew Cubbin gave this phone to us.
Do you recognise this phone?
It's 18 years old.
It's a pay-as-you-go.
Our Digital Investigation Unit
was able to retrieve data from it.
Texts from you to Drew Cubbin.
From Izzy Alessi to Drew Cubbin.
From Marie Monroe to Drew Cubbin.
Making arrangements.
Arrangements to meet.
Arrangements to buy drugs.
Would you like to say
anything about that?
They were able to retrieve
a few voicemail messages, too.
BEEP
MARIE: Oh, hi, darling.
Can you meet me at Izzy's tomorrow
at two? We won't have long.
Izzy can fetch the girls from school,
but I'll need to get
them back over at four
cos Phil's going over,
and he'll want Iz to himself.
Hey! Ring me, you bastard.
I'm bored. And lonely.
And horny.
MARIE LAUGHS
BEEP
Do you recognise that voice?
It's Marie Monroe.
Drew Cubbin confirms
that he and Marie
would sometimes meet
for sex at Izzy's.
We retrieved the headboard from
a bed that Izzy had at the time.
Do you recognise that bed?
Traces of semen on it
match your DNA profile.
How do you explain that?
Do you recognise these, Mr MacAfee?
These boots were recovered
from the Secrets car park in Lochee,
under one of the bollards
you installed, August 14th, 2001.
Those dark stains are blood.
The blood matches
the DNA profile of Marie Monroe.
We were also able to extract
a DNA profile from inside the boots.
It matches yours.
A boot print in the soil
at the dump site
is a match with the sole
of these boots.
Can you explain why your boot
has Marie Monroe's blood on it...
...and left a print
where her remains were dumped?
We know Marie was wearing a pink
dress on the day she went missing.
Do you remember that dress at all?
Marie's movements are unknown
after she left Izzy Alessi
at Tall Ships at 8.20pm.
We believe she may have met someone
and been driven somewhere,
as no-one saw her walking home,
which is what she told Izzy
she was going to do.
Do you have any idea
where Marie Monroe
might have been that night?
Or what she might have been doing?
Or who she might have been
doing it with?
You don't treat Izzy right.
Cut it out.
Marie's remains were recovered
three months
after she was last seen alive.
We can't be precise
about the circumstances
surrounding her death.
But we do know some things.
Her hyoid bone was broken.
The break is consistent
with Marie having been throttled.
We're thinking this is the most
likely cause of death.
After she was killed,
her body was dismembered.
Whoever did it
cut through the flesh of her legs
and arms with a knife.
Cut through the bones with a saw.
It's clear from the direction
of the cuts
Marie's body was on its front
when they did that.
Perhaps they didn't want to look
at her face when they did it,
so they rolled her over.
Do you have any opinion about that?
PHONE RINGS
Hello?
It's Neil. Can you talk?
Yeah.
Phil MacAfee's been charged.
We charged him with murder,
abduction, assault,
dismemberment,
concealment of a body,
attempt to pervert the course
of justice.
We've thrown the book at him.
He is one of the most cold
and calculated bastards
I've ever dealt with.
Are you there?
Yeah.
I just need to let it sink in.
I'll call you back.
Bye. OK, all right.
Well, who needs a confession
when you've got forensic evidence
as brilliant as that? Yes!
Sorry we're late.
The Super wanted to buy us a drink.
Right, come on.
Well, what is everybody having?
Trina's buying.
Oh! I have to get back to my dogs.
But you wanna join us?
You wanna come get drunk
in the country?
Oh, sounds fun.
What do you reckon, boss?
Ah, thanks for asking, Kathy,
but I'll get drunk in town.
Trina, you get drunk wherever
you like, of course.
I'll get drunk with you, boss.
Thank you, though.
Have you spoken to Emma?
Yeah. Yeah. We're going to drop in
on her just now.
The reason I'm not coming back
to Kathy's is...
...I would say something foolish.
I would love that.
SOFTLY: Emma.
I missed you.
CHURCH BELL TOLLS
MINISTER: Welcome, everyone.
We are gathered here to celebrate
the life of Marie Monroe.
DANIEL ON VOICEMAIL:
Emma, I've decided not to come.
It meant a lot you wanted me there,
but I doubt the others
will feel the same.
I'm leaving Dundee.
My flat's up for sale.
I want to give wherever I get
to the Nardonis and the Kumars.
I'm so sorry
I won't see you before I go.