[Birds chirp]
[Spanish acoustic guitar music]
♪ ♪
[Horse whinnies]
- [Grunts]
- All right.
Okay.
- The green down there
about 400 yards on the right,
and we will have
a perfect par four.
- It's a wonderful dream, Cal.
- Good, 'cause I'm in
the making-dreams-come-true
business.
- [Laughs]
[Horse whinnies]
- Speaking of
making dreams come true.
Hey, come say hello to Cal,
baby!
- Hello!
Kids are waiting. I'll see you
at the party, Cal.
- [Laughs]
- [Sighs]
[Horse whinnies]
- How are you?
- [Speaks Spanish]
- Great ride.
Gracias, Gustavo.
- De nada.
- No, you didn't watch it.
- [Laughing] That's all right,
sweetheart, that was a good try.
That was a good try.
Diego's right, sweetheart,
keep your eye on the ball.
Don't... don't look up. All right,
we'll put it over here.
You and me.
Oh, let's get it out there
a little bit more. All right?
All right, here we go.
- [Sings]
- Keep your eye on the ball.
Both: One, two,
three!
- That's it! That's it.
That's it.
Now, come and try again.
- Hi, senoritas,
como es todo?
[Speaking Spanish]
- Daddy!
- Hi!
[Growls]
- Daddy!
- Who's your papi?
- [Squeals]
- [Laughing] Oh.
- All right, let's see,
let's see.
[Laughter]
No, no, no,
hang on, hang on.
[Laughter]
- Oh!
[Mexican music]
♪ ♪
- Would you mind zipping me up
the rest of the way, honey?
Please.
Thank you.
- Something is not right.
- What's not right?
- I think
something's missing.
Something's missing?
What...
- Well, what if...
Let's see.
- [Sighing] Oh.
- How 'bout that?
- [Gasps]
It's beautiful.
- It's better, no?
[Chuckles]
- Mm.
- Happy anniversary, carina.
- Thank you.
Both: Mmm.
- You like?
- I like.
Both: "Happy anniversary to our
mom and dad.
"They're so cool,
"they really rock.
[Laughter]
"They're nice,
even when we're bad.
"Thank you for this party.
It's really, really fun.
"Thanks for being
our mom and dad.
God bless us, everyone."
All: Aw!
- Okay,
that is gonna inspire me.
- Oh, Eduardo!
- Whoo! Here, here!
- Hear, hear.
- All of us
dream of finding true love.
And for anyone who knows me
here, they will tell you,
the day that I met jayne,
I found mine.
Today we celebrate
our marriage
and the very clever children
it has produced, huh?
[Laughter]
But I celebrate my marriage
every day,
'cause it is my everything.
You are my everything.
Happy anniversary,
my one true love.
- [Whispering]
Happy anniversary.
All: Aw!
- I love you.
[Applause and chatter]
- Mmm.
- When I met and married Eduardo
15 years ago,
I moved here from Maryland,
I knew exactly
what I was getting.
I was getting the most
wonderful man in the world,
but that's not all I got.
I got a new home,
new friends,
and a new family.
Thank you all so very much
for celebrating with Eduardo,
and our two beautiful kids,
and myself tonight.
Thank you so much.
- Yay!
- Cheers!
[General agreement and laughter]
- This is
a beautiful ranch.
- You're looking at
15 years of sweat equity.
It was in a shambles
when we got it.
- Oh, really?
I would have thought that...
- Oh, because Eduardo is a
valseca, that we would be rich?
- Well,
his father was legendary.
The William Randolph hearst
of Mexico, I've been told.
- Absolutely, yes.
Eduardo makes a modest income
from the estate,
but we bought this place
at auction.
At the time,
on one wanted it.
- Smart investment.
- Very much so.
- We'll see if we can make it
pay up.
- [Laughing] Oh, it has,
in all the ways
that matter.
It's mariachi time.
Are you ready?
[Laughs]
- Um, after this.
- [Singing in Spanish]
♪ ♪
[Laughter]
[Singing in Spanish]
♪ ♪
[Crowd laughs and calls out]
[Cheering and applause]
[Indistinct chatter]
- [Whispering]
Thank you for everything.
- [Whispering] You're welcome.
- Good night.
- Kids are asleep.
Do you mind a little unzip,
please?
- Not at all.
- [Kisses]
- Senor valseca,
you know,
I am feeling very, very lucky.
- Really?
- Yes, I am.
- [Sighs]
[Sighing and kissing]
- Oh.
- Good morning, daddy.
- Morning, dad.
- Morning.
Ooh,
banana pancakes!
Mmm.
Be still, my beating heart.
- [Laughing] Mm-hmm.
Just for you,
my love.
Sit and eat.
- Mmm.
- [Sighs]
Okay, kids,
it's time to go.
Here is your homework.
It's late.
- Oh, you know what?
- Let's go, you guys are late.
- Sit, eat.
Luiz and I will
take the kids to school today.
- Yeah, no problem.
- No, no, no, no,
breakfast can wait.
- Come on, get your plates,
please. No, no, no,
get your plates, please.
- Mm.
- Clear your plates.
- Andale, andale,
let's go.
- Maria.
- Thank you.
Mmm!
- I'll see you later.
- Diego.
- What time is
your football game at?
- Saturday...
- Saturday at 11:00?
You have to be there
at 11:00,
or you have to be there
at 10:30,
'cause the game starts
at 11:00?
- Can I play football?
- Yes, sweetheart,
you may play football.
- You can't...
You have to get the shoulder
pads, and the helmet.
It's too much money.
- [Laughing] Oh, stop.
- I think it's too much.
- What's that Van doing
parked right there?
That's not a very good place
for it to...
It's a dangerous place
for it to park.
♪ We're going to school,
and we are gonna like it ♪
♪ we're going to school,
we're going to school ♪
♪ now get out really fast ♪
All right, guys,
be back here at 3:00.
Diego, 3:00 means 3:00.
- [Speaking Spanish] Be good.
Behave.
- So fun last night.
- Thank you.
Bye, love you.
Have a good day at school.
- I, uh, didn't get the memo
about casual day.
[Laughs]
- Oh, my gosh!
I'll be back, I'll be back.
Eduardo hasn't had
his banana pancakes yet.
- Oh you spoil that man,
you know?
- Only because he spoils me.
- Buenos dias.
You ready for class?
You do your homework?
Good to see you.
You get your homework done?
- Let's hurry back,
I can't believe I walked away
from your pancakes.
I want to get orange juice...
What do we have
to do today?
- Yeah, but should I
make some more?
I mean, those pancakes...
That's that car
from the school.
What's he doing up there?
- I don't know,
but he better be careful.
That road is in terrible shape.
[Tires screech]
- Eduardo!
What's he doing?
Honey?
[Honks horn]
Honey, please don't do that.
- I...
[Honks horn]
- Honey, please.
- Excuse me!
Por favor!
- Honey!
That car's coming up
very fast.
[Crash]
Oh!
What's going on?
- Oh!
- Oh, no.
[Tires screech]
- They're coming to the car.
[Yelling in Spanish]
- [Yells in Spanish]
- No! No!
[Yelling in Spanish]
Eduardo!
No!
- Jayne!
- [Yelling in Spanish]
- Ugh!
- Jayne!
[Yells in Spanish]
[Struggles]
Ah!
No!
[Car horn beeps]
[Struggling and yelling]
- No!
[Crying]
- [Yelling in Spanish]
- Oh!
Oh!
- Vamanos!
[Van starts]
- [Gasps]
[Whimpers]
No!
- No!
- [Cries] Oh, my god!
- No, no, don't hurt me.
Please!
- Honey, be still,
sweetheart.
- No.
- Honey, just be still.
Honey, be still.
- Shut up!
- Shh.
- [Whimpers]
- No!
- Eduardo, stay calm.
[Gasps]
It's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay, honey.
- Be still.
- [Crying] We have children.
Do you have children?
- Shut up!
- [Whimpers]
Oh.
- Don't move.
Don't make a sound,
or we will kill you,
your husband, and your children.
- Pronto!
[Whimpers]
- [Yells in Spanish]
Vamanos!
- [Yelling in Spanish]
[Car starts]
[Car drives away]
- [Pants]
[Gasps and struggles]
[Sobs]
[Struggles]
[Cries]
Help me.
[Screaming] Help me!
Help me!
[Sobs]
[Screaming]
Help me!
- Do you have a cell phone?
My husband's...
No?
Does anybody have a cell phone?
Someone must
have a cell phone.
My husband has been kidnapped,
and I have to call the...
Oh, god, thank you.
[Sobs]
Yes,
my name is jayne valseca.
My husband
has been kidnapped.
[Police siren]
[Tires screech]
[Police intercom chatter]
[Police siren]
- Wait here, senora.
- They... they abandoned
their vehicles
on the road from the school
with our car, um...
You should send someone
to identify them.
- The vehicles
were probably stolen.
- Oh, my god.
They left the keys.
I could have followed them,
I could have stopped them.
They left the keys.
No, senora,
they would have killed you both.
Senorajayne?
- Yes.
[Whispering]
Oh, my god.
They spelled my name right.
They spelled it
with a "y".
No one spells it with a "y".
This was not random.
They know exactly who we are.
They know exactly
who we are.
- Oh!
[Whimpers]
[Metal detector hums]
- Oh!
Oh! Oh!
Ah!
Mm.
[Grunts]
What? No.
No! No!
[Pants and whimpers]
Oh, no!
No!
[Grunts]
No.
Oh.
[Groans]
Ah!
[Breathes hard]
[Door latches]
[Grunts]
[Whimpers]
[Breathes hard]
- [Indistinct]
[Chatter in Spanish]
- No, senorita, [speaks Spanish]
- Mom, um, yes, I, uh,
I have something to tell you,
and, um...
It's not good.
No, I'm fine,
I... I'm okay, I'm okay.
And the kids are okay, it's, uh,
it's just... it's Eduardo.
He, uh...
Uh,
he's been kidnapped, mom.
I don't...
We don't know why.
The kidnappers said
that they would, um,
they would contact me via email,
and they ha...
No, I don't want you
to come down here.
I need you to stay there.
I have a very good
support system, Olivia is here,
and, luiz, and Gustavo,
and it's...
I just need you to stay there,
and...
And hopefully this will be just,
ver...
Taken care of quickly.
I have to, uh, go,
because the police are here,
and I need...
I absolutely will, mom.
I... I love you, and I will...
I will contact you, okay?
- Senora,
I need you to sign this.
- All right.
What is this?
- It authorizes us
to investigate
and negotiate
on your behalf.
- Okay, you've um, you've
handled kidnappings before, yes?
- Yes.
Quite a few.
- And you've always
gotten hostages back.
- Every time.
- Good.
Did you I.D. The cars,
the vehicles?
- As I said before, senora,
they were probably stolen.
- Okay, how can you know
that they're stolen
if you haven't I.D.'Ed them,
and-
and have you blocked the roads
to Santa Natalia?
- I assure you, senora, we are
doing everything that we can.
- [Stuttering]
Excuse me for one minute.
[Speaks Spanish]
- All the gates are locked.
The media's gathering.
- I don't want to
talk to the media,
'cause they're just gonna
turn this into a circus.
Look, the local police,
they, uh,
they want to handle
the negotiations.
- Are they qualified?
- I've never heard of anyone
being kidnapped
in or around Santa Natalia.
- Neither have I,
and I gotta be honest,
I don't know
if I trust them.
- Aren't there people
who do this? Specialists?
- Yes, absolutely.
Eduardo had a friend,
Jorge,
who had a business partner
kidnapped a few years ago,
and they had a private firm
bring him back.
- Do you know
how to reach 'em?
- No,
but Eduardo will know how.
In his, uh... in his contact list,
I'm sure I'll find it.
Okay?
[Whispering] I'm gonna go find
that, I'll be right back, okay?
- Okay.
[Phone rings]
- Hello?
- Yes,
this is senorseptien.
- Hi, this is jayne valseca,
I'm from Santa Natalia.
I got your name from, uh,
Jorge ramos.
- I see.
How can I help you?
- My...
My husband was...
Was kidnapped this morning.
Uh, about three hours ago.
- [On phone]
I'm very sorry to hear that.
- I need to retain someone
to help negotiate his release.
- Of course, did senor ramos
advise you of our fee schedule?
- Yes, um, 2,500 a day,
plus expenses.
- Valseca.
Publishing valsecas?
- Yes, that's...
That's right.
- Which is why
they targeted you, no doubt.
- But that's crazy,
because we're not rich.
- Oh. Uh, have the kidnappers
made their demand?
- Not yet. I'm... I'm still
waiting for an email from them.
- Please,
tell me what happened.
- Um,
well, there were four men
in three vehicles.
We had just dropped
our children off at school.
- Excuse me, you were with your
husband when he was kidnapped?
- Yes.
- But the kidnappers
didn't harm you.
- No.
- How do you know
they will email you?
- Uh, they left a note for me
before they drove...
Drove off with him.
- Did they leave
anything else?
- Uh, no, I don't...
Uh, yes.
[Stutters] There was a... a...
A hammer in the front seat.
A new one, uh,
the price tag was still on it.
- I'm afraid
we can't help you.
- Uh, I'm sorry,
are... are you not available?
- I recommend you contact afi.
- Afi. The federal police.
I... why can't you handle this?
- Afi will explain it to you.
- [Sighs] But...
- You know anyone
in Mexico City?
- My husband's...
My husband has family there.
- Have one of them
go down to afi headquarters,
fill out the proper paperwork.
- To fill out forms?
Okay, but...
- It's almost noon.
I suggest
that you act quickly.
Best of luck.
[Phone beeps]
- [Sighs]
- Uh, he wasn't interested,
I guess.
- Why not?
- I don't know.
- What was he saying
about afi?
- That we should have them
secure Eduardo's release.
- Federales?
- Wha...
- Someone in Mexico City
has got to
go to their offices
and [laughing] fill out forms.
- Carlos is probably home,
let me call him.
- Okay.
- Is that the kidnappers,
did they contact you?
- No, Olivia,
they're going to send an email.
- Oh. Yeah, right
[phone rings]
- Um, I'll get it.
Hello?
- Carlos, hi.
It's your sister.
Something bad has happened
to uncle Eduardo.
We need your help.
Talk to jayne,
she'll explain.
- [Weeps]
Jayne.
[Cries]
- Eduardo never
registered these guns
that he inherited
from his father.
The federal police
are coming...
- Senora, we can store them
in one of the upstairs closets.
- Okay.
Gustavo, what do you know
about kidnappings?
- Not a whole lot,
really, uh,
just what I read in the
newspapers or I've seen on TV.
But from the ones
I've read about,
they usually demand
a few hundred thousand dollars.
- Well, we should be able to
manage that.
- That is awful, jayne.
I'm calling up
your accounts now.
- [On phone] Between
the checking account and the cd,
we should have about 500,000,
right?
- [On phone] Yeah,
a little more than that.
Just under 550,
almost all of it in the cd.
- Good. That's good.
- But you don't have
access to it.
- What do you mean?
- The account
is in Eduardo's name.
You're not a signatory.
- But I... I've...
I write checks on it
all the time.
- On your
checking account,
which Eduardo funds every month
from savings and income.
- So I... I'm sorry,
what are you saying?
Are you saying that I don't
have access to my own money?
- Legally it's not yours,
it's Eduardo's.
- But we're married, and if I
can't get access to that money...
- I understand.
Let me see
what I can work out.
In the meantime,
is there anything I can do now?
- No.
Thank you.
- Afi called. An agent
is on his way from Mexico City.
- Oh, okay.
That's good.
- He'll be here tonight.
- Great.
Carlos wants to know if there is
anything else he can do.
- Uh...
- Mama too.
- I don't think so.
You know, not until we know
what we're dealing with here.
- Mama said she'd contact
Eduardo's brothers and sisters
and let them know what happened.
- Yeah, that would be helpful.
Maybe she could act
as the point person.
You know, to...
For the extended family.
- I'm sure
she'd be happy to.
It's almost 2:30,
and school will be out soon.
- Yeah, I know.
- Why don't I pick them up?
- No, no, no. I, uh,
I always pick them up.
I want...
Them to have the same routine,
things to be normal,
especially now. [Sighs]
- Listen, um,
if things get crazy around here,
the kids can come
and stay with us.
- I appreciate that, Olivia,
just... I, uh,
I want to have them close
right now, I think.
- When is he coming back?
- Soon, honey, soon.
- I hate it when
daddy goes away on business.
- I do too, honey.
Why don't you go get your
soccer clothes on, Maria, okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
- Why are the TV trucks
outside the gate?
- Sit. Come sit down.
Sweetheart, please,
sit down, love. Sit down, honey.
- Something happened to dad,
didn't it?
You weren't at school today,
and teachers were whispering.
- Honey, um,
your dad, he, uh, he was kid...
He was kidnapped this morning.
- Is he dead?
- No.
God, no!
He is not.
Sweetheart, no.
- If they killed him,
I'll kill them.
- They're not gonna kill him,
honey.
They're not
gonna kill him.
- How do you know?
- Because I won't let them.
We won't let them.
All right?
- We have to find him.
We have to bring him back.
- We will.
We will, baby, I promise.
I promise you.
All right?
It's gonna be okay, baby.
It's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay,
sweetie.
[Mouse click]
- Jayne,
why are you still up?
- Oh, I can't sleep.
- Can I get you something?
- No, no, no,
that's all right, thank you.
Why are they making us wait?
I don't understand.
[Phone rings]
- Hello?
Yes, this is she.
Okay, um, someone will there
to pick you up right away.
Okay.
Uh, the afi agent is here.
He's at the business station.
- He came by bus?
- Apparently.
- I'll go get him.
- [Whispering]
Diego, sweetheart.
Honey,
why are you sleeping here?
- [Whispering] Keeping her safe
till dad comes back.
- Well, good.
That way, he won't have to
worry about her, right?
Sleep tight, baby,
I love you.
- I love you too.
- Okay.
- Senoravalseca.
- Yes, I'm jayne valseca.
- I'm Raul from afi.
I'm here to help you negotiate
your husband's release.
- I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Are you here alone?
- Please,
if we can talk inside?
It's late.
You're all in shock,
and I'm probably not
what you expected, I understand,
but I can assure you
that I am older than I look,
and I've been doing this
for a number of years.
- Okay, but, um,
we are in crisis situation here.
No offense,
you arrived by bus, and, uh,
if I may ask,
are you even armed?
- Senora,
I came like this for a reason.
If I had made
a more dramatic entrance,
unmarked SUV, federal plates,
lights flashing,
it might have made you
feel better about me,
but it could have
cost your husband his life,
and put you
and your children at risk.
There's a way
that these things work,
and I can explain everything
in the morning.
- In the morning?
No, no, no, we...
We have to act now.
This is...
- Have the kidnappers
contacted you?
- No, not yet,
they have not.
- No. I don't expect they will,
it's not their m.O.
- But they could
at any moment.
- I doubt they will
tonight.
They're probably sleeping,
which is what I recommend we do.
- [Sighs]
- But to be safe,
if you can give me
your user name and password
for your email account...
- And why?
- We'll be logged in
at headquarters.
We have sophisticated software
that can quickly identify
the isp addresses that
the kidnappers are sending from.
- You don't just have me
working on this with you,
but you have
all the resources of afi.
- [Moans]
[Keyboard clicks]
[Sighs]
- [Sighs]
[Sniffs]
Oh, jayne.
[Cries]
- There are many different types
of kidnappings in Mexico.
The most sensational
happen in the drug trade,
where the victims
are never seen alive again,
but the vast majority
are for money.
There are
express kidnappings
where prompt payment
guarantees expedited service,
but that's not
what we have here.
- How do you know?
- Because it was
meticulously executed
by a highly coordinated
group of men,
who made themselves
impossible to identify,
and they left behind
the hammer.
- What does
the hammer mean?
- It's the calling card for
the popular revolutionary army.
- The e.P.R.,
but that's a... that's
a political group, isn't it?
- And they don't negotiate
with private security firms
like senorseptien's,
which is why
he referred you to us.
- But what would a political
group want with Eduardo?
Why would they kidnap him,
it doesn't make any...
- To finance operations.
But that's the good news.
It's a business deal to them,
a negotiation.
They treat their victims
comparatively well,
and they never kill them.
But it's not all
good news.
The ransom will be high,
at least a million dollars.
- We don't have
that kind of money.
- Well, obviously,
they think you do.
Another thing you need to know
about e.P.R.,
which
you're obviously learning,
is that they move
at their own pace.
They control
the negotiations.
[Phone rings]
- Senora, forgive me
for being insensitive,
but I need to see
where you were attacked.
- Uh, they...
They, uh, they dragged
Eduardo from the car
to the Van that was
right in front, and...
I was over here, fighting them,
[Laughs] Which is insane,
I know, and I...
[Sighs]
Then I grabbed on to the wire
and this...
Then they pulled me into the Van
with Eduardo on this side,
and...
They put something over my head
so I couldn't see anything more.
Not here, anyway.
[Bar music and chatter]
[Keyboard clicks]
[Phone rings]
- Hello, luiz?
Okay,
we'll be right there.
It's the kidnappers,
they emailed.
- Yes, I know. I'm on my way
to the situation room.
[Overlapping chatter]
Uh-huh.
Yes. Okay.
Um, yes, that's it.
That's it.
We got it.
- Excellent.
They're tracing
the email now.
- Listen up, everyone.
- Eduardo valseca's kidnappers
just contacted his wife.
When we get a GPS read
on the location,
I want them to move.
Stay on this.
[Overlapping chatter]
[Email alert chime]
- In what American state
did jayne and Eduardo meet?
Oh, they know everything
about us.
[Sighs]
- "Senorajayne,
we hope you got home okay.
"In all future communications
we will write you by email,
"and you will
respond by placing ads
"in the newspapers
that we designate.
"Place the following
in the want ads section
"of noticias diarias
in the animals and pets section.
"Buy chow chow dog Austin,
vaccinated with
complete pedigree, 8,000 pesos."
That's it?
What...
What does this mean?
- It means
they're demanding
$8 million
for Eduardo's release.
- What?
[Gasps]
- It's a big number,
but the initial demand
always is.
Remember,
this is a negotiation.
- How can I
negotiate that?
And... and place ads
in newspapers?
Why can't I just
email them like this?
I don't understand.
- They know
we'll be tracing I.P. Addresses.
They'll use a different one
every time.
Open up anonymous accounts,
and then close it.
We'll trace all of them,
in case they slip up,
but they'll send them
from busy Internet cafes,
where there
are no surveillance cameras,
and the customers pay
with disposable cash cards.
- Well,
what does this mean,
"buy chow chow dog,
Austin,
vaccinated with"...
Austin.
Wait a minute.
Austin, the land deal,
Cal.
- Who is Cal?
- Cal wimberley.
He's a real estate developer
in Austin.
He's been talking
with Eduardo and me
about purchasing
part of our ranch
to build a golf course.
He hasn't made a formal offer,
but the number we've been
kicking around is 8 million.
Otherwise this land is just
a beautiful piece of property.
We can't even
borrow against it.
- Was this land deal
common knowledge?
- No, although Santa Natalia
is a very small community.
I'm sure
that some people must know.
- Well, that probably explains
the size of the demand.
- Maybe Cal
is willing to buy now.
- [Over speaker] Obviously,
I'll do everything I can
to help secure
Eduardo's release,
but you have to understand,
I don't have the money.
I'll need to secure a commitment
from my usual financing sources.
It'll take at least a few weeks,
maybe a month.
- A month?
- And there's
the same complication
as with the cd account.
The title to the land
is in Eduardo's name.
- But we can work around that,
can't we?
- Under the circumstances,
a judge might Grant jayne
power of attorney.
- Of course he will.
In the meantime,
I'll move this along
as fast as I can, jayne.
I promise.
- Okay,
thank you very much, Cal.
Probably at least a month.
- Even if you get
the 8 million,
it wouldn't be smart
to offer it to the kidnappers.
- So how should I respond
to the ad?
- Let them know that you're
concerned about senorvalseca,
and doing everything you can
to secure his release.
- Concerned?
I'm goin' out of my mind.
- Hola, senora.
- I have to tell Maria
what's happening.
Why don't you draft a response
that you think is appropriate.
- Okay.
- You can do that?
Take people for money?
- These are very, very
bad people, sweetheart.
- Was one... was that man in the
car with you one of the bad men?
- No, no, no. He's, uh,
he's trying to protect us.
His name is Raul.
- I want daddy back.
- I know you do, sweetheart.
We all do.
"Looking to buy
Austin chow chow puppy.
"Vaccinated
with complete pedigree.
"The funds required
not presently in hand,
working to acquire same."
Yes, and that's
in tomorrow's edition?
The animal and pets section?
Yes?
Okay,
thank you very much.
[Phone beep]
Okay, now what?
- If e.P.R. Is true to form,
it won't be good.
[Metal doors open]
[Struggles]
- Oof!
[Groans]
[Coughs]
Oh!
[Gasps]
Okay.
- "Must move, urgently.
Or they will kill me."
Keep writing!
- "You must move urgently,
or they will kill me, jayne.
"Don't tell them
the funds are not in hand,
"we have the money,
you know we do.
"Why are you
lying to them?
"Have you abandoned me?
"Have you become a cold,
heartless bitch,
who cares nothing
for the man who loves her?"
- We, uh, we have to
make a counter-offer.
- You can't.
- We have over $1/2 million
in the bank.
- They won't take it,
it's not enough.
- I don't care!
You read Eduardo's letter,
they're gonna kill him!
- They won't kill him,
they're posturing.
- And what he said,
what Eduardo said,
he doesn't really think
that I abandoned him, does he?
Please tell me he...
- You know that's not
Eduardo writing,
it's the kidnappers.
Their goal is to frighten you
and bully you
into giving them what they want.
The most effective way to
do that is through your husband.
- How do you know this?
How do you know this?
- I've been
in this situation before.
- Well,
this is not a situation for me.
This is my husband,
and they're torturing him.
Luiz,
I'm going to the market.
- Senora.
- Please, give me the bag,
I need to get...
- Senora,
that's not a good idea.
- Let's go together.
- I need to get outta here
and do something.
- Raul!
I think I found something.
I found these this morning.
Could those be
the kidnappers'?
- It's possible.
- Can they help you figure out
who they are?
- They might.
Good work.
[Overlapping chatter]
- All right.
Muchas gracias.
[Engine starts]
[Phone rings]
- Senora?
- I'm just leaving the open-air
market, and I'm being followed.
- All right.
Where are you now?
- I'm on my way home, I should
be there in a few minutes.
- Don't panic.
Meet me at the gate.
It'll be open.
- Okay.
- I need you to go inside.
- Is something wrong?
- Find Maria, keep her safe.
Okay?
- Got it.
- Stay inside!
[Tires screech]
- Where's Maria?
- She's in her room.
- What's happening?
What is it?
- Open the gate!
Open the gate,
just open the gate!
- All right.
[Tires screech]
- Are you okay?
- Um, yeah.
- It's okay.
[Sobs]
- Are you all right?
- [Sighs] [Whimpers]
- Yes. It's registered
in guanajuato
so it could be local.
I'll also be express-mailing you
some cigarette butts
we found on the property.
They could be
the kidnapper's.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- We need to I.D.
These plates.
One of the kidnappers followed
senoravalseca home.
Car's probably hot
but who knows.
Maybe e.P.R. Got sloppy
this time.
- So what was that all about?
Are they trying to
kidnap me too?
- No. They're just trying to
intimidate you.
- Well, they're doing
a damn good job of it.
- Their goal is to wear you down
until you give them
what they want.
- I can't give them
Not until Cal comes through.
- But what if they come on
the property?
What if they threaten
the children?
[Gunshot]
[Gun clacks]
- If anyone tries to threaten me
again, or my kids...
- I understand.
- You should know that our guns
are not registered.
- I don't have a problem
with that.
- Good.
[Gunshot]
[Sirens wail]
- That acknowledges that we are
returning your vehicle.
Since we haven't heard anything
to the contrary,
I presume your husband
is still missing.
- Yes, that's right.
- How many weeks
has it been now?
It's too bad.
We would have secured
his release by now.
- Thank you.
- We'll let you know
if we need anything else.
[Whispers]
Let's go.
- [Under breath]
Took them long enough.
[Guns clicking]
- Okay.
Thanks.
The car belongs to a woman
in Santa Natalia.
It was missing from her garage
the time you were threatened,
but she didn't report it because
sometimes her nephew
borrows her car without asking.
- Okay. Well,
could it have been her nephew
that followed me home?
- He's a junior in high school.
[Phone rings]
And we didn't find a match
in our database
for any of the DNA
on the cigarette butts.
- Of course not.
Luiz, I can't talk to anyone
right now.
- It's Cal wimberley calling
from Texas.
- Cal!
Hey, Cal.
It's great to talk to you.
Are we close?
- I'm afraid not.
- Oh. Okay, um...
So, how much longer because
it's... it's been almost a month.
It's been over a month.
- Jayne, I really hate
to tell you this, but...
The deal's not going
to happen.
- What?
- It's just that money's gotten
incredibly tight right now,
what with the economy, and...
Mexico's not considered
a smart investment right now.
- Cal, Santa Natalia's
a-a great investment.
It's... it's beautiful here.
Our property is beautiful.
- It's not the land, jayne.
It's the violence, the crime.
Well, you know,
you've been affected by it
more than anyone.
- I need that $8 million,
Cal.
- I can't get it, jayne.
None of my partners
are interested.
[Sniffling]
- I counted on that money, Cal.
I counted on you, Cal.
- Jayne.
I'm so sorry.
I tried to convince him, but...
- Money is tight for us too,
and right now,
it's just, with no guarantee
of getting it back...
- But Olivia, Eduardo would
never renege on a debt.
Olivia, you know that.
Come on!
- I know.
But...
- But what?
Come on.
- What if he
doesn't come back?
- What are you saying?
That...
- No.
- That he's dead, Olivia?
- Sweetie...
It's... it's a possibility.
- It is not possible!
It is not possible.
And I will never stop believing
that Eduardo is alive,
Olivia, never.
- Jayne?
- I wondered why you stopped
coming around to help us,
and now I know why, Olivia.
I... now I know why.
- We remain deeply interested
in purchasing your chow chow.
But there is no way on earth
we can meet your price.
We must arrive at a more
reasonable figure.
Please respond in good faith.
- Yes.
- Come on.
[Blade unsheaths]
- So...
You wish to negotiate
a lower price.
There is no way on earth
you can give us what we want.
In that case, Eduardo is
sending you an incentive
to think otherwise.
Take the highway
west out of town.
When you cross the arroyo,
go north 5 1/2 kilometers.
There's a turn on the road.
Stop there.
In front of the dead tree,
buried in the ground,
you'll find a gift
from your husband.
- [Screaming]
[Grunting]
- Would you like me
to open it for you?
- They're I.O.U.S.
- I.O.U.S?
- Signed by Eduardo,
made out
to local businessmen
and friends.
- I.o.u.s for what?
- To advance me money that
he'll pay back for his release.
- That's a novel way
to collect a ransom.
- Well, it's worth a shot.
- There's nothing I can do
with these, jayne.
- But... but this is
Eduardo's signature.
You know that it is.
- But these are not legally
viable instruments.
Have any of the parties
on these notes accepted that?
- No. That's why I brought
them to the... to the bank.
I thought that if you could
guarantee them...
- We can't.
- This is Eduardo's
life, okay?
It's his life.
If these instruments
are not viable,
then I need access to
our savings account,
and I need it now!
- I'm as frustrated
as you are.
- No, you're not!
- [Sighs] Jayne, please.
Things move slowly
in Mexico.
- Obviously.
May I have my papers back?
- [Sighs] I'm very sorry.
- I am too.
- [Laughs]
- Get it! Get it!
Kick it to Raul.
- Pass it to me.
- Otra ves.
Pass it.
- Pass it to me, Diego.
- Kids!
Go in the house now, please.
Diego, Maria,
inside the house, please. Now.
Now!
In the house, please.
Is this what you do
to get my husband back?
By playing soccer with them?
- Senora...
I know you're frustrated.
- No!
You are not
their father, okay?
Their father is somewhere
being tortured right now.
- I know what
you're going through.
- Oh, geez, you have no idea
what I am going through!
What it feels like to know
that my husband
so desperately needs me...
The father of those children...
And everything I do to save him
comes to nothing!
That every day
that he's not released
brings him closer to death.
And if he dies, I die.
You have no idea how I feel.
- [Grunts]
[Horse neighing]
- Beautiful animal, senora.
It's a pity you have to sell it.
Are you selling the ranch
as well?
- No, I'm not.
- I'm in the market for a ranch
in the area. I can pay cash.
- I'm not in the position
to sell.
- No?
- No.
- I understand senora
desperately needs money.
- Are you interested
in the horse or not, sir?
- How much are you asking?
- Uh, $10,000.
- $3,000. I'll give you $3,000.
- $8,000.
That's the lowest I can go.
- $4,000.
I can't go any higher.
- Cash?
- Mommy?
- Yes, love?
- Here, take it.
Give it to the bad man
so daddy can come home.
- Come here.
Thank you, sweetheart.
- Mommy?
- Yes, baby?
- Sometimes, I forget
what daddy sounds like.
- [Sniffing] I know, baby.
I know.
[Latin music]
♪ ♪
[Spanish acoustic guitar music]
- Raising funds as quickly
as possible.
Still difficult.
Again, request lower asking
price.
- No, wait.
[Groans] No...
[Gun cocks]
No!
No, no!
- What is it?
- "You do not take us seriously,
senora.
"Here is proof
that you should.
"If you do not respond with
numbers that are satisfactory,
we will shoot Eduardo
in the other leg."
- I know that it looks bad.
I've seen them do this before.
They're just ratcheting
up the intimidation.
Listen to me.
They shoot through
the muscle at close range.
That cauterizes the wound.
If they have antibiotics,
which I promise you they do,
other than the pain
of that gunshot
and whatever recovery time
Eduardo needs,
there's no permanent damage
or loss of function.
They're just doing this
to get to you.
- [Sniffs]
- Stop!
- No.
- Always remember,
he's just merchandise.
They won't really hurt him.
He's far too valuable.
- It's almost like
waterboarding, isn't it?
Make the victim feel
as if they're going to die.
Pull him back from the brink,
make him...
Then do it again
and again and again.
[Sighs]
And I'm the victim.
- Only if you choose to be.
- Mom, Raul.
Come play.
- Okay, let's do it.
- Pass it, pass it, pass it.
- Diego, no.
- Okay.
Nice, nice.
Good, good.
[Phone rings]
- I need to talk to you.
- Esta bien.
- How much?
- Excuse me?
- How big of a service fee
do I have to give you
to gain access to my money?
- Service fee?
I-I don't...
- Isn't that what you want,
to free up my money,
is a bribe, yes?
- Jayne...
No, of course not.
- Then why won't you
release our money to me?
- Because I can't.
- What do you mean you can't?
Of course you can.
- The bank won't let me.
- Of course. Why disperse
hundreds of thousands of dollars
that you don't
expect to get back
when you can hold onto it
and earn interest.
- This is not my decision,
jayne.
- Then whose decision is it?
- I apologize for this.
I tried to explain
to senoravalseca that...
The banks' hands are tied...
That there is nothing we can do.
- I would like you to listen
very carefully.
My husband is being held
in captivity and tortured.
And for months now,
this bank has refused
to release funds
that could free him.
Money that is his.
Money that you have no legal
or moral right to hold on to.
So this afternoon, I'm filing
a lawsuit against the bank
for misappropriation of funds
and intentional infliction
of pain and suffering.
And if Eduardo is murdered
or dies in captivity,
I will make it
a wrongful death action.
Do you understand?
- This is not what
I meant when I said,
"don't choose to be a victim."
I meant
"don't let them get to you."
- You saw the photo... how
much more can Eduardo endure?
If I keep negotiating
with them on their terms,
keep selling off everything
that Eduardo and I have,
there will be nothing left,
and it'll be too late.
- You cannot give e.P.R.
An ultimatum.
- Yes, I would like to place
an ad in tomorrow's classifieds
in the animals and pets section.
Account number 6-5-7-3-2.
"We have funds in hand
to purchase your chow chow.
600 pesos. This is our sole
and final offer."
- [Muttering angrily]
- Well, that's all the money
we have... every last cent.
And they're not going
to get any more.
- You know how they'll respond?
- [Sighs] Yeah.
- And you're prepared for that?
- I don't know.
I hope so.
- But if I don't fight
to get Eduardo back,
I won't get him back.
- No, no... [groans]
[Echoing gunshot]
- All right.
Okay, I have it up.
- Everything's in place.
- Okay. Keep me posted.
- I will.
Has senoravalseca backed down
from her position at all?
- Not an inch.
[Phone beeps]
An e.P.R. Defector
contacted us.
In return for his immunity,
he's giving us information.
He says there's a hostage
being held in Angelica.
- And it's Eduardo?
- We don't know.
But it could be.
We're raiding the location
this afternoon.
- Read it.
Read it!
- "We have made
our sole and final offer.
"If it is unacceptable,
"keep your chow chow.
"If we never see it
"or hold it
in our arms again,
so be it."
[Dogs barking]
- Shoot you,
tell her your suffering
will continue,
and this is her answer?
"Take it or leave it."
How are we supposed
to respond to that?
- [Sighs]
- What?
- Believe her.
[Quietly sobbing]
- I'm sorry it wasn't Eduardo.
- I'm just glad that
no one was hurt.
And another family
is celebrating.
- They are. But e.P.R.
Held this man for over a year.
- He's back home,
but getting back to normal...
It won't be e...
- Raul, I understand that
by giving the kidnappers
an ultimatum,
I am taking a huge risk,
and it absolutely terrifies me.
But Eduardo is my husband,
so ultimately,
it's my decision
and my responsibility
to bring him home safely,
not yours.
If I fail, I'll fail
on the only terms
that makes sense to me.
And I will try to
accept the consequences.
Can you understand that?
- Yes, I can.
[Car door shuts]
- Hola, senor.
Gracias.
Can I help you?
Do you want something
because I am right here!
Hello,
can you look at me?
[Engine starts]
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
Talk to me!
[Speaking Spanish]
[Email alert chimes]
- Mom, are you okay?
- What is it?
- [Softly crying]
They accepted the offer.
They're ready
to release Eduardo.
They're going
to release dad.
They're ready
to let Eduardo go.
[Crying and laughing]
- Here are our instructions.
Deviate from them
in any respect,
and you will never see
your husband again.
The ransom needs to be paid
in unmarked, non-sequential
U.S. hundred-dollar bills.
[Zipper rasps]
- You are to drive
to Mexico City
with an associate.
Your husband has suggested
Gustavo ortego.
- Jayne?
Hi.
- Hey.
- How are you?
- I'm fine. How are you?
- I'm, uh, disappointed
in myself.
Ashamed. You came
to us for help and I...
- You don't have to explain.
I understand.
- I do think Eduardo
is still alive.
I really want to.
- I appreciate that.
I'll call, okay?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Good for you for keeping up
with the yoga.
You look great.
- Yeah.
- Do not bring anyone else.
If we suspect afi agents
or any other
law enforcement officers
are monitoring your movements,
we'll immediately
execute Eduardo.
- They won't make it easy.
- I know.
- Remember, don't give them
the money
until you have
the proof of life.
Cuidado, Gustavo.
- [Whispers] Be careful.
- It's almost over.
I'll be back
for Diego's birthday.
[Sighs]
Thank you.
I'll be back.
[Engine starts]
Let's go.
- When you arrive
in Mexico City,
check into the motel
we have designated.
Await our further instructions.
We will contact you there.
[Email alert chimes]
Leave the motel now.
[Knocks on door]
Mark the letter "t" on your
vehicle with duct tape.
Drive to the bridal shop
at the following address.
Drive to the following address.
There you will find a telephone
where we have left instructions.
Now, drive to the mercado
at the address below.
[Phone beeps]
Now drive to the bakery
at the address below.
Now drive to the jewelry store
- Senora.
- [Sighs]
- This is...
This is today's edition.
He's alive.
- "Here is your proof of life.
Now, proceed to the following
destination."
- [Sighs] Okay.
- Wait for our signal.
[Engine shuts off]
Do not attempt to get out
of the car.
And keep your hands visible
at all times.
We will be watching you.
[Tires screeching]
[Engine revving up]
- Where's Eduardo?
Where's... where's Eduardo?
- No se, senora.
- Where is he?
Where is he?
[Crying]
[Screaming]
Where is he?
I don't understand.
[Screaming]
I don't understand!
[Screaming and sobbing]
[Cellphone rings]
- I'm here.
When?
- A few hours ago.
We stayed, hoping they'd
bring Eduardo, but...
[Crying]
But they haven't...
- Okay, go to the motel.
Call me as soon as
you get there.
[Cell phone beeps]
- What happened?
- They took the money,
but they didn't release Eduardo.
- [Softly] Oh, no.
- Excuse me.
- [Sighs]
- Raul?
- This isn't how they work.
Something's terribly wrong.
[Email alert chimes]
- "We have the money.
"We counted it.
"It is all here in unmarked
bills as we have requested.
You may return
to Santa Natalia."
[Engine starts]
- Blow out the candles.
Yay!
Mwah.
Happy birthday, honey.
- I made a wish.
I wished that...
- No, don't say it out loud,
sweetheart.
- I want some cake.
- I know you do. I do too.
Let's do this.
All right, get those candles
out of there.
- I'll finish up.
- Thank you, luiz.
- Nothing.
- [Sighs]
So they never kill
their hostages.
You told me that, right?
- Yes. I did.
- Then we just have to believe
that this is...
No different.
We did everything we could,
Raul.
- I hope so, senora.
- Senora.
You realize that you have
never once called me jayne.
I don't think I ever learned
your last name, either.
- Actually, senora...
You never really learned
my first.
- Hmm.
- You can't do that.
- Stop, Diego.
- Only move to the sides.
- Maria.
- Keep it there.
- You're cheating.
- I'm not cheating.
He's cheating.
- Can't do that.
- Yes, I can.
- You can only move
to the sides.
[Water running]
[Softly]
- Eduardo.
Eduardo?
Eduardo!
Eduardo.
[Softly]
- Jayne.
- Daddy?
- [Sobbing]
- Daddy! Daddy!
- [Crying]
[Sniffling]
Captioning bycaptionmax
www.Captionmax.Com